In this lesson, we're going to add multifactor authentication to our own individual user account.
So let's head over to AWS.
I'm in the Identity and Access Management console.
And as you can see, we've already got a couple of security recommendations.
It's saying that we should add MFA for the root user and for ourselves.
Now what we're going to do in this lesson is add MFA for our own user accounts.
Now, the process is very similar but slightly different for the root user. I've actually added a link
to an AWS article that you can follow if you want to log out and log back in as root and add MFA
or root.
So that's something you could potentially do after this lesson.
Now it's important to note that with IAM, we never need to select a region. So that's something that
pops up in exam questions quite a lot.
Where you get some kind of scenario, where users are being added to some other geographical area in
the world and you need to know what to do with their accounts and how to set up their accounts.
Well, with IAM, you only ever have the accounts in one place and you can use those accounts with any
region around the world.
So let's set up MFA for our user account.
I'm going to click on users, select my user account, then click on security credentials, and we can
see towards the middle of the screen here
next to assigned MFA device,
we don't have any assigned devices. So, I'm going to click on manage.
We're going to use a virtual MFA device. Now,
for this, you will need an authenticator app installed on your mobile device or on your computer.
Now I personally use the Google Authenticator app on my phone.
So if you don't already have one installed, install the Google Authenticator app and then click on
continue.
The next thing to do is click show QR code.
You'll need to point your phone's camera to the QR code, and it should open Google Authenticator.
Once you've done that and you've got Google Authenticator open, it should be generating a code and
displaying that on your screen.
So what you need to do is add the code that's on the screen right now.
I've added mine. And then you need to wait for that code to expire and it'll generate a new code and
you need to add that into the MFA code two box and then click on assign MFA.
And that's it.
You've now got MFA enabled for your accounts, and you can see that we have an ARN for the virtual
device here.
So next time you log in, you will also be asked to supply the code from your authenticator app.