Welcome back.
There are a couple of different methods for access control.
One is known as Role-Based Access Control and the other is known as Attribute-Based Access Control.
So RBAC and ABAC and I'm going to cover those in this lesson.
So firstly, we have Role-Based Access Control.
Now, this is where we might have multiple groups and those groups are created as containers to hold
users who have a specific job role.
So in this case, the admin group, the development group, and the operations group.
And then we place our users into those groups.
We then take permissions policies and apply the permissions policies to the group.
So the users inherit the permissions that are assigned to the group and the groups are organized
by job role.
This is a good method and it's a way that you can apply the minimum permissions a user needs for
their specific job function.
So, for example, the operations group here has a user called Andrea and Andrea will have some permissions
applied that give her the access she needs as an operations personnel, whereas Lee will get the specific
permissions he needs as a developer, but they won't be able to do each other's jobs.
So there will be specific permissions that they have which people in other groups don't.
So it's about minimizing the permissions you assign to users and giving them exactly what they need
for their job and that's known as the principle of least privilege.
You'll find several policies in your account.
These are AWS managed policies that are known as job function policies.
So these are supposed to be closely aligned to industry specific roles.
So we have administrator and data scientist and security auditor and system administrator
and several others.
So you can have a look at these and see whether they fit your specific use case.
If they do, then that can be quite useful.
It also means that if you don't have much experience in writing IAM policies, then you can use policy
documents that have been pre-created by AWS.
So, for example, we might have a billing admins group with a user called Joanne
and a permissions policy applied.
And that permissions policy would use the billing job function policy, the AWS managed policy.
And the actual JSON code looks like this and it gives Joanne the specific permissions that she needs
to do her specific role as a billing administrator.
Attribute-Based Access Control is where we're using attributes in this case, tags to define access
to our resources.
So we have a DBAdmins group in IAM.
We have Dave, who is a member of that group, and Dave has a tag assigned to him to his user account.
And that gives him two pieces of information here. So the tag is a piece of metadata.
That's a key value pair.
We have the key, which is department and the value, which is DBAdmins.
So that's a tag applied to that particular user.
So tags are a way of signing metadata to resources using key value pairs.
Now, we then have a permissions policy assigned to the group and that permissions policy looks like this.
So let's try to understand this.
Firstly, there's an effect which is "allow", so it's going to allow some access.
The action is three different API actions.
We've got RebootDBInstance, StartDBinstance, and StopDBInstance.
The resource is * so any resource, but there's a condition.
So the condition says that the string has to equal.
And then we've got two particular tags here.
We've got the AWS principal tag. That's the tag applied to the user here.
So it's applied to a principal in IAM and that needs to be department/DBadmins.
We then have a resource tag.
So in this case it's the RDS database and it needs to have the DB tag environment and production.
So the permissions will be granted to the resources when the tag matches the correct value.
So let's have a look at the tags associated with these two RDS databases.
The top one has an environment of production and the bottom one has an environment of development.
So when Dave actually tries to reboot the DB instance in production, he's going to get a success because
the reboot DB instance action is allowed as long as the department equals DBadmins
on the specific principal tag.
And the DB tag for the RDS database should equal environment production, which it does.
If Dave then tries to stop the other DB instance that's going to fail and that's because the tag
associated with that database has an environment of development, and that's not allowed, it's not in
the policy.
This is a great way of implementing access control as it gives you a lot of flexibility.
So that's it for the theory.
We will actually perform a lab later on in this section where we'll look at implementing RBAC and ABAC.