Hello and welcome to this section.
In this section, I'm going to cover two main services. One is AWS cloudformation,
that is a service that's used for deploying infrastructure through code.
So we define our infrastructure as we want it to be built
in a template file and cloud formation takes that
file and uses it to then automate the implementation,
the creation of those resources.
Now,
the other service that we're going to look at is elastic
beanstalk elastic, beanstalk features quite a lot in the developer associate exam
beanstalk is often referred to as a platform as a service or PAAS solution
and that's because beanstalk will give you a managed
environment onto which you can deploy your code.
So it's really great for developers who
don't want to manage the underlying infrastructure.
That's the low balances and the ec2 instances and even databases
that are connected to your applications.
So there's lots of coverage of beanstalk in this course and we'll also
do quite a few hands on lessons and not just within this section.
We'll revisit elastic beanstalk later on when we get to the developer tools as well.