In this lesson,
I'm going to deep dive into some of the components of a CloudFormation template.
So CloudFormation templates as you know,
are YAML or JSON-based templates that are used to describe
the end state of the infrastructure that you want to create using CloudFormation.
After creating the template, you can then upload it to CloudFormation directly
or you can upload it to S3
and then use CloudFormation to connect to S3 when you're creating your stack.
CloudFormation will read the template and then make
the API calls to provision your infrastructure on your behalf.
And then the resulting resources are known as a stack.
We have logical IDs which are used to reference resources within the template.
Then we have physical IDs which are used to identify
resources outside the CloudFormation after they've actually been created.
Now let's look at some of the functions such as
intrinsic functions that we can use in a template.
CloudFormation provides several built-in functions
that help you to manage your stacks.
And these are known as intrinsic functions
and they help you to assign values to properties
that are not available until runtime.
We'll go over some of them in this lesson but there's lots more
and you can look at the full list here on the AWS website.
So let's start off looking at the intrinsic function called Ref.
This returns the value of the specified parameter or resource.
When you specify a parameter's logical name, it will return
the value of the parameter.
And if you specify a resource's logical name,
it will return the value that you can typically use to then refer to that resource,
such as the physical ID.
So let's look at an example.
This resource declaration is for an elastic IP address.
And it needs the instance ID of an EC2 instance.
So it's going to use the Ref function to specify the instance ID of the EC2
instance resource.
So we can see here we have the property for the Elastic IP address
and we need the instance ID.
So it's using Ref and it's referencing my EC2 instance which can be found
somewhere else in the template.
Next we have Fn Get Att.
So this is an intrinsic function that returns
the value of an attribute from a resource in the template.
Here's the full syntax in YAML and here's the short form in YAML.
Now, let's have a look at an example.
This template will use the get at to actually return certain values for the ELB.
Firstly, it's going to return the sourcesecuritygroup.owneralias.
So here, within the security group ingress rule,
we need to identify the security group owner ID.
And so we're going to use get att to find it within the MyELB resource.
And the same then for the source security group name.
We then have FindinMap.
This returns the value corresponding to keys in a
two-level map that's declared in the mapping section.
Here's the full syntax in YAML and then the short form in YAML.
So again, let's have a look at an example.
So this example shows how to use finding map for a template
with a mapping section that contains a single map.
And that's called region map and you can see that here.
And within that we have regions defined
and then the AMIs for specific architectures.
And so we're using
the FindInMap down here in resources where we're declaring the my EC2 instance.
We've got properties, then we've got image ID,
and we need to know the AMI ID for this resource.
And so we're going to use FindInMap.
Next, we have resources.
So the required resources section will declare
the AWS resources that you need to include
in the stack such as EC2 or S3 buckets or whatever it is you're provisioning.
Now this is a mandatory section.
Resources are declared and can reference each other.
So here we can see an example of an EC2 instance being declared as a resource
within the template.
Next we have parameters.
This is an optional section that you can use to customize your templates.
Parameters enable you to input your custom values to your template
when you create or update your stack.
And they're useful for template reuse.
And here's an example where we're using parameters to define the
instance types that we want to allow for our EC2 instances.
So the type is string,
the allowed values are the three different EC2 instance types we want to allow.
And then the default here
is the one which will be selected by default if you don't change it.
Then we have mappings.
This is an optional section that matches a key to a
corresponding set of named values.
So we saw this in another slide just a little while ago.
We can see here we have a region map.
And within that map we then have us-east-1, us-west-1,
and then we've defined the AMIs
for specific architectures within each of those regions.
Now an exam tip here, with mappings you can
set the values based on the region as we can see.
And therefore you can create a mapping that uses the region name as a key
and contains the values you want to specify for each specific region.
So if you're defining, for example a template which deploys EC2 instances
and you want to use it across regions,
you're going to need to supply different AMI IDs.
Therefore you can use region map to solve that issue.
We then have output.
So this is another optional section where you can declare
output values that you want to import to other stacks.
And you can also return them in response to certain
things like stack calls or view them in the console.
So in this example here, we have an output and what this will do
is return the idea of a VPC within the value here
and then it's going to record that for cross stack referencing.
We then have conditions.
This is another optional section that contains statements that define
the circumstances under which entities are created or configured.
For example,
in this sample code here, what's going to happen
is the resources are only going to be created
if the ENV type parameter is equal to prod.
So here we've got Ref ENV type, and if it's equal to prod,
then the condition will pass and that resource will be created.
If it was dead for example of some other value
then it would fail and the resources not created.
Lastly, we have the transformed section. This is another optional section
that specifies one or more macros that CloudFormation uses to process your template.
You can use the transform section to actually reference
additional code that you might have stored in. S3.
It could be code such as lambda code or other snippets of CloudFormation code.
Now this one is really important for the exam to understand.
It's AWS and then serverless.
This transform specifies the version of the AWS
serverless application model, AWS SAM to use and we're going
to learn a bit more about that later on.
This model defines the SAM syntax that you can use
and how CloudFormation will process it.
Again, we'll look at that in a bit more detail in another lesson.
We also have AWS Include.
Now, this transform works with template snippets that are stored
separately from the main CloudFormation templates.
It's always good to look at some examples. So let's have a look at some example code.
So here we're using the AWS serverless transform
to specify a resource, which is a lambda function.
And it's a way of simplifying how we can define our lambda function and its
code so we can see what the code is being referenced in the code URI there as an S3.
And that's it for this lesson. I will see you in the next one.