AWS Elastic Beanstalk is a service that can automate the creation and management of web applications
running on Amazon EC2. What it would do, is it will actually create the entire environment for you,
including Amazon EC2, a web application environment running on top of that, such as Node.js, for
example, and also an auto scaling group,
load balancer and even Amazon RDS, if you choose as well. It's often referred to as a platform as
a service solution.
Now it is similar in many ways to AWS CloudFormation, but its scope is different.
Its scope is much narrower,
just the few services I just mentioned. And it's more about managing that environment for you.
So, creating it and then managing it. So you can update your code.
You can view operations information from CloudWatch or within the Beanstalk console.
So with Beanstalk,
think about managing web apps and with CloudFormation, think about building a very, very broad set
of infrastructure.
So let's have a look at how it works.
In this particular example, we have an AWS region, a VPC, couple of availability zones with public
subnets, and we've created an Elastic Beanstalk environment.
Now, in this case, a developer has some code in a zip file.
The developer is going to upload that code to Beanstalk.
Now that code contains the information required for the web application.
Beanstalk will then provision an auto scaling group, some EC2 instances.
It will load the web application onto those instances. And in this case, it's also created an application
load balancer in front of those EC2 instances.
Everything that you can see there within the EB environment, the Elastic Beanstalk environment is
launched and then managed by Elastic Beanstalk.
You can actually launch and manage both EC2 instances and Docker containers
on ECS using Beanstalk. Elastic Beanstalk supports Java, .net, PHP, Node.js, Python, Ruby, Go and Docker
web applications. And it also supports a long list of languages and development stacks which all put
on the screen for you here.
So you can see from this list, this really is all about web applications.
And again, that's what you should think of when you see questions arising around how to deploy and
manage a web application environment on Amazon EC2 or just on AWS.
It will push you towards Beanstalk as being a good solution.
So let's have a look at the components of Beanstalk.
There are several layers to Elastic Beanstalk.
Firstly, you have the application.
The application will contain the environments, the configuration of those environments and the versions
of our application code.
You can have multiple application versions within your application.
So here we can see an example of where we have some code in an Amazon S3 bucket and there are actually
four different versions of that code.
A version is a specific reference to some deployable code.
So it's important to understand each version
here is where you've updated your application code and you can always go back to a previous version.
It still references all within your application.
Typically, the code will be stored in Amazon S3 buckets.
A version can be applied to any environment.
So what is an environment?
Well, in this application here we have multiple environments, we have development and we have production.
An environment is essentially an application version that's been deployed on AWS resources. And those
resources are deployed and configured by AWS Elastic Beanstalk.
Now, the environment is not just the EC2 instances, it's anything else that is provisioned by
AWS Elastic Beanstalk, including auto-scaling groups, load balancers and even an RDS database.
There are two different types of environments we can deploy.
We've got web servers and workers.
Now, a web server is a standard application that listens for and processes HTTP requests over port 80 or over
a secure port.
So a web server is a web application.
We then have a worker.
A worker is useful for when you need to process information, perform some kind of long running task
that's going to take a while.
You don't want your web application to perform that.
So, what you do is you offload that workload to a worker environment.
Now, the worker will listen on an Amazon SQS queue, so it's going to process messages from a queue.
So it's really good for any long running tasks, any heavy processing that's going to take quite a while
to complete.
So let's put that all together.
We've got our Elastic Beanstalk application.
Here we have a web server environment and a worker environment, and we have our user.
The user is sending traffic
to the webserver on port 80 or port 443. The webserver is then going to place any information that
requires any kind of heavy processing or something that's going to take a long time to complete.
It puts that information into an SQS queue.
The worker will then process the information in the queue, so it's going to poll the queue, find the
message and process that information.
All of this is created and managed by Elastic Beanstalk. So, that's it for the theory.
In the next lesson, we're going to go into a hands-on and we'll create a web server environment and
a worker environment.