Hi guys, and welcome to another hands-on lesson.
In this lesson,
we're going to create another Elastic Beanstalk environment and we're going to see
how we can update that environment without actually incurring any downtime.
So I'm back in Elastic Beanstalk and I'm going to choose my application here.
And what we're going to do is create a new environment.
It's going to be a web server environment. Click on select.
And it gives us a default environment name, I'm happy to accept the defaults there.
We don't have our own domain name so I'm going to leave that blank.
We're going to use managed platform and we're going to choose Node.js again.
And as before, we're going to choose to upload our own source code.
So let's upload the original Node.js.zip file.
Now, I also want to configure options.
And all we need to do here is select custom configuration.
Now of course, for high availability we can always use a load balancer
and have an Auto Scaling group with instances.
But for this example, all we want to do
is ensure that there's at least one instance running at all times.
So I'm going to click on create environment.
And that's going to take a couple of minutes to create.
And then what we'll do when it's ready is we're going to update our application and
we're going to use rolling with additional batch
so that an additional instance is launched.
So that took a few minutes.
But now my Elastic Beanstalk environment is finished and it's healthy.
If I click on the link, it takes me to this landing page.
And if I go over to the EC2 console,
I can see the instances running. Now, the terminated one is from a previous lesson.
So this is the one that's part of this lesson.
If I come down to Auto Scaling groups we'll see it's
created an Auto Scaling group with a desired capacity of one.
So this all looks good.
Now what I want to do now for this test is I'm going to choose to upload
an application. I'm going to upload the Node.js Blue Zip file that we created earlier.
Choose upload.
And we have the deployment preferences here.
Now, you'll note that earlier on in a previous lab,
we didn't actually have these options here and that was because we were not
using a custom configuration that just enables certain options for the free tier.
Now we should still stay in the free tier anyway.
But those options aren't available unless you choose custom.
So now we can see the deployment preferences and we've got all at once.
Rolling, rolling with additional batch, immutable, and traffic splitting.
So what we're going to do is use rolling with additional batch.
And we're going to leave the other settings as default and click on deploy.
And while that's happening we should have a look in EC2
at both the Auto Scaling group and the instances and see what's going on.
back in Auto Scaling, we can see that the desired capacity has now changed to two.
If we go in and have a look at the activity, we can see that a new instance
is being launched.
And so if we come back up two instances,
then we can also see another running instance now.
So the application should still be available.
Let's click refresh.
And we can still see the old version of the application. It's still green.
It hasn't turned blue yet.
Once the update is complete, we'll have our blue screen and then the old instance,
the previous instance will actually be terminated.
So this is a way that we can ensure that
there's always an active version of the application running.
I can see the message here that the instance deployment completed successfully.
So let's come up and refresh our page. That's gone blue as expected.
And then if we come back to EC2 and refresh,
and we've still got two running instances.
But shortly, one of them should be terminated
Now while that process is happening, if we come back to Elastic Beanstalk,
another place you can make changes is by going to configuration.
In configuration, you can see there's lots of settings here that we can modify.
For example, we could add a load balancer,
you can change the default settings here.
For application deployments, we chose rolling with additional batch but you
can specify one of these other options here.
If I cancel out of there,
we've got information about the instances, the software, the X-ray daemon,
those kind of settings.
And we've got EC2 security here.
So for example,
we could then choose a key pair if we want to use a key pair with this instance.
You can also change the instance profile.
Once you've made changes, you can apply the changes and the
configuration will be applied for you automatically.
Let's go back to EC2.
Just give this a refresh and sure enough, one of our instances is shutting down.
So if I go back to Auto Scaling groups,
yep, now the desired capacity has been reset back to one.
So that's it. That's how we can deploy application updates with Elastic Beanstalk.
Let's go back to the environment. And I've finished with this environment now.
So I'm simply going to go into actions, terminate.
Make sure I copy in the environment name
and then terminate my environment.