There are a few additional advanced configuration options
in Beanstalk that are subjects on the exam, as well as using certificates.
So firstly we're going to start off with something called the .ebextensions.
Now you can add Elastic Beanstalk configuration files
these are the, in the .ebextensions directory to your web application source code to
configure your environment and customize the resources it contains.
The configuration files are YAML or JSON-formatted documents
with .config file extension.
And you put them in a folder that is named .ebextensions and deploy
that in your application source code.
So for example,
here we have some options settings for an Elastic Beanstalk environment
with our load balancer type being a network load balancer.
Now the option_settings section of a configuration file
defines the values for configuration options.
The resources section allows you to further customize the resources
and define additional resources beyond the functionality
provided in the configuration options.
So you get a lot more flexibility here and scope for customization.
Additional sections of the configuration file will
let you configure the instances that are launched in your environment.
They include the packages, sources, files, users, groups, commands,
container_commands, and services.
Again, this definitely comes up in exam questions to make sure you
understand that this is a way to customize Elastic Beanstalk.
Remember that .ebextensions is
a directory and within that directory
you then have your .config files.
And you've got to include .ebextensions within your source code bundle.
So next, using HTTPS with Elastic Beanstalk.
You can use SSL/TLS certificates.
They can be assigned to an environment Elastic Load Balancer.
You can use AWS certificate manager for managing those certificates.
The connections between clients and the load balancer are then secured with SSL/TLS.
Backend connections between the load balancer and EC2 instances are not secured.
You can configure the certificate through the console or through the .ebextensions.
So for example here you can see we have an option_settings parameter
and within that we're defining our secure listener,
we're enabling it on port 443 for the HTTPS protocol.
And then we've got the ARN for our SSL/TLS certificate.
Now if you do want end-to-end encryption so you
want encryption not just from the client to the load balancer,
but from the load balancer to the EC2 instances, then you can do that.
You can use a self-signed certificate on the EC2 instances.
And again the configuration can be made using .ebextensions.
How you actually configure it is dependent on which load balancer you're using.
So let's have a look at an example.
So here we're going to have a file called HTTPS  Re-encrypt-ALB.
It's a .config file. It's in .ebextensions.
It's got some option settings defined
and we can see that we've got the listener being defined on our ELB.
And then we've got the port and the protocol for the backend as well.
You may want to redirect any incoming HTTP connections to HTTPS.
And there's a couple of ways to do this.
One way is you can use the instance web service configuration.
So you're actually configuring the web service on your EC2 instances
to respond to any HTTP traffic with an HTTP redirection response status.
And the configuration for that is platform dependent.
Next you could use the load balancers, so you can configure an ALB
to send redirection responses to HTTP traffic. Now, that is specific to the ALB.
And that's it for this lesson. I will see you in the next one.