Welcome to the exam cram for infrastructure as code and pass. So let's get into it
with cloud formation.
Infrastructure patterns are defined in a template file using code.
Cloud formation builds your infrastructure according to the template file,
template files are Jason or Yamil. Code
infrastructure is provisioned consistently with fewer mistakes
so less chance of human error.
Less time and effort is also expended
than configuring resources manually.
You can use version control and peer review for your cloud formation templates.
It's free to use your only charge for the resources provisioned by cloud formation.
It can be used to manage updates and dependencies
and it can roll back and delete the entire stack as well.
You create update and delete stacks using the templates,
stacks are deployed through the management console cli or a P I S.
With stacks sets.
You can create,
update or delete stacks across multiple accounts
and regions with a single operation.
An administrator account is the account which you use to create the stack set
and the stack set is managed by signing into the AWS administrator account
in which it was created
nested stacks allow re use of cloud formation code for common use cases
now make sure you re watch the template deep dive
session for important exam knowledge that's a really must watch video
AWS elastic beanstalk deploys and manages web applications.
It can also deploy the E L B auto scaling and even a database
Web servers are standard applications that listen
for and then process http requests.
Typically over port 80.
Workers on the other hand,
use a background processing task to listen for messages on an amazon sqs queue
beanstalk deployment options are all at once.
This deploys the new version to all instances simultaneously.
Rolling updates a batch of instances and then moves on to the next batch.
Once the first batch is healthy,
rolling with additional batches like rolling but it
launches new instances in a new batch,
ensuring that there's full availability for your application
immutable
launches new instances with a new auto scaling
group and deploys the version update to those instances
and then swaps traffic to those instances. Once they're healthy
with blue green,
you create a new stage environment and then deploy your updates there,
elastic beanstalk configuration files.
The dot e B extensions can be added to your web application source grade
and they're used to customize environment and resources.
They are Yamil or Jason formatted documents
with a dot config file extension and they
get placed in the dot e B extensions folder in your application source code bundle
the option underscore setting section of a
configuration file defines values for configuration options.
The resources section lets you further customize the resources
in your application's environment.
Ssl TLS certificates can be assigned to an environment elastic load
balancer and you can use a c m for the certificate.
The connections between clients and the load balancer are then secured.
That's it for this lesson. I'll see you in the next one