Hey guys.
In this lesson, we're going to create a custom Amazon virtual private cloud.
This is essentially what we're going to create a virtual private
cloud with a CIDR block of 10 000 slash 16.
There's going to be two public subnets and
two private subnets across two availability zones.
And you can see the CIDR blocks for each individual subnet
in the diagram.
Of course,
we're going to need an internet gateway so we can launch
instances and enable them to be accessible from the internet.
And,
and there's going to be a main route table.
That's the default route table that's created when we create our VPC.
We'll also create a separate route table. That's one for the private subnets.
That means it doesn't have the internet gateway.
And if we want to in the future, of course,
we can put a path to a net gateway
if we want to enable outbound internet connectivity.
So that's why we need a separate route table for the private subnets. So I'm in the
managmeent console, let's go across to VPC and we're going to create our VPC here.
So let's go to your VPC's,
we're going to click on create VPC. Now, there's a couple of options here.
We can do it manually or you can actually use this VPC and more function.
And that's really good. It gives you this diagrammatic output as well.
So it kind of shows you what you're creating, you can give it a name,
it's chosen the exact CIDR block we want by default.
And also you can then choose the number of availability zones
by default.
It's two with the number of public subnets as
two and the number of private subnets as two.
Then you can choose whether you want to create NAT gateways and an S3 gateway as well.
So that's one option.
The other way is to just create VPC only and
then you can actually add in the subnets yourself.
So of course, both ways are really good.
I really enjoy this VPC and more, I think this is a great function
and you'll probably use that quite a lot. But let's look at the other way as well. And
we're going to use a file which has defined the ranges that we're going to use.
So this is the file in the Amazon VPC directory in here
We've got the name,
the CIDR block and then we've got the information for the different subnets.
Public one, A public one B, private one A and private one B.
So let's start by copying the name of the VPC.
We're going to pop that in the name tag here. And then we need the IPV four CIDR block.
So that's this one here exactly as you see
it in the file 10 000 slash 16.
Back in the console. We can put this in here where it says IPV four CIDR.
Now, we don't need an IPV six CIDR block and the default tenancy is the best option.
So that's it. We just create the VPC. So that's it. The VPC has now been created.
You can see that we don't actually have any subnets.
There is a route table, of course, that's created by default by the VPC creation.
Now what we want
next is create our subnets.
So let's come back to sub nets on the left hand side here, I'm going to create subnets,
choose my VPC.
So of course, we need to choose the one we just created my VPC.
Then we can add in the subnets one by one.
So Subnet, one of one is going to be our first one.
I'm going to copy the name, paste that in.
You may have noticed that we had a
specification for which availability zone in the file.
It said US easr one A. So we'll choose us
east one A and then let's get the CIDR block.
So back in the file, we're now going to copy this CIDR block. So this is
a slash 24 10 010 back in the file.
Let's just paste that in now I can do exactly the same thing for the next subnet
and then repeat that for subnets 2, 3 and four. So I've just done that.
I now have all four subnets to find Subnet one there
Subnet two public one B in us East one B subnet,
three private one A in US East one A
and then finally Subnet four private one B in US East one B.
And of course, I've added in the correct side of blocks for each of those.
So now we can create the subnets. It's going to automate that process for us.
And now we have these four new subnets in our VPC.
Let's go over and have a look at the route table configuration.
So we have a route table here for my VPC.
It won't have any explicit associations.
So we can see subnets without explicit associations are here. We have four.
So essentially they're implicit associations.
They haven't been statically defined or
manually defined against this particular route table.
So there's no explicit subnet associations.
Now,
what we do want to do is create a new route table and
take our private subnets and put those in the new route table.
So let's go back up a level, create rout table in the file here. We've got private RT
as the name. It's got to be in the correct VPC
Of course, and then we're going to associate private one A and private one B.
So let's give it the name, select the VPC and create rout table.
And now we want to go to sub net associations, edit
and then choose private one A and private one B and then save associations.
So now we have the explicit subnet associations.
So if we won't go back to the original route table, the default one,
the main route table, we now see there's only two implicit associations.
OK?
There's none explicitly but the private one A and one B have been
moved out to the new route table that's designed for the private subnets.
Lastly, we're going to create an internet gateway. So we're going to it my
IGW back in the console, we're going to go to internet gateways,
create internet gateway, provide the name and then create it.
Now, what we need to do is go to actions and attach to VPC,
select my VPC and then attach internet gateway.
So that's it.
The route table creates very quickly if you come back to rout tables,
choose the main route table.
That's this one here. In fact, I'm going to give it a name. Let's call this one main Dash
RT.
So we know that's the one in
our custom VPC. I'm going to choose the route table ID
and we can see we only have the local route.
So what we want to do is add the route now to the internet gateway,
it's going to be all zeros.
And then we're going to choose internet gateway and select
my IG W and then save and that's it.
Our custom VPC is now configured.
All that's left to do is launch some EC2 instances and test it out.
So let's go to EC2. I'm going to launch an instance.
We're going to use the default Amazon Linux 2023 AMI
T two micro. I'm going to proceed without a key pair.
We're going to choose the correct VPC. So that's the new VPC, my VPC
and create a security group. So we'll just call this one web access as we usually do.
In fact, I'm going to add on my VPC on the end.
So it's clear sometimes in the console which one
to choose now, what we want to do is just add in any rules.
We've got SSH, let's also add in http from anywhere
and we've got SSH
already by default.
So let's launch this instance now that we have our route table set up successfully,
we're going to launch an EC2 instance and test
that we can actually access that instance from the internet.
Now, before we do that, what I want to do is head over to subnets,
we're going to choose our public subnets, one by one, go to actions,
edit Subnet settings
and enable auto assigned public IPV four address and then click on save.
I'll do that one for the other public Subnet as well.
We want to make sure that we get those public IP addresses.
OK. Let's save that one.
And now we're ready to launch our instance in the course download,
we have some user data here, which we're going to use.
So let's copy this user data.
It's simply going to install a web server under security groups.
We're going to create a security group. I'm going to call this web access dash
my VPC and the same in the description as well.
So we know which one this is associated with for VPC
We're going to select my VPC for inbound rules. We're going to add both SSH
and then http
and in both cases from anywhere. And that's our security group set up.
Now, let's go to the EC2 management console in EC2.
I'm going to launch an instance. I'll leave the default Amazon Linux 2023 MA
I T two micro. I don't need to keep air. Of course, we need to change our VPC.
So I'm going to choose my VPC, select existing security group,
choose web access and then we need to scroll down to advance
details all the way to the bottom and paste in our user data
and then launch
while that's happening. I'm also going to launch an instance into a private subnet.
OK.
So let's call this one private and I'm just
going to scroll down for the instance type.
We'll leave it as it is. I don't need a key pair for VPC.
Of course, we need to check, select our my VPC.
And then for security group, this one's going to be private access.
And what I'm going to put into here is simply
we can have SSH
but also I want to have the ICMP all, so all ICMP
IPV four from,
and we can actually select the security group of our public instance.
So that would be the web access, my VPC.
OK. So we're only going to allow IC MP from this security group.
Now, we do need to make sure that the subnet is correct as well.
So let's just go and put this into a private subnet.
So I'm going to choose private one A
so now it's not going to get a public IP. All right, scroll down.
Let's launch the instance on EC2
I'm going to select my public instance,
copy the public IP address and let's put that into a browser
and that works. So that's awesome. That's definitely working.
We know that port 80 from the internet is working.
So we have an internet gateway,
we have a public IP address and we should be able to connect in via SSH
as well. So let's use instance connect and now we're connected to our instance.
Now what I want to do is send a ping request to the private instance.
So that will check that we connectivity to our private EC2
instance.
So we're simply going to run ping,
put in the private IP address and we get a successful response.
So that's it.
I've now tested that my internet gateway and everything is working,
routing is working as expected and all that's left to do is
just terminate these two instances and we're done for this lesson.