So we've created our custom VPC, and I'd just like to test it now. So, we're going to launch some EC2
instances, two instances in two different public subnets and one in a private subnet.
And we're actually going to do that via the command line.
It's really useful to know the command line.
Now, not all exams require you to know the command line, so for the Solutions Architect Associate,
it doesn't really matter too much. For the developer,
it does a bit more for certain services. And definitely, for the SysOps exam.
Now, whatever exam you're doing or whatever career path you're taking in AWS, it's still a really
useful skill to have.
So, it's definitely worth learning the command line.
So, we'll launch some instances using the command line and then we'll use those instances just to test
connectivity with each other.
There's a couple of things I want to do before we get started there.
Firstly, I want to create a NAT gateway. So, I'm in the VPC management console. Under NAT gateways,
let's create a NAT gateway.
I'm just going to call it My NAT-GW. And I need to select a subnet.
Now, remember, with NAT gateways, they always go in public subnets.
So here I'm going to choose public-1A.
And that I know is within the correct VPC as well.
So connectivity is public.
We allocate an elastic IP and then just create the NAT gateway.
Now, of course, it won't work until we update the route table for our private subnets.
So under route tables, let's choose the Private-RT, go to routes, edit routes, add route and we're
going to specify 0.0.0/0.
And this time it's going to be a NAT gateway and we'd choose that Nat gateway ID.
Now, our private subnets will have access to the internet. And that's important because when our instance
launches, we're going to run some user data. And that's going to connect to the internet to download
some binaries for HTTPD.
Next thing is, under security groups, we need a security group.
Let's create a security group.
I'm going to call it Public-Web,
give it a description, and make sure I select My VPC. For outbound rules,
by default, it allows all traffic to any destination. For inbound,
just for now, we're going to add all traffic from any destination.
So, this is very open.
Don't worry, we're going to lock it down in a subsequent lesson and practice with some different security
group configurations.
But for now, let's just open everything up.
I'm going to create my security group. And that's ready to use.
There's a file in your course download and that's in the code Amazon VPC Directory, and it's AWS CLI
Run Instances.
We need to add some values into this file.
The first thing we need to do for this command is specify an image ID. So, the command is aws ec2 run
-instances. And these are the values that we need to specify.
So first, let's find the AMI ID that we want to use.
AMI IDs are region specific, so we've got to make sure that everything we do in this lesson is within
the same region.
It's also where you created your custom VPC.
So for me, that's North Virginia.
Hopefully, it's the same for you.
Let's launch an instance. Next to the Amazon Linux 2 AMI,
let's grab this AMI ID.
Don't take anything in brackets there.
Copy that to the clipboard.
Come back and paste that it.
In the instance type, we can just type this in.
It's just going to be t2.micro. For security group ID,
let's go back and find the ID of our security group.
I can see my public web access security group.
Let's just copy that security group
ID, come back and paste that one in.
Then we need the subnet ID.
This time, I'm back in the VPC management console.
Let's go to subnets. First,
I want the public-1A subnet ID. So, I'm just going to copy that to my clipboard.
Key name is the key pair that you're using in this specific region.
Back in EC2, you can go to key pairs if you don't remember what it is and just copy this name and we
can paste
that in.
Lastly, there's some user data that we're going to specify.
Now, this is the user data file.
What it does is it runs a web server and then it creates a couple of variables from the metadata where
it actually grabs the subnet ID.
And it basically just puts that into a simple web page so we can see where the instance is running. In
our command here,
we just need to specify the name of that file.
Now, what you want to do is change to your Amazon VPC directory where we have all of this information
and this is where the file is.
So copy that to your clipboard.
Make sure you have the file:// and then the name of your file.
Now, let's copy this and make sure it works before we fill out the other two.
Now you will have had to run
AWS Configure before you do this exercise. You should have specified an access key ID,
secret access key, and your region must be the same as the region where we're trying to deploy our instances
now. So mine is all good. Let's paste in this command and run the command. That appears successful.
And we can see that we have an instance running in US-East-1A and there's quite a bit of information
if you just space bar and go down the page here.
So let's go into EC2 and check
it's launching. Back in EC2, I can see I have this instance at the bottom here running.
Now, I'm just going to label this one as public-1A
so I know which one it is. Now, the next thing we need to do is to go back over to the VPC management
console,
take the subnet ID of public-1B, and come back to our file. And we're going to use this one.
So what we can do is copy all of this.
Put it in 1B here, and then I'm going to take this subnet ID and just overwrite this one here.
So we should now be able to launch into public-1B. Let's copy this to our clipboard, come back and paste
it in.
That looks good.
If I refresh the page here, we have this pending instance.
That's the public-1B.
So I'll just give that a label so we know which one it is.
And then lastly, we're going to launch the instance in our private subnet.
So again, I just need to get the subnet ID for private-1B.
So I've copied that to my clipboard, come back, paste that in.
And now we have the command.
And this user data should run okay
in the private subnet because we're able to connect out to the internet via the NAT gateway.
So I paste this in. Hit enter. There we go,
we should have another instance.
Back in EC2, I can see my pending instance here.
So let's call this one private-1B. Great,
so I have these instances.
Let's just give a refresh and see where we're at.
So a couple of them are running. Let's sort by name. That might make things a bit easier.
I'm just going to copy to my clipboard the public IP for public-1A and paste this into a browser
window.
And I get this web page. And it gives me the subnet ID. So that should correspond with the subnet for
public-1A.
So that's great.
We've proved that we can connect from the internet to our EC2 instance.
Now, the other thing I want to do is connect between my EC2 instances. Back in the console here,
what I'm going to do is connect to public-1A.
Use the EC2 instance connect.
And while that's just connecting, let's come back. Next,
I want to get the private IP address of my public-1B instance, and that's 10.0.2.25.
And let's just change back to the EC2 instance connect.
And I'm going to ping 10.0.2.25 and let's see if that responds.
So that proves that we have connectivity to our instance in the other public subnet, public subnet 1B.
So we have two-way connectivity,
the response is coming back as well.
So that's great.
Lastly, let's check that we can connect to our private subnet.
So let's see what the private IP address is.
It's 10.0.4.148.
So let's ping 10.0.4.148 and let's see if that works. And it does.
So, we get an ICMP response.
So that's great.
That shows that we have that connectivity working.
One other thing we could do from here is see if we can connect to that web page.
So we'll use the call command and specify 10.0.4.148 and hit enter.
And we get a response here that says this instance is in the subnet with ID and it gives us the subnet
ID.
So that's the H1 header for the HTML web page that we have on that website. So, we can see that we have
port 80 open as well.
We're able to connect to the instance in the private subnet. And we can also infer from that that the
instance can connect out to the internet because it was able to install that web service.
So that's it for our connectivity testing for now.
Now, I'm going to leave all of these instances and the Nat gateway running because we're going to come
back and carry on when we do some testing with security groups and network ACLs.