In this lesson, I'm going to show you how to create and attach EBS volumes in the AC two management
console.
I'm going to go to launch templates and use the launch template we created earlier, and that makes
it a bit easier to launch my instance.
So I'm going to launch instance from template.
Now I do need to change a couple of things.
I need to select the option, proceed without a keeper and I need to select a subnet and I'm going to
choose Public one A and that has to be in the same VPC as our security group, which in this case it
is.
So now I should be able to launch my instance.
Great.
That's launching.
So while my instance is launching, let's just refresh here so we can see it.
We are going to go down to EBS and the volumes pane here.
Choose volumes.
Now you can see that we already have a volume and that is the route volume for the instance that we
just launched.
And you can see that it's in use.
So what we're going to do is create a extra volume.
So we choose create volume.
Now we get to choose the volume type.
So we could choose GP to GP free IO one, IO two or the older hard disk drives, the C one or RST one
or even the magnetic, which has been around a long time.
Now if we choose something like the IO one, you get to configure the performance characteristics such
as the input output per second.
The IOPS.
You get to specify the size, of course, as well.
Now, what we'll do is we'll keep things a bit cheaper.
We'll go to GP two and we'll keep the 100 gigabytes and it tells us the fixed performance that we can
get for this particular volume.
Now which availability zone should we put it in?
Well, we just selected us East one A for instance.
That means this volume needs to be in US East one, eh?
Because otherwise the instance won't be able to use it.
So we do need to use the US one a availability zone.
Now you can optionally encrypt the volume and you can choose to use the default key from us.
And that will encrypt the volume and all the data that's stored on it.
I'm not going to select this option for now.
Let's choose create volume.
So the volume is now in the creating state, and it shouldn't take very long before it's ready.
Okay, so the volume is now available.
If I select the volume going to actions, we can then attach the volume.
So note that you can also modify in here.
So if you needed to change the volume type or the size of the volume or obviously you could change the
performance characteristics of IO one as well.
But we'll keep it on GP too.
I'm not going to modify it.
All I want to do is attach it to my EC2 instance.
So now I'm going to attach the volume and I should be able to find my instance nice and easily.
It's going to decide the device name to use and we can click on attach volume and that's it.
That's all there is to it.
We've now attached an additional volume to our instance that we could then partition and format and
use.
Now, what will happen to this volume if we terminate our instance?
Well, the root volume by default will be deleted when you terminate your instance, but any extra volumes
that you add will by default still remain in your account.
So if we terminate the instance, we should find that this extra volume remains behind.
So let's test that out.
Let's go back to instances and I'm going to terminate my ESI two instance.
And if we come back to volumes.
What we should see shortly is that that volume will be removed and the additional volume will remain
and it will be available for us to attach to another EC2 instance.
So there we go.
That didn't take long.
The root volume was deleted and the extra volume is now available for us to use and attach to another
AC two instance.
So EBS is persistent storage and you can keep that data long term and move your volumes between instances
if you need to.
That's it for this lesson.
I will see you in the next one.