Welcome to another hands on lesson.
In this lesson, we're going to create an Amazon FS file system and mount it to two instances across
two availability zones.
Now remember that the FS file systems are mounted to Linux instances and we'll need to run some commands
on Linux.
The first one here is where we make a mount point.
This is a directory on the Linux instance to which we will mount the file system.
Then there's a couple of ways that we can install the utilities we need and mount the file system.
The first is using the standard NFS client and for that we would install the NFS utils and then run
this command.
Now this command specifies the file system some parameters and then in red here we can see the DNS name
for the file system and it gets mounted to the mount point.
That means that if you write some files to this location, you will see those written to the FS file
system.
Now, the other way, and what we're going to do is to use the AWS fs utils for that.
We install the Amazon FS utils package and then we use the Mount Helper command to actually mount the
file system.
And that's what we're going to do when we're ready to mount our file system.
So let's head over to the console.
I'm in the easy to management console and first what we're going to do is create a security group and
then our instances I'm going to click on Create Security group call this one FS access and add the same
into the description.
It can stay in the default VPC for inbound rules.
We'll need to manage our instances using SSH, and I'll need to allow that from anywhere.
Now I do need to add another rule for FS, but at this point I won't be able to do it the way I want
to.
I'll show you what I mean.
If I type NFS before the network file system, we get the port range specified.
But what I want to do is I want to secure it to the security group itself and I can't see the security
group when I type.
SG.
I can see other security groups in here, but I can't see the ID of this security group, so I can't
do that one yet.
What I have to do is create the security group.
Then we're going to run.
EDIT inbound rules, add a new inbound rule again, Type NFS protocol is correct, and then let's type
SG This time we can see the group.
This security group will be attached to our instances, but it will also be attached to the file system.
And this rule we've just added will allow inbound traffic on the NFS port from the instances that have
this security group attached.
So let's click on Save Rules.
That one's done.
Let's go to instances and it's launched two instances.
Now what I'm going to do is use the Linux to Amy so defaults there t to micro don't need a key pair.
That's fine.
We're going to select an existing security group, we're going to choose FS access.
And the only other thing I want to do is click on, edit and select my subnet.
This one will go into USSD one A and that's basically it.
Let's just launch that instance.
Then we're going to go back, launch a second instance, and it will have the same settings except it's
going to be in US East one B So let's add the security group, come in to subnets and there's one B
there.
Okay, So they're in different subnets.
And that's it.
The instances are launching.
Great.
So let's go over to FS and create our file system.
So I'm going to search for FS.
Open it up in a new tab.
And this is the console page for FS and all we need to do here is simply create a file system.
We can optionally give it a name, I just call it my FS file system.
We'll leave it in the default VPC the same as our instances and we'll leave the standard storage class,
selected it and we'll just create our file system.
There are more options if you want to customize the performance and other characteristics, but we'll
just create.
All right.
So that is being created and that will take a couple of minutes.
Now, if we click on the file system and we come in here and then go to network, what you'll see is
that it's creating these mount targets in all of these different availability zones.
But there's also a DNS name here.
Now we're going to copy that DNS name and use it for our commands.
So I have this document open.
This is in the course download, which you find at the end of section one of the course.
Unzip the file and then in the code Amazon FS directory you'll find this document called Amazon FS commands
MD.
What I need to do is delete out this DNS name here.
So we should be left with just this colon and a slash and then paste in the correct one.
So now I have the correct ID for my file system.
So make sure your document looks like this.
We'll be using this shortly.
Now we're going to run these commands in order, so I'll copy the first one.
Let's go to EC two.
I'm going to refresh the page, so I've got my two instances and I'm going to open easy, to instance,
connect for each of these instances.
So just open up instance, connect for each one and we're going to run the same commands on each instance.
Okay, so let's paste in this command here.
This is going to run the update manager.
Do the same for the second instance.
While that's happening, I'm going to go and get the other command.
Let's come back to the first instance.
There was nothing to update, which is good.
Let's just make that directory that's been done and do the same for the second instance.
Then we're going to install the fs utils.
So let's copy this command, go back to my first instance, paste the command that's installing very
quickly, do the same for the second instance.
So we're ready to mount now, but we need to do a couple of things first.
So let's go back to FS.
Let's refresh the page.
Now you can see that the security group is default and we don't want that.
We want to click on Manage because we have our own security group.
This one is not going to work.
Now our instances are in UX, one, A and B, So for ease, let's remove these other points.
We don't need them.
I'll get rid of the default security group and then I'm going to add in FS access to each of these.
So now we've enabled the mount points only in the US s1a and one B availability zones and we have a
security group attached and that security group will allow inbound access on the NFS port from the instances
because they are in the security group.
All right, let's go down and we're going to save this.
And we now have the DNS name in our command.
So we should be able to mount this file system.
So back in the document, I'm going to copy the entire Mount Command and I've already updated my DNS
name, so it is correct.
Let's come back to our first instance here and I'm going to clear the screen and bring this down so
you can see what's going on.
Let's click on Mount.
And that's done.
So the fact that we don't get an error message is good news.
I'll do the same here.
Let's run this command.
And again, we've mounted the file system.
So we should be able to change directory to the FS mount point now and then create data there and we
should be able to see that data from the other instance.
So we have our file system mounted.
Now if I change directory to the mount point, which should be in my current folder so I can change
directory to FS, Mount Point and then run LHS.
Of course there's nothing in there.
So what I'm going to do is run sudo make directory test directory and now we have a directory and I
could run sudo touch test file and then I have a file as well.
Okay.
So that's all I'm going to do.
Just add a couple of things and hopefully when we mount the directory from the instance in the alpha
availability zone, it should see the same information.
So back on my second instance, I'm going to change directory to the FS Mount Point run LS and of course
there are my files.
So that's it.
We have launched two instances and attach them to an RFS file system and we can read and write data
from multiple availability zones to the same FS file system.
So that's it for this lesson.
What I'm going to do is I'm going to go back and I'm going to terminate my two instances.
And then I'm going to also delete my FS file system so the instances are going down.
Let's go back to FS, click on file systems, select the file system, choose delete, and then we just
need to enter the idea of the file system, which I can just copy from here and then confirm.
And that's it.
That should start deleting fairly soon.
Just keep an eye on it.
Make sure it does.
And I will see you in the next lesson.