In this lesson,
I'm going to cover routing and session management for the Elastic Load Balancer.
So firstly we're going to look at an Application Load Balancer.
Here, we have multiple subnets in different availability zones
and we have our workload distributed across those subnets.
Now we've actually got each of these,
each of these tiers of our application perhaps in a different target group.
So we've got TG1, TG2, and TG3.
Now they're used by the ALB
to route requests to the registered instances within each of the target groups.
So we have an application load balancer here
and we can configure rules on the listener.
Now ALBs will listen on HTTP or HTTPs.
So let's say we have a client here.
And the client is trying to connect to our application and they've typed in the URL
example.com/specials.
Now it reaches the load balancer
and the load balancer sends this specific request to TG1.
So why does it do that?
Well, we've got a couple of options for how we distribute
or route our traffic to our different target groups.
Requests can be routed based on the path in the URL.
So in this case the path has been used and slash specials has been used
by the load balancer to determine where to route the traffic.
So it's using the path in the URL.
Maybe the user now clicks on another link and they go to orders.
Now orders might be processed by a different part of the application.
So now we have the connection going through to target group two.
So as I mentioned that this is where we're using the path in the URL
and that's called path-based routing with the ALB.
And it's one of several different ways we can intelligently route our traffic.
Another way we can do it is by using the host header information.
So here the customer is connected to members.example.com,
and the load balancer can now see members in the host header
and it knows that that means it should route the traffic
to target group three instead.
Here the request is being routed based on the host field in the HTTP header.
And this is known as host-based routing.
With our ALB, the targets can be EC2 instances,
IP addresses, Lambda functions, or containers.
Next we have the Network Load Balancer.
So again, let's say we have workloads across multiple subnets.
And in this example we have two target groups.
We've got a Network Load Balancer and we've got elastic IP addresses attached to each
of our subnets for our load balancer to use.
So NLB nodes can have elastic IPs in each subnet.
So that's a static public IP address that your NLB can
use and that can be white listed in your client's firewalls.
NLBs can listen on multiple protocols, TCP TLS, UDP, or TCP_UDP.
So here again we have a client who wants to connect to an application.
They've typed in example.com.
And the Network Load Balancer has routed the request to target group one.
If the client then connects to example.com again,
but this time they're using the colon :8080 to indicate
that they want to connect to the port 8080
rather than the default port for the protocol.
So the default ports for the protocol would be 443 for HTTPS,
but now we're indicating that we want to connect 8080.
The NLB can't do host-based or path-based routing like the ALB.
But we can create different listeners.
And each of those will require a unique port for routing.
Now the connection can get routed to target group two
if the connection is made with a different port number.
So here we're using the IP protocol data in the connection request to route the
connection to a different target group.
Targets can be EC2 instances or IP addresses.
Targets can also be outside of a VPC such as on-premises data centers.
Now what about session state?
So session state is where we want to store some information somewhere about a session
that's taking place on one of our applications like an application running on EC2.
So that will help us if a connection needs to be made again
and we don't want to have to recreate that information, so we want it to be there.
So we want some session state data.
Maybe it's authentication information.
Maybe if it's a gaming application,
it's information about the current gaming session.
So here we have multiple instances.
We have a client connecting to a load balancer
and getting sent to one of the instances.
Now what happens here is
information about the session is getting stored in a DynamoDB table.
DynamoDB is a great option for storing session state data.
Elasticache is another one that sometimes comes up in exam questions
in relation to session state data.
So what happens now is if the EC2 instance fails then the connection needs
to be made again and it gets made to a different EC2 instance.
But that instance can go and pull the cached information that's in
the DynamoDB table so that session state data doesn't get lost.
And in this case maybe it's authentication information
so the user does not get asked to re-authenticate
when they're connecting to the new instance.
So hopefully they won't even notice that anything happened.
Elasticache as I mentioned is another
popular solution for storing session state data.
We then have something called sticky sessions.
What this is, is when our connection goes through to a certain EC2 instance,
a cookie is generated and client bound to the instance for a specific lifetime.
So how long the cookie actually lives in their cache.
Session state data such as authentication details may be
stored locally here or they could also get stored
in something like DynamoDB so we don't lose that information.
But for some reason we might want to make sure that
if the client reconnects they come back to this same instance.
So that's what the cookie will tell them to do.
Now, if the instance fails, then a connection will need to be made to a new instance
and now the client is directed to that instance
and obviously the session state data is going to be lost.
So you could use it with a session store like DynamoDB
if you want to make sure that information is available.
So that's it for this lesson. I will see you in the next one.