Welcome to another hands-on lesson.
In this one we're going to launch an application load balancer
and attach it to our Auto Scaling group.
In the EC2 management console we already have our Auto Scaling group ASG1.
And it has a desired capacity of two and there are actually two running instances.
Now if I click on instances and if I
select one of these instances and click on networking,
we can see the subnet is public-1B.
Let's have a look at the other instance.
Go to networking.
And it's in public-1A.
Great, that's exactly what I wanted.
Next, I'm going to create a target group for our load balancer.
So I'm going to select crate target group.
Now, the target type for this is going to be instances
because we already have our EC2 instances.
Alternatively, you can use IP addresses, you can direct traffic to Lambda functions
and even other ALBs.
Now I'm going to call this TG1.
The protocol is going to be HTTP, the port is going to be 80.
So this is where traffic is going to be directed to from the load balancer.
And of course we have a web application, a simple Apache website running on Port 80.
I need to make sure my VPC is correct.
I'm using this VPC for the Auto Scaling group and the instances.
So I need to have the same one for my load balancer.
I'm going to leave the protocol version.
For health check, we've got either HTTP or HTTPS.
HTTP is fine. We don't have a certificate on the instance so we can't use HTTPS.
We can click next.
And you can see that there are instances. I could directly add the instances
to the target group but I don't want to do that.
So let's just click on create target group.
So that is the target group created.
Next, we're going to create the load balancer.
So let's create a load balancer.
Now I'm going to choose an Application Load Balancer. Click on create.
I'm going to call it ALB 1.
It's going to be an internet-facing load balancer
so we can connect to it from the internet using IPv4.
I don't want to use dual stack which means you get IPv4 and six.
Again, I want to make sure that my VPC is correctly selected.
And I'm going to select us-east-1A and 1B.
And in those two I want to make sure that I've got my public subnets, so public-1A.
In this case it's chosen the wrong one. So public-1B.
For security groups, I don't want to use this one.
I want to select my web access security group which already has HTTP enabled.
For listeners and routing,
we're going to create a listener which listens on port 80, that's HTTP
and then it forwards traffic to target group one, and remember
target group one also then is listening on port 80.
So the traffic comes straight through to the web application running on that port.
Now we don't need a global accelerator,
let's just come down and select create load balancer.
So that's the load balancer being created.
And you can see it's in a provisioning status.
But we haven't actually connected the instances to the target group.
We've connected the target group to the load balancer
but the Auto Scaling group is currently detached.
So what I want to do there is go to Auto Scaling groups,
click on ASG1,
scroll down and under load balancing, click on edit,
choose Application, Network or Gateway Load Balancers,
and then choose my target group.
So by doing it this way what happens is any time a new instance is launched
into the Auto Scaling group, it will be picked up by the
load balancer and load balancing will include that instance.
So let's select update.
And that's done.
So now it's just a matter of waiting for a few minutes for it all to start working.
Now if I go across to target groups,
select TG1, we can see that we have our two instances
and the health status is initial.
And that means that target registration is in progress.
So those instances will be registered and they should turn to healthy very soon.
So it just took a couple of minutes and now the health status has changed to healthy.
So our instances are registered.
Now if your instances don't become healthy, if they become unhealthy then
there's something wrong in your configuration so if you do follow
all of my steps exactly, you will get the same result.
But if you don't then it must mean that you've missed something.
So one of the things to check is your security groups to make sure
you have your security groups set up to allow port 80.
We use the same security group for the instances and the load balancer.
So make sure you're using a security group that allows inbound
traffic from any source to port 80.
The other thing you can do is actually go
and try and connect directly to your instance using its public iP address.
So if I copy the public IP
and try and connect, I should see direct access to the instance.
If that doesn't work then you've done something wrong.
You need to make sure that the user data run correctly,
your instance has public connectivity to the internet and is reachable,
and of course you have the security groups set up.
So ours looks good.
So let's go down to load balancers.
And what I'm going to do is I'll just copy the DNS name of the load balancer,
go to a new tab in my browser,
put that in, and we can see that we get a result.
Now if I just hit refresh, we should get load balanced between the instances
in the different availability zones.
So that's all working.
So that's it for this lesson.
Now, we have finished with the load balancer and the Auto Scaling group.
So what we're going to do is simply terminate the load balancer
by clicking on delete, click on yes delete.
Now don't delete the target group.
We are going to use that again. So you can leave the target group.
There's no cost to having a target group.
The other thing we're going to do is to terminate the Auto Scaling group.
So we can select our auto scaling group, click on delete.
We need to type delete to confirm and then delete.
And that will delete the Auto Scaling group and the EC2 instances.
So that's it for this lesson. I'll see you in the next one.