Hi guys, in this lesson we're going to use the Command Line Interface to create
an Auto Scaling group and an Application Load Balancer.
Now it does rely on the fact that you performed the
lessons using the management console earlier on because we're going to use the same
launch template and target group that we created earlier.
In the course download,
you'll find the EC2 directory and you'll find this file, create-asg-alb-cli.md.
Now, in here you're going to find the commands that we need to run.
So what we need to do is make sure that the information in here is correct
before we run these commands.
So the first one is to create the Auto Scaling group.
So we use the command AWS Auto Scaling group, create Auto Scaling group.
We give it a name. I'm going to call mine ASG2.
We give it a launch template.
I already called my launch template My EC2 Web App.
So I'm going to use the same name here.
I want the minimum size to be one, max to be three,
and the desired capacity to be two.
And I want to use two availability zones, us-east-1A and us-east-1B.
Now for those availability zones we need to specify the zone identifiers.
That's the subnet IDs.
So let's make sure those are correct.
In the VPC management console, I'm going to go to subnets,
choose public-1A,
and then copy the subnet ID.
Come back,
paste that in, mine was already correct and then do the same for public-1B.
So just make sure you got the correct subnets IDs.
Mine's already done so there shouldn't be any change there.
That's all ready to go.
So now I can copy this whole command to my clipboard,
and on a command prompt, I'm going to run this command.
You know how to use profiles. We did that earlier on in this course.
And what I'm going to use is a profile which is called cloud labs.
And that profile has access keys associated with my user account.
So make sure you have your CLI set up with your user credentials,
not the ones we used for Paul earlier on.
And if you need to either delete the credentials file and recreate it by
running AWS Configure or just create a profile for your specific user name.
So let's try and run enter and see if this works.
And we didn't get any response in terms of error messages so it looks like it worked.
Let's go to the EC2 management console,
go to Auto Scaling groups,
give it a refresh.
And there we go. We've got the ASG2.
And we can see the desired capacity of two.
So we should find that means that our instances are going to be launched.
Let's refresh EC2.
And we've got two pending instances here.
So that worked.
Next we need to create the load balancer, create a listener and then attach TG1,
the target group one to ASG2.
So the first one is the create load balancer command.
Note that this is AWS ELBV2 create load balancer.
We're going to call it ALB2.
Now, I've already added my subnet IDs.
So, you can copy yours down from the first command
and then --security groups.
And I've specified my security group ID.
For that, you can go back to the management console
and simply copy the security group ID
for the web access security group that you're using.
So that's all set up.
Let's copy this to my clipboard.
I'm going to paste that in.
Again, I'm going to use my profile, hit enter,
and that should create the load balancer.
And we can see some information about what's being created.
Back in the EC2 management console, we should now be able to go down to load balancers
and if we give this a refresh we should soon see our load balancer.
I need to remove this filter.
And there we go. We've got ALB2 and that's being created.
It's in a provisioning state.
The next command is to create the listener, so we need a listener
and we need to specify the ports that we're going to listen on the
protocol and also what we're going to do for forwarding.
So in this case, we create a listener using AWS ELBV2 create listener.
And then we have --load-balancer-ARN.
And this is the ARN of our load balancer.
So simply come back to the management console, copy the ARN
for your load balancer, come back here.
I need to update mine.
So let's paste this in.
Now I've got my ARN correctly set.
The protocol is HTTP the port is 80
and the default actions are to forward to a target group
And we need to get the ARN for our target group.
So let's find our target group.
Copy the ARN,
and then paste it in.
So let's go here to target group ARN equals, remove this,
paste it in, and we've got our command.
So let's create our listener.
I'll paste that onto my command line and again specify my profile
and hit enter.
So that's done.
So if we go back to the management console,
we should be able to see this configuration.
Let's look at our load balancer, click on listeners,
and that's the listener we just created.
That's forwarding to target group one.
Now the only thing to do now is we need to attach
the target group to the load balancer.
For that, we're using the AWS Auto Scaling attach low balancer target groups.
The Auto Scaling group name is ASG2.
And then the target group ARN
is the ARN of our target group, so I'm going to copy that from up here
and then just override that information.
So now I have the correct ARN for my target group.
Copy to the clipboard, paste it in, add my profile information,
and hit enter.
And I think that's worked.
So now if we go back to our Auto Scaling group,
choose ASG2, scroll down
and we can see that we have the target group one attached to the load balancer.
So let's go and grab the ARN
for our load balancer, in fact the DNS name.
Let's copy the DNS name, go to a new tab in my browser and hit enter.
And there we go.
Just as before we now have instances running.
So that's how we can do this all using the Command Line Interface.
If you want to delete your load balancer, an auto scaling group
using the command line, you can do that using these commands here.
I do need my load balancer at ARN.
So let's take that from here.
Copy and then I'll paste it into this command.
And lastly we only need the ASG2 name.
So it just requires the name of the Auto Scaling group.
So first let's delete our load balancer.
And that's done.
And then I'm going to delete my Auto Scaling group as well.
So now if we come back to the EC2 management console, refresh,
load balancer has gone.
And if I go down to Auto Scaling groups, we can already see
that it's in a deleting state.
So that should remove the load balancer,
the Auto Scaling Group and the EC2 instances.