In this hands-on lesson, we're going to create some tables in DynamoDB,
add some items and look at some configuration settings.
So I'm logged into DynamoDB.
And what I'm going to do first here is create a new table.
So the first thing we need to do is give it a name.
I'm simply going to call mine My Forum.
Then we must enter a partition key. So this is mandatory we need a partition key.
I'm going to call mine Post ID.
So the idea here is that I'm creating a forum and in that forum the
partition key will be the ID of the post which should be a unique value.
Now optionally you can create a sort key but for
this particular table we're not going to do that.
Now if I scroll down a little way you can see
that we have the default settings applied.
If we want to customize settings we can choose customize,
we can choose the table class.
So we have the standard class or the infrequently-accessed class.
So IA would be recommended for tables that store data that's infrequently accessed.
And that might save you some money.
Then we have the read and write capacity settings.
The capacity calculator is a really useful tool for calculating the read
capacity units and write capacity units you need for your table.
So that will provide the amount of performance that you need.
And it also is linked then to billing.
So in here you can enter the average item size that you're expecting,
how many reads a second, how many writes a second,
and then which model you want to use for consistency.
Now we'll be covering the RCUs and WCUs.
and the various different consistency models a bit later on in this section.
So next we actually have the read write capacity settings.
So the calculator helps you work out what you need
and then you can specify them either using on-demand or provisioned.
With on-demand, you're paying for the actual reads and writes
that your application performs,
whereas provisioned you're actually provisioning a certain allocation
and then if you don't use it you still end up paying for it.
So you've got to understand what's best for your model.
Then we can specify individually the read capacity and write capacity that we need.
Secondary indexes are something we're going to cover a bit later in this section.
And here we can see an estimated cost.
And this should fall well within the free tier.
For encryption at rest there's a couple of options for the key that's used.
Now the data is always encrypted but you get to
choose whether it's the key that's owned by DynamoDB, whether it's an AWS-managed key
or it's one that you're storing in your account.
So you're using the key management service.
So I'm not changing any of those settings. I'm just going to create my table.
The table has been created. That just took a few seconds.
Now on the left hand side here we have tables so we can then choose our table
and then we go into update settings where we can change the settings
of our table or explore items where we can actually see the items.
We don't have any items at this point.
So under update settings, you'll see that there's various different options here.
We will be exploring most of these throughout this section.
What I'm going to do now is create a couple of items. So let's go to explore items.
I'm going to create an item, so I'm manually going to add an item into my table.
So in this example I'm adding a post to my forum.
And it has a specific value. So that's the unique value for this post.
Now I might also want to add additional attributes, so let's add a string.
And this is going to be the subject
and I'm simply going to type Hello.
Then I'm going to add another attribute.
This time it's going to be a number.
So you see there's various different
options for the type of attribute that we create.
And this one will be replies, and we'll give it a number, let's make that 12.
So I'm gonna create my item.
So my item has been created.
And we can now see it in the table.
Now I want to create another item.
And what I'm gonna do is I'm going to
attempt to create another item with the same information.
So let's just enter all of the same values as before
add the number.
This one is going to be replies 12.
And let's try and create this item.
And we have a error message. And that is the conditional request failed.
An item with the primary key you provided already exists.
So of course we could change the number of replies.
It doesn't matter.
We can change the subject line.
That also doesn't matter.
The only thing that matters is the post ID.
Because we don't have a sort key, so we're not using what's called a composite key.
We must have a unique value for this item here.
So what I'm going to do is just change that value and create the item.
And this time it will work successfully.
Now let's go back up to tables.
And we're going to create a second table.
This one is going to be called my store
as if we're creating a store for an eCommerce backend.
Now I'm going to add in a partition key.
This time it's going to be client ID.
It's also going to be a string.
And then we're also going to add a sort key. So now we're creating a composite key.
So a partition key with a sort key.
And the sort key is going to be created.
And I'm going to leave that as a string.
And there's various different ways you can record dates and times.
So other than that, I'm not changing anything. So let's just create this table.
So my store has now been created. Let's click on my store, go to explore items.
We're going to create an item.
Now you'll see that we must enter both the client ID and the created.
So both of these boxes are here already for us.
I'm going to enter an email address for the client ID.
And then I'm going to enter a timestamp for created.
And then we could add something else. So this is supposed to be an eCommerce store.
So let's say that we're adding a category
for our products.
And this one might be a phone.
And let's just create that item.
So now we have that item in our table. We can see the client ID,
the created timestamp, and the category.
What I want to do now is create an additional item.
And it's also going to be another order from the same user, so the same client ID.
Now remember that with my forum,
we weren't able to do that because there was only a partition key, no sort key.
And the post ID in this case had to be unique. We couldn't have two of the same.
But that wouldn't be good in a store because we want the
same person to come back and buy multiple items from our store.
So there's going to be an additional entry from Chris.
But as long as there's a different timestamp which there always should be,
then the two together become unique. So that's the composite key.
So let's create an item.
And I'm going to put chris@example.com again.
I'm going to paste in a timestamp which is a different timestamp to before.
And then we can add in some kind of attributes.
So maybe this time I'll add category computer.
And let's create that item.
So this time it worked.
And that's because we have a composite key.
So the combination of the client ID and the created timestamp, the sort key here
are unique.
So that works really well for this eCommerce store.
And that's it for this lesson.
Now we've finished with my forum but we're going to keep my store.
So I'm going to go back to update settings, choose my forum, go to actions,
and delete table.
And then I just need to type delete
and that table will be deleted for us.