Hi guys. In this lesson, we're going to practice using the scan API with DynamoDB
and we're going to do so using the AWS CLI.
Now in your course download, you'll find this file.
So in the code directory, DynamoDB and then DynamoDB CLI commands.
And there's quite a few commands here.
Now we might not run every single one of these but you can certainly in your own time.
Now what you'll notice is the very first one here actually references a file.
So what we're doing here
is we're running this command AWS DynamoDB batch write item,
request items, and then we're supplying a file.
So we're actually going to populate our
DynamoDB table with some information that's stored
in here, in this mystore.json.
So this is the mystore.json file.
And what we're actually looking at here is we specify the table name.
So remember we created a table earlier called My Store.
Now if you created your table with a different name,
you need to go back and create My Store.
And you need to make sure you have the correct partition key and sort key as I used.
So once you've got your My Store table running,
then we're able to populate the data.
So our command is going to call this file and it's going to issue PUT requests
to put certain items into the DynamoDB table.
And they include information such as the client ID which is a string value
and an email address.
Created which is a timestamp,
SKU, category, a size and so on, quantity, which is a number.
So various information.
And the information that's included in
each of these different items may be different.
With some items, an attribute might have a string value whereas the same
attribute in a different item is a number value.
So that's the flexibility of DynamoDB.
So we've got all these items in here.
What we need to do is come back and copy these files to our clipboards
and then go to the CLI.
So I'm on the CLI here and I'm actually in
the directory in my course download where this file is.
So I've got mystore.json.
So I'm going to paste in that command.
And let's run this file.
So that looks good. That's a good response.
If we go to DynamoDB now, we should be able to find those items.
So back in DynamoDB I'm going to choose my store,
explore items,
and let's just give this a refresh.
And now we see all of these new items.
So lots of items with various different information.
Note that of course because of the composite key, they must all have the client ID
and the created values populated.
But for everything else it's optional.
So we've got various different attributes associated with our various items.
Let's now run the first scan command, this AWS DynamoDB scan.
And we literally just give it the table name.
So let's copy that to our clipboards
and I'll paste that in.
And we basically get the items.
So if I hit my space bar, I'm just finding that essentially all of the items are here.
Right at the bottom, it then tells me that the count is 23.
So that's how many items there are. That's how many were actually scanned.
So let's quit from there.
There's also an option to specify a page size parameter
and also here a max items.
Let's copy the max items.
And I've set it to two.
So I'm going to paste this one in.
and let's head answer.
And so now we have two items.
But note that the scan count is still 23
because remember with a scan it's still scanning everything
and it's just returning whatever you filtered it to return.
Back in our file, another thing we can do is use a projection expression parameter.
And we can specify stuff like the created or the category or the color.
So one of the attributes.
So let's copy this one, the first one on the list.
And let's run this command.
So now, note that we're returning just the information
about the various items. So we see a list of items
but all we're seeing is the created timestamp.
And again at the end we've got the scan count as 23.
So of course, if we did the same thing with another attribute like color,
we get a very similar result.
So let's run this command and now it's actually returning the color.
And of course in this case a lot of the items
do not have this attribute specified so they're just blank.
And then we can see the ones that do. There's just two of the items.
But again of course, we scanned 23 items.
There's then a filter expression parameter.
So now rather than filtering based on the attribute here,
we're looking for specific values of attributes.
So we're looking for the filter expression
and we're looking for the client IDs and where the user name is specified.
And then the expression attribute value
in this case we're looking for a specific user.
So let's copy this and go over and run this command.
So I'm going to hit enter.
And now I can see some items
that were ordered by Chris.
So you see the various different items here that were ordered by Chris.
We see a count of six and of course everything in the table was scanned.
In the next filter expression parameter example, we're looking for size
and numerical value and we're looking for one that is equal to
this specific value of 12.
So let's run this command.
And now we only get one item which has a size
that has a numerical value equal to 12.
The next command is very similar but it's looking for size greater than
and then the item value of 12.
So let's run this command and now we get some more results.
So that's just a few examples of how we can use
various different commands on the CLI to scan our DynamoDB table.
And in the next hands-on lesson,
we'll run some queries so you can see the difference between scanning and querying.