Welcome back. In this hands-on lesson,
we're basically carrying on from the previous one.
In the last lesson we looked at how to use the Scan API.
And the Scan API returns all items in a table
and then we're able to run various different parameters
in the command line to filter the results.
But what we want to use now is a query and a query can often be a lot more efficient.
So let's run some queries.
Now if we scroll down a little way, you'll find that
there's two different queries that we have available to us here.
So the first one the command is AWS DynamoDB query. We supply our table name.
And then we supply key conditions.
And the conditions are the client ID. We have a comparison operator of EQ,
that's equal to,
attribute value list, and then we're looking for an ID
that's a string value and it's chris@example.com.
So if I copy this to my clipboard.
Let's paste this in.
And I'm going to run this command.
So now I get the items back and again what we're seeing
as a result very similar to one of the scans we did
is a series of items that have been purchased by chris@example.com.
But notice the difference in the summary here.
So the scan count is six and that's equal to the actual count of items returned.
Whereas when we ran the scan API,
we had a count of six items returned but the scan count was 23.
So now we're not scanning the whole table,
we're querying specifically certain values and that can use fewer RCUs.
Next we're going to use a key condition expression parameter.
So this one is DynamoDB query. Again, we supply the table name.
We have key condition expression.
In this case it's client ID name
and then expression attribute values,
name,
and then it's a string value which is chris@example.com.
So this should be a very similar query to the one that we just ran.
So let's run this command.
And now we get a similar list of results.
So there's a lot of power to the API
and the way that you can scan and query your tables.
Now back in DynamoDB itself, we can scan and query items here so
we don't always have to use the CLI or the API.
We can actually run our search parameters here in the console.
So you can choose between scan and query.
For example, we can enter an attribute name
and I could put in here client ID.
And then similar to before, I could put in chris@example.com
and then run.
And again, we'll have a very similar
result where we're actually filtering what's returned.
And then using a query,
we can now choose our table or index,
we can specify the partition key,
and then we can specify sort key.
And we can add on various filters as well.
So the power that we have on the command line,
much of that is also available through the console as well.
So continuing with our example, let's use chris@example.com.
Under the sort key we can use equal to
or we can specify one of these different options.
So for example, I could say greater than or equal to.
And let's specify one of these created keys.
Enter that in.
And then for attribute name,
let's put in category
and then simply exists.
And let's run that query.
So that returned four items and we know that Chris has six items in the table.
But in this case the sort key was specified as being greater than
or equal to this value and the category must have that attribute populated.