Hi guys and welcome to the exam cram for amazon dynamo DB.
So dynamodb is a fully managed no SQL database service.
It's a key value store and also a document store.
It's non relational key value type of database and data is
stored in partitions which are replicated across multiple availability zones.
It provides low latency in the milliseconds.
Microsecond latency can be achieved if you add
dynamodb accelerated dax.
All data is stored on SSD storage and replicated across multiple Aziz in a region.
Global tables will synchronize tables across regions.
Dynamodb table classes are standard which is
default and the recommended for most workloads
and standard infrequent access,
which is lower cost for infrequently accessed data.
Dynamodb supports identity based policies, but not resource based policies.
There's two types of primary key. You've got a partition key and a composite key.
Composite key is a partition key plus a sort key in combination.
Best practices are to use high cardinality attributes,
use composite attributes and cash, your popular items.
So using decks,
you can use random numbers for write heavy use cases to spread across partitions.
Dynamodb supports eventually consistent and strongly consistent reads
with eventually consistent reads. When you read data from a table.
The response might not reflect the results of a recently completed write operation
with strongly consistent reads.
Dynamodb returns a response with the most up to
date data reflecting all updates from prior write operations,
strongly consistent reads use more throughput capacity
than eventually consistent reads
and dynamodb uses eventually consistent reads by default.
You can configure strongly consistent reads with a get item query and scan A. P. I. S.
Dynamodb transactions.
Makes coordinated all or nothing changes to multiple items,
both within and across tables,
transactions provide
at emissivity, consistency, isolation and durability
in dynamodb
enables the reading and writing of multiple items across
multiple tables as an all or nothing operation.
There's no additional cost to enable transactions for dynamodb tables.
You pay only for the reads or writes that are part of your transaction.
And dynamodb will perform two underlying reads
or writes of every item in the transaction
throttling occurs when the configured, R. C. U. Or W. C. You are exceeded
and you may receive a provision.
Throughput exceeded exceptions.
The scan operation returns one or more items and item attributes
by accessing every item in a table or a secondary index.
A query operation finds items in your table based on
the primary key attribute and a distinct value to search for
and else I provides an alternative sort key to use for scans and queries.
That's the local secondary index.
It gives you a different view of your data organized by alternative sort key.
A global secondary index. G. S. I is used to speed up crews on non key attributes.
You can specify a different partition key as well as a different sort key with a G. S.
I.
Optimistic locking is a strategy to ensure that the client side
item you're updating or deleting is the same as the item
in dynamodb
that protects database rights from being overwritten by
the rights of others and vice versa.
A T T L A Time to live attribute lets you define when items
in a table expire so that they can be automatically deleted from the database.
With GTL enabled on a table, you can set a time stamp for deletion on a per item basis,
there's no extra cost and it doesn't consume any W C U S or R C U S.
Dynamodb streams captures a time ordered sequence of item level modifications
in any dynamodb table.
The information is then stored in a log for up to 24 hours
tax is a managed service that provides in memory acceleration for dynamodb tables.
It will improve the performance from milliseconds to microseconds
even at millions of requests per second.
Global tables is a fully managed solution for deploying multi region,
multi master database.
When you create a global table,
you specify the regions where you want the table to be available.
That's it for this exam, cram, I'll see you in the next one