this section is about databases and analytics.
Now of course we did cover dynamodb a bit earlier on in the course.
That is a database technology but it's covered in such a large amount of
detail in the exam that I had a complete section just for that service.
Now,
what we're gonna do in this section is cover some of the other database services.
Now we've got to learn about amazon relational database service. RDS
that's a service we can use for managing relational databases in the cloud
such as SQL server or SQL we'll also look at amazon elasticache
which is used for running in memory databases in the cloud.
Lots of different use cases such as session stores or as a
front end to another database like a relational back end like RDS
I'll then go into quite a bit of detail on amazon kinesis
kinesis is a suite of different services
that deal with streaming data and analytics of streaming data.
And then lastly I'll cover amazon Opensearch, a relatively new service
and the successor to elasticsearch.
So lots to get on with. I'll see you in the next lesson