In this lesson I'm going to cover the Amazon Relational Database Service, RDS.
So, RDS is a managed relational database.
Now, it runs on EC2 instances, and that means you need to choose your instance type
to determine the performance characteristics for your database, the CPU, the memory,
the storage and so on.
Now, what types of database engines can we run?
Well, the first one is called Aurora.
That's the subject of another lesson. That's a proprietary AWS database.
Then you've got MySQL, MariaDB, Oracle, Microsoft SQL Server, and Postgres.
So quite a few to choose from.
Now, if the database you need is not on the list, you can't use RDS.
You have to install it on EC2.
With RDS, we can scale a couple of different ways.
So scaling up, scaling vertically is where we change our instance type.
So here we've moved from a db.m4.large with two CPUs and 8GB RAM
up to the M4, which has more processing power and more RAM associated with it.
So that scaling up.
Now we can also scale out for some specific performance characteristics.
And we can also implement disaster recovery so we can have some
high availability fault tolerance and disaster recovery for our applications.
So how does that work?
We have something called an RDS master.
So this is running in an availability zone and this is our primary database.
It's the one on which both reads and writes get performed.
We can then have a standby instance.
Now the master will synchronously replicate to the standby instance.
So the stand-by is always in sync with the master.
Now this is known as multi-AZ.
And you essentially have a passive standby which is used for disaster recovery.
So that means in a dire situation, when the master fails or becomes inaccessible, then the standby
can take over it automatically.
We also have a Read Replica.
Now, Read Replicas use asynchronous replication, so there's a little bit more of a delay
but they replicate from the master as well and they're used for scaling reads.
That means scaling the queries on your database.
So this is a way of scaling out, scaling horizontally, but only for queries.
So that's important to remember.
The Read Replica is used for queries, the writes still always go to the master database.
So here we have our app server and we can see in green all writes are going to the master, but reads
can instead go to the Read Replica so that we can scale and offload a bit of the performance impact
from the master to the replica.
So that's how that all works.
Now a little bit more about RDS.
So, just to recap, it does run on EC2 instances, so you have to choose the correct family and type.
It's a relational SQL type of database.
It's usually used for transactional use cases, so an operational database or OLTP.
Easy to set up, highly available.
It's fault tolerant and scalable as well.
So here you would use it for all sorts of operational and transactional use cases such as online stores
and banking systems just to name a couple.
You can encrypt your Amazon RDS databases as well, and that enables encryption at rest.
So the storage is encrypted.
You can also encrypt your connections to RDS.
An encryption uses the AWS Key Management Service, KMS.
Now, RDS supports the following database engines.
We covered these earlier.
So just remember SQL, Oracle, MySQL, Postgres, and Aurora as well as MariaDB.
And it scales up by increasing the instance size.
And Read Replicas are a good option for Read heavy workload, so you can scale the performance
horizontally as well.
And lastly, we have disaster recovery with the Multi-AZ option.
So that's it for the theory.
Let's go into some hands-on in the next lesson and launch an RDS database.