In this lesson, we're going to go into the console and create an RDS MySQL database.
I'm logged into the AWS management console and I'm on the dashboard for Amazon RDS.
Now, as you can see, AWS want to push you towards the Aurora,
so there's this great big button up here.
But what we want to do is we're going to create an RDS MySQL database.
So, under databases choose create database. We can then choose the standard or the easy create.
We're going to stick with standard.
Again, they're trying to push you towards Aurora, but we're going to select MySQL.
Now, if we scroll down to templates, there's three pre-defined templates, production, dev/test, and
free tier.
Now, we will switch to free tier in a moment.
But there are some configuration options that are removed when you do that.
So, I want to show you first those configuration options.
Now, I'm going to call my database Digicloud.
I'm going to leave the master username as admin, enter a password, and then confirm that password.
You then get some options for the DB instance class.
And there's quite a lot of options here, many of which will cost quite a bit of money.
So you want to be careful here.
We're going to use a t2.micro, but it's not available at this point in time. So, I'll leave it on standard.
And we're going to scroll down.
Next, you have storage. Now,
as you can see, by default, we're going to have a provisioned IOPS SSD io1 volume with 100 GiB
allocated and a provisioned IOPS of 3,000.
Now this is for this production database, so it's going to change soon when we switch to a free tier
database.
With RDS, you can auto scale the storage layer and by default, that is enabled.
We also have Multi-AZ, which on this production template is also enabled by default.
That's going to change when we switch to free tier as well.
I'm going to leave it in the default VPC.
I'm not going to change the subnet group. Now, for public access,
if you want your database to be accessible from the internet, then you would choose
yes. If you have instances in EC2 and you want to talk to your database on a private IP, then you
would leave it on
no.
By default, the default security group is added.
Now, bear in mind, there might not be a rule that allows the relevant port.
The port is 3306 for MySQL.
So if you do want to connect an EC2 instance to your database, you'll need to make sure that your
security group has a rule allowing 3306 from your application instances.
There are three options here for database authentication.
The default is password, and we're going to leave it on that one.
You can also have a password with IAM database authentication, and you can choose Password and Kerberos,
and then you would add a directory.
Now we don't have a directory, let's leave it on password.
We then have some additional configuration options.
Now you can see the estimated monthly cost here, and as you can see, it does cost quite a bit of money
this database.
So, you certainly don't want to launch this one.
Now, let's just expand additional configuration.
We do need to provide a name here.
I'm going to call it Digicloud.
Automated backups are enabled by default with seven-day retention.
Now remember, if you don't want to have automated backups, you would put it to zero days and the
maximum is 35.
We can leave it on seven.
You can select a backup window of your preference or leave it on no preference. When using the production
template,
encryption is enabled by default, and it's using the AWS RDS default key.
So, let's just leave that option
for now, that is going to be removed when we go to free tier as well. There's then performance insights,
which is enabled by default, and that will log more detailed information about performance and you
can retain that data and encrypt it.
Monitoring, there's another option for monitoring here where you can get more granular, detailed information
about things like the threads of your CPU and the granularity can go right down to one second.
Under maintenance,
we have the auto minor version upgrade enabled. So, that will update automatically for minor database
version updates and that will do so during the maintenance window.
And we haven't specified a preference here.
Deletion protection simply means that you can't delete your database without an extra step.
Now, we're going to scroll back up to the top and switch to Free tier.
So, back at the top of the page, just scroll down to where the templates are and go to free tier. Now, most
of the settings will remain.
So, we've still got our database identifier, our admin and password. For burstable classes,
we now have a t2.micro option. So that's selected by default.
You'll notice that the amount of storage has reduced. Multi-AZ is now greyed out.
And when we scroll all the way down to the additional configuration, there's no option here now for
encrypting our database. But we're going to get around that in another lesson. So, we can leave now
all of these defaults, scroll to the bottom, and then create our database.
The database is now in a creating state.
Now, it can take quite a while with RDS for creating databases and modifying databases.
So, you want to sit back and be patient for a few minutes and then we'll continue.
The database creation has now completed and our database is available. Now,
you can see a couple of things here, such as the DB identifier and the region and availability zone
and the size of the database as well.
Now if we actually click on the database on the left,
we now get quite a bit more information. You can see here the end point, so this is the end point that
you would use in your application to connect to this database. And you would use the port 3306
because this is MySQL.
You can see which availability zone the database is running in, the VPC, subnet group, subnets, and so on.
This particular database is not publicly accessible.
You can see the security rules here. Now, as I mentioned before, to connect to this database
you'll also need a rule allowing inbound to port 3306.
We don't have any replication at this stage.
Now let's head up to the top.
Under monitoring, we get some relatively basic information about the database.
There are also some more advanced options for monitoring, including enhanced monitoring,
OS process list and performance insights, but they're not enabled on this database. Under logs
and events,
we can see where our CloudWatch alarms are if we have any,
some of the recent events, and then the log files.
Now, if you choose one of these log files, you can click on view
and it will actually show you the log file, there's nothing really in this one.
So, let's close out of there. Under configuration,
you get a summary of the current configuration of the database. And then under maintenance and backups,
you can see the backups that have been created.
So, we have the automated backups enabled here,
we can see a snapshot that's being created at the bottom.
Now, if we head over to snapshots on the left here, we have the system generated snapshots and we've
already got one.
And then we have manual snapshots.
So, in here, we can click on take snapshots, choose our database, and I'm going to create a snapshot.
I'm going to call it Digicloud unencrypted because this is an unencrypted database,
so we're creating a snapshot and that snapshot is going to be unencrypted.
So let's take the snapshot. And that task is now going to run.
And that would take a few minutes.
Let's go back up to databases, choose our database, and we also have the actions menu here.
Under actions, you can create a read replica, take a snapshot, restore to a specific point in time
using the automated backups, and you can stop, reboot, and delete your database as well.
Modify will take you back to the wizard, where you can change options like the DB instance size you're
using.
Now that's it for this lesson.
And what we're going to do in the next hands-on lesson is we're going to create a read replica and enable
Multi-AZ.