Hi, guys. In this lesson, we're going to dive a bit deeper into the security aspects of Amazon RDS.
So with RDS, we run our RDS databases within a VPC. Our RDS database will have an IP address.
Now, we can connect to an RDS database over the internet. And we saw that option in the console where
you can select to make your database publicly available.
Now we also have security groups assigned to our database.
So maybe you've got one called RDS SG.
We then have our EC2 instances, our applications that want to connect to the database.
They should also have their own security group. And according to best practice, they would have a separate
security group to the RDS database.
And then we'd create a rule that allows the App Security Group to access the database on the relevant
port.
If it's MySQL, that will be 3306.
Now we can also enable SSL/TLS encryption so that we have encryption in transit for the connection from
the application to the database. As well as encryption in transit,
we might want to encrypt the actual database volume at rest. For that we can enable RDS encryption,
which will encrypt the database at rest including the database volume and any snapshots that we create.
And that uses the advanced encryption standard 256-bit encryption.
So, with encryption at rest, that includes the database storage, backups, read replicas, and snapshots
that you might create.
You can only enable encryption at the point in time that you create the database, so it's not something
you can change after you've created the database. And that includes disabling encryption for databases
that you've already encrypted.
The AES 256-bit encryption is a very strong encryption standard, but it has minimal performance impact
on RDS.
If you're running Oracle or SQL Server, you also have support for the transparent data encryption standard
and that can have a performance impact.
The AWS Key Management Service, KMS is used for managing the encryption keys that you use to encrypt
RDS databases.
A couple of really important exam tips for RDS encryption.
So just to be clear, you cannot have an encrypted read replica of an unencrypted DB Instance or an
unencrypted read replica of an encrypted DB Instance.
So in other words, the read replica will always have the same encryption status as the primary. So,
a read replica of an encrypted primary will be encrypted. When you create a read replica,
the same KMS key is used if the replica is in the same region as the primary.
if the replica is in a different region, then a different KMS key will be used.
You also can't restore an unencrypted backup or snapshot to an encrypted DB instance.
So again, it's about not being able to change the encryption status of an existing database.
Now, how do we then change the encryption status of our database?
Well, key exam tip is you cannot do it for an existing instance. But what you can do is with your
RDS database that's unencrypted,
take a DB snapshot, which will also be unencrypted.
Copy that snapshot to an encrypted snapshot, and then you'll be able to create an RDS instance
with a new endpoint.
So the point is, it is a different database,
not the same database.
It's a copy of the same data, the same database tables, but it is a different database endpoint,
so you now need to update your application to point to the new encrypted database.
That's it for RDS security.
And in the next lesson, we're going to do a hands-on where you'll see how to encrypt a copy of our
snapshots and then create a database from it.