Hi, guys. In this lesson, we're going to create an encrypted copy of our RDS database.
Now, as you know, we can't change the status of our existing database in terms of encryption. But
we already have a snapshot which is unencrypted.
So, we're going to copy that snapshot,
enable encryption for the snapshot, and then from the encrypted snapshot we'll create a new database
instance that will have its own endpoint.
So let's go over to the console. Back RDS,
I'm going to go to snapshots and I have my unencrypted snapshot here.
I'm going to select the snapshot, go to actions and copy.
Now I'm going to keep it in the same region.
I'm going to give it a new identifier,
Digicloud encrypted.
We're going to leave the other defaults and just select encryption.
And for encryption we're going to use the standard default AWS RDS key.
So let's copy this snapshot.
So we can see at the top here that the snapshot copy is being created.
So, just give it a few minutes until it's created and then we're going to launch a database from it.
My snapshot has been created, so I'm going to select my encrypted snapshot, go to actions, and restore
snapshot.
We can now provide an instance identifier.
I'll call this one Digicloud encrypted.
I'm going to leave it in the same VPC. And in fact,
I don't need to change any other settings here except for the DB instance class.
So, I'm going to go back to burstable classes. And I can't find the t2.micro on this list but I'll
choose the t3.micro. So, it's up to you.
If you actually launch this instance, there's a possibility it could cost you a small amount of money.
But we won't have it running for very long.
Now, I'm going to leave the other defaults.
We don't need a multi-AZ standby.
Scroll down to the bottom.
And as you can see, it is an encrypted instance and I can't change that.
It's greyed out. And that's exactly what I'd expect because as you know, we can't create an unencrypted
database from an encrypted snapshot.
So, I'm going to click on restore DB instance.
And now I have a new DB Instance being created.
If I click on that instance, go to configuration,
we can of course see that this is an encrypted database. And it's going to essentially be a copy
of our original database.
Now it will eventually have its own endpoint and port.
So, if you leave this to complete, we're going to have a different endpoint here than our other database.
So, we have created a separate database here.
We can't ever change the encryption status of the initial database. And I keep mentioning this because
it comes up in pretty much every single exam.
So, I'm not actually going to wait.
I know what's going to happen there in terms of adding the DB endpoint.
So, what I'm going to do is just go through and delete all of my databases.
Now, you can deselect the option to create a final snapshot.
We don't want to retain automated backups, and we just select the acknowledge here. Type delete me
and delete. And I'll do that for each database.
So, all of my databases are now deleting.
Now, the other thing I want to do is go to snapshots. And under manual, I want to go to actions and
delete both of my snapshots.
If you do get an error like I did because the encrypted snapshot was being used to actually create a
database, just go back and wait for your databases to complete deleting and then delete your snapshot.