Amazon ElastiCache is an in-memory database and is often used for caching data that comes from other
databases, so we'll see how that works.
Now, let's get through a few facts first.
Amazon ElastiCache is a fully managed implementation of the popular Redis and Memcached database
engines.
ElastiCache is a key value store.
It's an in-memory database which offers really high performance and low latency. So, it's often used
in use cases where we're trying to improve the performance of an existing database like an RDS database
or where we just need that really low latency for storing data.
We can put it in front of databases like RDS and DynamoDB, and it's a very common use case. Now,
ElastiCache nodes run on Amazon EC2 instances. So, you do need to choose an instance type when
you launch your database cluster.
So let's have a quick look at a very simple diagram to show you how it works with RDS.
So let's say we have an Amazon ElastiCache node and we have an RDS database and an application instance.
The application will write data to the RDS database.
That data will then get loaded to the ElastiCache node, so it's consistent with the RDS database.
Now, that isn't always the way it works,
there's a couple of nuances to that, but this is one way it can work.
Then if a read for that specific data is issued, then we get a cache hits because it goes to the ElastiCache
node and it comes back at higher performance and lower latency.
Now, the differences between Redis and Memcached implementations is a key topic for the exam, so
you need to understand the differences here. Now in terms of database persistence,
the data is not persistent with Memcached, but it is with Redis.
Now, as you'll note, there's two columns here for Redis, cluster mode enabled and cluster mode disabled.
Memcached is often used with simple data types, whereas Redis is for more complex data types.
Partitioning a data does happen in Memcached. We'll
see this in more detail in the next lesson. Whereas with Redis, the data is not partitioned.
With encryption, you only have options for enabling encryption with Redis.
You don't get high availability replication with Memcached
but you do with Redis.
Now, what about multi-AZ?
Well, you do get that with both implementations. With Memcached,
you can place nodes in multiple availability zones, but there's no actual failover or replication. With
Redis for both implementations,
it does allow auto failover and you can have read replicas and they're on a per shard basis.
The scaling of the databases is a little bit more complex. And in the next lesson, you'll see diagrams
that make it a bit more clear.
But essentially, with Memcached, you can scale up in terms of changing the node type and you can scale
out by adding nodes.
But each of those nodes is a separate partition because remember, it supports partitioning. With Redis,
you scale up by the node type or you can add a replica if it's Redis cluster mode disabled or shards
if it's Redis cluster mode enabled.
Now, Memcached is multi-threaded, whereas Redis is not.
So try and remember that one that does come up as an exam question.
You don't get any backup with Memcached, whereas you do in terms of automated backups and manual snapshots
with Redis.
So what are some popular use cases for ElastiCache?
You want to use it with data that's relatively static and frequently accessed.
Applications need to be tolerant of stale data because sometimes you might not have the synchronization
of the data between the backend and the cache,
or at least that could be some latency there. You can use it for use cases where it's either slow or expensive
to get your data from your existing database compared to the cache.
So if the cache is faster or cheaper or maybe both, then that would be a good use case.
You get pushbutton scalability for the memory, for the writes, and for the reads.
So that is a useful feature of ElastiCache, and you will learn a bit more about that in the next lesson.
ElastiCache is very useful for storing session state data.
That's another common use case.
DynamoDB is another solution.
So if you see questions relating to storing session state data, then often ElastiCache or DynamoDB
will be good answers.
So with that in mind, there's a few examples here like a web session store, database caching, leaderboards,
and streaming data dashboards.
And that's it for the core theory.
And in the next lesson, we'll look at how we can scale ElastiCache.