Hi, guys. Welcome to this hands-on lesson.
What we're going to do is launch an Amazon ElastiCache Redis cluster.
So let's head over to the console. In the AWS management console,
I'm on the ElastiCache dashboard and I'm going to choose the get started button.
I can now choose my cluster engine.
Let's have a look first at the different options available for Memcached.
We can deploy in the Amazon cloud or on premises if you have AWS Outposts.
You can then choose a name.
You can specify which version compatibility you want, port numbers and so on.
Now, for node type, we might want to change to t2.micro here. So that's an important point to remember
about ElastiCache.
It is based EC2 instances you're paying for these nodes when they're provisioned.
We can now choose the number of nodes we want. With Memcached,
each node is a separate partition of data.
So maybe I want three nodes.
I can now choose my VPC.
I'm going to use the default VPC and then I can create a subnet group. So, I've given it a name and a description.
Now, I can select the subnets I want to use. So maybe I want to use A, B, and C.
I can then select the zones.
So now, I can select which zones I want each of my nodes to be in.
So maybe I'll choose 1A, 1B, and 1C.
So now, I'm using three different availability zones, so each partition of data will be in a separate
AZ.
You can then choose your security group and your maintenance window.
So, we're just going to cancel out of here so we don't have anything saved in the console.
Go back to create and choose Redis.
Now, of course, with Redis, we have two options, either just Redis on its own with the cluster
mode disabled or cluster mode enabled.
Now, I'm just going to scroll up and try to get all this on the screen.
What I want to show you is what changes down here in the bottom part of the screen when I enable cluster
mode enabled.
So, keep an eye on the bottom of the screen, let's select the cluster mode enabled.
And as you can see, now, we can specify the number of shots and the replicas per shard. If I turn it
off,
we just get the number of replicas and we have an option for multi-AZ.
Now we're going to leave it off. Let's scroll down.
Let's give this a name and a description.
I'm going to leave the defaults for the version compatibility and the port and the parameter group for
node type I will change to t2.micro. Click on save. Under subnet group,
I'm first going to change my VPC. Then I'll specify the name of a subnet group and provide a description.
And now we can select the subnet.
So maybe again, I want to choose A, B, and C.
Let's choose our zones and we've got our primary now and two replicas. So we can have those across different
availability zones.
Now, if I went back up to change the number of replicas here and come back down again,
so now I have a third replica and I could put that in a different AZ.
I'm just going to stick to two replicas. Let's come back down the page again.
Security groups, I'm going to leave as they are.
We could select encryption at rest here and choose a default key or a customer managed customer master
key.
I'm going to leave that off.
You can enable encryption in transit and choose from these different access control options.
So you've got user group Access Control Lists or Redis Auth.
If you use Redis Auth, you have to specify the name of a token.
We're going to leave it off.
You can enable slow logs for slow running queries, and you can seed the data from an S3 location.
Now we're going to leave the remaining defaults, including the backup as enable automatic backups
with a retention period of one day. For maintenance window,
we'll leave that as the default and just select create.
The database is now in the creating state and we'll just need to wait a few minutes for that to complete.
My database is now ready and we can see the cluster is in the available state and it's all up to date.
If I just expand the menu here, we can see quite a bit of information, including the ARN.
We can see the primary endpoints, the engine, availability zones in use and much more.
Now, if you want information about the nodes, click on the cluster name and you can see the nodes
here.
Now, I just want to show you a couple of things back up the cluster level first.
If we select the cluster in the action’s menu, we can modify our cluster if we want.
Now, this is where we would go if we wanted to change the node type.
So, if we wanted to scale up, we could come in here and change to a different node type.
I'm going to cancel out of there and then go back in to the nodes. Now, for the nodes
we've got the primary and two different replicas.
If I choose the primary, actions, I can failover the
primary. If I choose a replica and go to actions, I can promote the replica. And then also we can scale
horizontally by adding a read replica to the cluster. We just give it a name and then choose the
AZ that we want the replica to be in.
Now, with a node selected, if we drag up this menu at the bottom here, you can see that we have some
node specific CloudWatch metrics.
And if we select a different node, we can see some different metrics here. So, you can view that information
over in CloudWatch, or you can see it here on a per node basis. Coming back up to the cluster level,
if I select the cluster and go to actions, you can also create a backup here as well.
So, with my cluster selected, I can give it a name and choose whoever I want to encrypt the backup and create
the backup, and that will then be viewable on the left-hand side under backups. Under events on the left
hand-side
here we can also see some information about recent events for the cluster.
We can see the cluster being created and we can see the different cache nodes being added as well.
So let's head back up to Redis, and I have finished with this cluster for now.
So, what I'm going to do is select the cluster, go to actions, and delete.
I don't want to create a final backup, so I just choose no and then delete.
And that would take a few minutes now to delete your cluster.