Kinesis always pops up in exam questions.
I haven't found recently that there's too much in terms of depth of Kinesis knowledge required.
Again, with the Solutions Architect pro, it's often about really understanding when you should use
these tools in more complex scenarios than you would get in the other exams, like the associate level.
So often, Kinesis will be used in a overall solutions architecture with several other services.
And you need to work out based on your understanding of the products, which one is best for a specific
customer requirement.
Now there's three core products that do come up in the exam, and that's Kinesis Data Streams,
Firehose, and Data Analytics.
Video streams doesn't really come up.
With Kinesis, you have your data sources, and in this case we're talking about streaming data.
You can then load that data into Kinesis Data Streams.
Data stream is often the front end.
This is where you're ingesting your data from your devices.
Maybe you're using IoT devices or something like that where you're streaming data into Kinesis.
So the data gets ingested into Data Streams.
We can then process it with Kinesis Data Analytics.
Data Analytics uses Apache Flink for processing Data Streams.
Now, with Kinesis Data Analytics, it's all about running SQL.
But you then might want to process your data with Lambda to perform some other kind of function
and maybe load it into a DynamoDB table, for example.
We've then got Kinesis Firehose.
Kinesis Firehose will load data straight to destination's and data streams can be a source for firehose.
So let's say in this example we're loading the data into Amazon S3.
We could then query that data with Amazon Athena, for example.
So this would be a good way to take our streaming data, load it into S3 and potentially do some
kind of analytics on it and processing of that data on the way there.
So we might have Kinesis Data Analytics before we go to Firehose or we might have AWS Lambda in there
performing some kind of processing of the data as well.
So there's lots of different ways you can use Kinesis.
But the key is to remember streaming data use cases.
That's when you're going to see Kinesis as being a good fit.
Now, you might also load your data into RedShift and query it with business intelligence tools
like QuickSight.
So we'll look at it in a bit more detail about the various destinations that are supported shortly.
So let's go into more detail on Kinesis Data Streams first.
With Data Streams, you have producers.
They send data to Kinesis and the data gets stored in a Shard for 24 hours.
And that's the default.
You can keep it there for up to seven days as well.
Consumers will then take the data from the Shard and process it.
The data can then be saved to another service.
So you can then save it out to S3 or RedShift or wherever you want to put it.
Kinesis Data Streams is real time, so somewhere around 200 milliseconds.
Something that definitely comes up in exam questions is the difference between Data Streams and firehose
Data Streams is real-time Firehose is near real time.
So watch out for the wording in question.
So here we have our streaming data coming from whatever source.
The producers are capturing and then sending that data to a stream.
And the stream has shards.
The data gets captured and stored for processing within the shards.
Then we have our consumers and our consumers in this case are EC2 instances.
They're going to process the data and then they're going to load it to a destination.
And you can see a few of the supported destinations here.
And then you can run your analytics against that data if that's what you need to do.
So the Kinesis Client Library is part of the software architecture on the EC2 instances that you
need to run in order to process data from the streams.
So KCL helps you consume and process data from a Kinesis Data Stream.
The KCL will enumerate the Shards and instantiate what's called a record processor for each Shard
that it manages.
KCL workers, which are instances in this case of EC2 running the agent can also have
multiple record processors.
So each of those is actually getting mapped to a shard.
Each shard gets processed by exactly one KCL worker and has exactly one corresponding record processor.
One worker can also process any number of shards.
So the number of shards can be greater than the number of instances you have to process them.
So each shard is processed by exactly one KCL worker and a record processor maps to exactly one shard.
Another thing about Kinesis Data Streams is ordering, and this definitely comes up in exam questions.
So on the left there, we have some producers and in this case, EC2, and they're just numbered
and color coded in this example.
On the right, we have our KCL workers with the record processors running.
A partition key can be specified with the record API action.
And that means that the data can be grouped by Shard.
So the data comes across from the producers.
And what's happening is the order is actually maintained for the records within a shard.
So as the records are added, they will be then processed in the order they went in.
They don't just get sort of thrown into some kind of bucket and processed in a random order.
So it's key to remember for the exam that you can have your records processed in order with Kinesis,
but you have to actually order them by shards.
So the ordering is only maintained within a shard, not across shards.
So next we have Data Firehose.
Again, we have producers sending data to Firehose.
There are no shards.
And one of the advantages of that is that it's completely automated in terms of scalability, very elastic.
With Data Streams, you have to add shards when you need to scale.
So that's something that you have to watch out for.
You've got to constantly monitor and you pay for the shards.
So it's important to get the number of shards correct.
Wth Firehose, the data is always loaded directly to the destination.
It's not stored within Firehose itself.
And optionally you can transform it or process it with AWS Lambda before it's actually stored
in the destination.
Now, as I mentioned before, you get near real time delivery, so somewhere around 60 seconds latency
with Kinesis Data Firehose.
So let's look visually.
Again, We have some kind of producer and the data is hitting Firehose.
It will capture it, potentially transform it, and then load that streaming data into a destination.
And here's just a few of the destinations.
We'll see some more shortly.
So the data gets loaded continuously to the destinations and optionally transformed before it's loaded
to the destination.
And then again, you can run your analytics tools against that data.
So let's have a look at the supported destinations.
Firstly, we've got Redshift, we've got ElasticSearch, Amazon S3, Splunk, Datadog, MongoDB,
New Relic, and also an HTTP Endpoint as well.
The last service we need to cover is Data Analytics.
This one doesn't come up in too many exam questions.
You've got to remember that data analytics is used when you want to perform real-time SQL processing
for the streaming data.
It provides analytics for data coming from Data Streams or from Kinesis Data Firehose.
The destinations can be Data Streams, Data Firehose or AWS Lambda.
So again, we have our data source streaming data.
The streaming data hits Kinesis Data Streams and then we can have data analytics running SQL queries
on the real-time streaming data.
You can then load it to AWS Lambda or you could load it to Kinesis Data Firehose.
So that's it for Kinesis.
I hope that is useful.
I will see you in the next lesson.