Hi, guys. In this lesson, we're going to cover off two analytic services.
One is Amazon Athena and the other is AWS Glue.
So Amazon Athena is a serverless service that we can use to run SQL queries against data.
Now principally, that data is on Amazon S3.
So you point Athena at your data source in S3 and then run SQL queries against it.
Now, the Athena can actually query data in a few different formats.
You've got CSV, TSV, JSON, and Apache Parquet and ORC formats.
Now you can also use AWS Glue as a data catalog, so it actually stores the metadata.
And that helps you build your tables in Amazon Athena.
We'll see this in the hands-on shortly.
You can also point Athena at some other data sources.
So you see this is straight from the console and we have several different data sources here.
Some of them are AWS and some are third party.
So we might want to run SQL queries against data in new sources.
So, for example, you might want to be able to run SQL queries against information in CloudWatch logs.
Well, you can do that with Athena, but you need a Lambda function as well.
So the Lambda function connects Athena to the data source and then you can map the data
into tables in Athena and query that data.
So a few core facts about Athena.
It's used for querying data in S3 using SQL and you can also connect some other data sources with Lambda.
The data should be in CSV, TSV, Parquet, and ORC.
You can use AWS Glue as a managed data catalog to store information and schemas about the databases
and tables that you're going to query.
Now, something that comes up in the exam in a couple of questions is how to optimize
Athena for performance.
Now, there's quite a bit here and to be honest, you don't need to know all of it in detail.
But just take note of the facts here.
And there's also a link attached to this lesson with a bit more information.
Partition your data, bucket your data within a single partition.
Use compression.
So AWS recommend using Apache Parquet or ORC.
Optimize you file sizes, optimize columnar data store generation.
Optimize ORDER BY and GROUP BY.
Use approximate functions and only include the columns that you need.
So a few key tips there.
Again, read the article that's linked to this lesson and that will give you a bit more of a background
on these or what exactly the recommendations are.
And that can come up in the odd exam question.
So next up, we've got AWS Glue.
This is a fully managed ETL service, extract, transform, and load.
You can use it for preparing data for analytics and it runs the ETL jobs on a fully managed scale-out
Apache Spark environment.
Glue can discover the data and then store the metadata in the Glue Data catalog.
And that's what we're going to use with Athena as well.
It works with data lakes such as data on S3, data warehouses like RedShift and data stores like RDS
or EC2.
You can use something called a crawler to populate the Glue Data Catalog with tables.
A crawler can crawl multiple data stores in a single run and on completion it creates or updates the
tables in your data catalog.
Then when you create ETL jobs in AWS Glue, it will use the data catalog tables as sources and targets.
So those are the key facts.
And we will go into our hands-on where you're going to see Athena and AWS Glue working together.