Hi guys. In this lesson, you're going to learn about the Amazon Simple Queue Service
SQS.
Now to help you understand what an SQS queue is and what benefits it brings,
let's have a look at a diagram.
So I want to give you an example of where you're not using an SQS queue.
So I would call this a direct integration
between different components of an application.
So for example, here we have a web tier on the frontend.
So the web tier is perhaps internet-facing.
And this is where things like orders might be coming in from customers.
You've then got an app tier.
An app tier might process some of the orders or whatever other information
is being received by the web tier.
So the web tier is connected directly to the app tier.
Now one of the downsides of this is the app tier
must keep up with the workload or a failure will occur.
So if the web tier suddenly gets a huge amount of demand, lots of orders are coming in
the app tier must also be able to scale enough to handle those orders.
Now, auto scaling is great.
That will help because it will automatically launch instances.
But those instances can take time to come up and be ready.
So there is a chance that you will lose
information and a customer order could be lost.
So what we could do instead is use a decoupled integration.
Now we have the web tier and the app tier and in the middle we have an SQS queue.
So what happens is the web tier is now integrated to the queue.
It's going to place the orders as messages in the SQS queue.
The app tier is then connecting to the queue, it's polling the queue
and checking, are there any messages I need to process?
Now, if there is a sudden huge amount of information coming in,
lots of orders being placed, then the queue can scale very easily.
So you'll just end up with a lot more orders in the queue awaiting processing.
The app tier may need to scale but it doesn't have the
issue of the direct integration where the orders might be lost because
they can sit in the queue for quite a bit of time
and the app tier can process them as soon as it's ready.
Now, SQS is pull-based not push-based.
A push-based service would be something like SNS, where you're sending
information as a notification. We'll look at that service in this section.
But SQS is pull-based.
And that means as with the previous example on the on the slide I just showed
the instances are polling the queue, they're checking the queue.
The queue is not sending the messages to the EC2,
the instances must connect to the queue and find those messages there.
Now it is possible to trigger some events and we'll look at that
later on in the section.
Messages are up to 256 KB in size.
Larger messages,
So messages above that limitation can be sent using the SQS extended client
library for Java. We'll also look at how that works as well in this section.
Messages can be kept in the queue from one minute up to 14 days.
And the default retention period is four days.
The SQS guarantees that your messages will be processed at least once.
Now there are different queue types to choose from.
We've got a standard queue.
And this has what's called best effort ordering.
Now, best effort ordering doesn't guarantee the ordering
of course, it's best effort.
So though the order, the messages are put on the queue,
maybe the order that they're processed when they're taken from the queue
that's not guaranteed.
So if ordering is very important, then a standard queue is not for you.
Instead, you would use a FIFO queue.
Here we have what's called first in first out delivery.
So the first message, number one here is going to be the first one
to be processed and then number two, three, four, five, six, and so on.
So here's some more differences between a standard queue and a FIFO queue.
With a standard queue, you get unlimited free put and nearly unlimited
transactions per second per API action.
You get best effort ordering
and occasionally messages might be delivered in an order that's different
into which they were put onto the queue.
At least once delivery means the message is delivered at least once,
but occasionally more than one copy of a message could be delivered.
We then have a FIFO queue.
This also supports high throughput.
FIFO queue support up to 300 messages a second.
That's 300 send, receive, or delete operations a second.
You can batch 10 messages per operation.
And that could lead to greater efficiency.
And when you use batching, the FIFO queue can support up to 3000 messages a second.
As I showed on the previous slide, FIFO queues support first in first out delivery.
They also have what's called exactly-once processing.
A message is delivered once and remains available
until the consumer process it and deletes it.
Duplicates are not introduced to the queue.
So it's important to understand what you need for your application.
Does your application logic ensure that the
messages are processed in the correct order
and that there are only processed once?
Or do you require that to be in the queue level
so you don't have to do it in your application?
FIFO queues require the message group ID and message deduplication ID
parameters to be added to messages.
So what are these? Well, let's look at the message group ID first.
This is a tag that specifies that a message belongs to a specific group of messages.
Messages that belong to the same message group are guaranteed to be processed in a
FIFO manner.
If they're not in the same message group, then that is not guaranteed.
Messages with a different group ID could be received out of order.
We then got the deduplication ID.
This is a token used for deduplication of messages within a specified
deduplication interval.
The interval is five minutes.
It's generated as the SHA-256 within the message body.
Now there's another configuration for a queue called a dead letter queue.
It's not exactly a type of queue. It's more of a use case and a configuration.
So what is this?
Well, let's say we got our web tier and application tier again
and we've got an SQS queue.
We then have a separate queue that's configured as a dead letter queue.
Now, what happens is a message is not processed successfully.
In this case the received count metric has exceeded the max received count
for the queue.
What this means is the message has been received
multiple times but it's never been successfully processed.
So there's a max receive count which has been exceeded.
So what happens now is the message could be lost.
But in this case with a dead letter queue,
what happens is that message is now moved over to the dead letter queue.
And that gives us a chance to analyze our failures.
A dead letter queue is actually a standard or FIFO queue
that's been specified as a dead letter queue.
So it's a configuration rather than a different type of queue.
The main task of a dead letter queue is handling message failure.
It lets you set aside and isolate messages that can't be processed correctly
so that you can then analyze why that happened.
It's not a queue type as I mentioned,
it's a standard or FIFO queue that you've configured
as a dead letter queue.
And this is where you do it.
You enable something called a redrive policy.
You specify the queue to use as the dead letter queue.
So that's the name of my dead letter queue, My DL queue.
And you specify the maximum receives before a message is sent
to the dead letter queue.
So that's that max receive count that we saw on the previous slide.
Messages are moved to the dead letter queue
when the receive count for a message exceeds the max receive count for the queue.
Dead letter queues should not be used with
standard queues when your application will keep retrying transmission.
And that's because you don't want that message to now be moved into
a dead letter queue because your application is going to
keep on attempting to process that message.
Dead letter queues will break the order of messages in FIFO queues.
There's another queue configuration that we call a delay queue. So what is this?
So again, we have our SQS queue.
We have a producer that's the instance that's
going to be placing messages onto our queue.
And it places a message.
Now I'm indicating the timeline here of the message as it's in the queue.
So over time, what is going to happen to that message in the queue.
So what we do with a delay queue is we've configured something
called a delay seconds.
Now let's say we have a Lambda function.
This is the processing component.
It's going to try and find the messages in the queue and process them.
So the function is polling the queue.
But at this point in the timeline, the message is still within the delay seconds.
That means that Lambda cannot find that message in the queue. It's not even visible.
Now as time goes on, the delay seconds is past now the message becomes visible again
and the lambda function can process that message.
Now, we can configure this through the delivery delay.
So you can see that just down here.
The default is zero seconds. So that means it's not enabled,
And the max is 15 minutes.
So when would you use a delay queue?
Well, maybe with large distributed applications that need
to introduce a delay in processing,
you need to apply a delay to an entire queue of messages for some reason.
And one example might be you're adding a delay of a few seconds to allow
updates to sales or stock control databases
before sending a notification to a customer confirming an online transaction.
You also need to understand what the visibility timeouts is.
So we've got a similar configuration here to the previous diagram.
We've got a producer and a consumer, both EC2 instances in this case.
So a message gets placed on the queue,
there's the delay seconds and the message cannot be returned
because it's not visible.
Then of course the message does become visible
and the instance is able to process that message.
Now, we could then have something called a visibility timeout.
Now, what this means is the message is invisible for a period of time.
Now, you might say, well hang on,
it's just been processed but well, it might not processed successfully.
So the message is not deleted from the queue
when an instance actually starts processing that message.
So the visibility timeout gives you a
period of time in which the message is invisible
and therefore can't be processed by any other EC2 instances.
Now let's say the message fails to process for some reason.
Now, after a period of time, after the visibility timeout expires,
the message becomes visible again.
And that means another instance or the same instance
can try and process that message again.
So the visibility timeout is the amount of time a message
is invisible in the queue after a reader picks it up.
Provided the job is process before the visibility timeout expires,
the message will then be deleted from the queue.
If the job's not processed within the visibility timeout,
the message will become visible again and then it's available for another processor,
another consumer to actually pick that message up and process it.
This could result in the same message being delivered twice.
So again, sometimes you need to think about where is going to be the logic to ensure
that this doesn't happen if it's going to be an issue with your application.
The default visibility timeout is 30 seconds, the maximum is 12 hours.
And here's a view into the configuration in the console where in
this case we have the default timeout of 30 seconds.
Moving on, we have something called long polling and short polling.
And it's really important in the exam to understand the differences
and the benefits and drawbacks of using either of these methods.
Of course, polling is where we're looking at the
queue and checking if messages are available to be processed.
With short polling, the instance will check a subset of servers
and may not return all messages.
So perhaps it doesn't find the message.
Upon a retry, maybe it does.
On the other hand, with long polling
we're more likely to receive the message because long polling waits
for the wait time seconds, which is a configurable value
and eliminates empty responses.
So as long as the wait time seconds is configured long enough,
then it means that it's going to find messages as they appear in the queue.
So essentially you're creating an API action, you're executing an API action,
and you're waiting to make sure that it results in actually picking up a message
and processing it.
With short polling. That's not happening.
You're checking, you missed the messages.
Either they're not there or you don't find them on the right servers
and then you have to issue another API action to repeat the process.
Now that can result in higher costs because
you are charged for executing those API actions.
So long polling is a way to retrieve messages from queues
and it waits for the messages to arrive.
Short polling returns immediately even if the message queue is empty.
Long polling can lower costs.
Long polling is enabled at queue level or you can
do it at the API level using the wait time seconds parameter.
Long polling is in effect when the received message wait time
is a value greater than zero seconds and up to 20 seconds.
And here you can see where you configure this in the console.
We've got the receive message wait time
and that's configured in this case to the maximum of 20 seconds