In this lesson, I'm going to cover some useful API actions with
SQS and also the extended client library for Java.
So let's look at some useful API actions.
These are ones that are very good to know for the exam.
Firstly, we've got change message visibility.
That changes the visibility timeout of a specified message in a queue to a new value.
The default is 30 seconds, minimum is zero, and the maximum is 12 hours
And we learned about the visibility timeout in a previous lesson.
We've then got Get Queue Attributes and Set Queue Attributes.
These get or set the attributes for the specified queue.
And there are lots of possible values and it's
recommended that you view them in the API reference.
I've provided a link at the end of this lesson and it's attached to the lesson as well.
Key attributes to know for the exam are, the delay seconds.
That configures a delay queue.
Zero seconds to 900 seconds with a default of zero seconds.
We've then got the receive message wait time seconds.
That sets the short or long polling configuration.
Again at zero seconds as a minimum and this one's up to 20 seconds.
The default is also zero.
We've then got the visibility timeout.
This is the visibility timeout for a queue from 0-43,200 seconds or 12 hours
with the default being 30 seconds.
Next we have the receive message.
This retrieves one or more messages up to 10 from the specified queue.
Using the wait time seconds parameter will enable long polling support
when you want to receive a message.
We then have send message.
With send message, you can specify the delay seconds parameter to delay the message.
The message deduplication ID parameter adds the deduplication ID for FIFO queues.
And the group ID parameter adds the group message ID
and that's also applicable to FIFO queues.
Now, those are just a few examples.
As I mentioned, attached to this lesson is a link.
I recommend you just have a basic understanding
of the API actions that are available.
Now let's look at the extended client library for Java.
So what is this? Well, let's have a look at a diagram.
We've got a producer, a queue, and a consumer.
We've also got an S3 bucket.
Now, the producer wants to put a message on to the queue.
And it does so.
But the producer is also using the SQs extended client library for
Java to send a message with a reference to an S3 object.
Now why does it do that?
Well, because the object is too big to be included in the message in the queue.
Remember the limit is 256 kilobytes per message.
So the message is actually referencing the large object in S3.
The consumer now receives the message
and it can then find the reference to the S3 object
and then process the objects as well.
So remember maximum message size is 256 kilobytes in SQS.
You would then use the SQS extended client library for Java to manage
Amazon SQS messages to reference them in the message you put in the queue.
It's useful for storing and consuming messages up to two gigabytes in size.
With the client library for Java,
you can specify whether messages are always stored in S3 or only
when the message size exceeds the limitation of 256 kilobytes.
You can send a message that references a single message object stored
in an Amazon S3 bucket.
And your processes can then get the corresponding message object from
the amazon S3 bucket.
They might then want to delete the corresponding message object from the S3 bucket
after they've successfully processed it.