AWS Step Functions is a service that coordinates the components of an application.
So let's have a look visually at what that means.
So let's say we have an application with some logic.
In the beginning, it needs to do something, process some code. Maybe a Lambda function is used for
that portion of the application.
Then we've got some branch and logics, some code within Step Functions that checks for a certain event.
You can also have wait conditions.
In this case, it's checking something related to the execution results of the previous Lambda function.
If that's a yes, maybe it sends a notification.
If there's a no, maybe it creates something.
And that can also be a Lambda function.
So, you can have many different Lambda functions and then you have your execution logic within Step Functions.
The notification might then get processed by a Lambda function as well.
We might then have a wait condition while processing takes place, and then eventually the Step Function
completes and we might have a result that also needs to be checked by another Lambda function.
So, we have this visualization here, and you actually see this in the console within Step Functions.
So Step Functions is used to build distributed applications as a series of steps in a visual workflow.
So, the workflow we saw in the previous slide, that's what you can see in Step Functions.
And it really helps you to understand the logic that you're building out.
You can quickly build and run what's called a state machine. And the state machine executes the steps
of your application.
So, what we do is we create the steps of our workflows using something called the JSON-based Amazon States
language.
We can then start executions and within the console you can actually see the real time status of each
step within the visual workflow.
Step Functions operates and scales the underlying compute layer, so it can scale seamlessly and work
very reliably.
Now, the best way to understand Step Functions is to see it in action.
So, in the next lesson, we're going to build out a couple of state machines.