In this hands-on lesson, we're going to create a couple of state machines in Step Functions.
Now, I'm on the main page for AWS Step Functions. And I'm going to click on get started. And this will
actually start a Hello World workflow.
So, a very simple application.
Now, the logic for this application is written in code within this definition within the state machine
itself.
And on the right-hand side we can see a visual representation of the code on the left-hand side.
And as you can see, this particular state machine has a start, then a pass,
then it goes through this Hello World example.
And on the right-hand side, if it doesn't see the information it wants, it's going to say no and just
end.
If it finds the information it's looking for, then the answer is yes.
It's going to wait for three seconds and then it's going to say Hello World,
and that will be the result.
So, let's click on next.
I'm going to leave
all the defaults here. It's going to create its own execution role.
We're going to have logging off and just create the state machine.
Now, once it's being created, we then get the start execution.
In this case, we can see the input and the input here has is hello world example
true? And the true will be the yes result.
So, then it's going to process and it's going to produce a hello world message after waiting for a
delay period.
If we change that to false, then it wouldn't work.
So, let's leave it as it is and click on start execution. And you can see that it's happening in real
time.
So, we're waiting now for the three seconds before it actually completes this particular state machine.
So now, the state machine is complete. And you can see the event history information, quite detailed information
down at the bottom here.
Back up at the top, we can see the execution input and then we can see the execution output.
So that's a simple example.
Now, what we're going to do now is see how we can use a Lambda function with a state machine.
Now, this file is in your course
download in the code directory
Step Functions you'll find this marked down file Step Functions with Lambda.
So, the first thing we need to do is go over to AWS Lambda and we're going to create a function.
So, I'm going to copy the name of the function,
and in Lambda, I'm going to create function, provide the name.
We're going to use Node.js 12.
We're going to allow the creation of a new role for basic Lambda permissions
and we're going to create that function.
Now, while that's happening, let's get the code.
So, the code we're going to deploy is going to be this code right here. Within the function, under the
code section,
let's delete the existing code,
paste this new code in and click on deploy.
Now, I need my function ARN, so let's copy that to our clipboards.
Come back.
I'm going to pass that in right here. To see it working,
let's configure a test event with the following data.
We're going to copy this to our clipboards.
Come back, go to test, new test event.
Let's call it
Hello Function. Paste in this information and then test.
And so the result we get is Hello
AWS Step Functions. So that's working correctly. Now, we need to create our state machine.
So, we're going to go and create a state machine. And we're going to use this code here.
So, back in Step Functions under state machines, I'm going to create a state machine.
I'm going to choose the option to write your workflow in code.
It's going to be a standard type.
I'm going to delete all the code from here and paste my code in.
Now we need the ARN for our Lambda function.
So back in my file, I copy the Lambda function ARN. And let's paste that over the top here.
So, we remove this ARN, paste the new ARN in,
scroll down to the bottom,
choose next.
You can rename this if you like.
I'm going to leave it as my state machine.
It's going to create its own execution role.
Scroll down and create state machine.
That's the state machine created.
Now, let's start an execution.
And we're going to put in some JSON code here.
The JSON code is this code here.
Now, what you want to do is just change this to your name. So, I'm going to change it to Neal.
Copy the code.
Delete the input here.
Put our new code in and start the execution.
And so that should run the Lambda function, which it has.
And we have a successful result.
We can see the input that we placed and then the output should be
Hello, Neal.
So, another very simple example just to show you how you can use a state machine with AWS Lambda.