In this hands-on lesson, we're going to create an event bus and rule that triggers based on state
changes in EC2.
So, we saw this example in the previous lesson.
It's simply going to be a state change in EC2 where we terminate an event.
And that should trigger an email via an SNS topic.
Now, in EC2, I've already launched an instance. So, you'll want to go ahead and just launch an instance
and then copy the instance ID to your clipboard. In EventBridge,
we're going to create a rule.
I'll give it a name, EC2 State Change. And then I'm going to choose event pattern, predefined pattern
by AWS service.
The service provider is going to be AWS, then EC2. For event type,
you want to choose EC2 instance state change notification. And then we're going to change to specific
states and I'm going to choose terminated.
For instance, I can actually add my specific instance ID. So, we can now see the event pattern has
been recorded here.
We're looking at the source aws.ec2.
We're looking for an instance state change notification, and specifically, we're looking for terminated
events related to this specific instance.
Next, we need to specify a target.
So, I'm going to choose SNS and then for topic, we already have a topic here from earlier in the course.
So, I'm going to choose my email notification and then simply create this rule.
So that rule is enabled.
Let's go and terminate our EC2 instance and see what happens.
So, back in EC2, I'm simply going to terminate my EC2 instance. And then, I need to go and check my email
and see if I've received a notification.
So, here is the notification message that I received about 30 seconds later.
We can say it's an instance state change notification from EC2. We've got some information about the account,
the time it occurred, the region, and the resource specific information as well.
So that's a simple example of using an EventBridge rule to trigger an action based on a state change
in EC2.