Amazon API Gateway is a service we can use to create and publish REST APIs
HTTP APIs, and Websocket APIs.
Now, there's lots to learn for this exam. So let's get on with it.
So let's get started with a quick overview of what API Gateway is
and how it works with various services.
So I'm going to do so through a diagram.
So we have our region here and our API gateway is deployed within a region.
We've then got some clients on the internet.
Now they might be things like mobile clients.
They could be a service,
they could be another web service or something running on the internet
that needs to connect to the API to process some information.
It could be another website that uses the API.
So they connect to the API.
Now, maybe in this case it's a REST API over HTTPS.
Could also be an HTTP API or a Websocket.
The API can be integrated with various backend services.
So for example, it could be a Lambda function
in the public address space, so with a public endpoint.
Or it could be Lambda in a VPC.
So a Lambda function that's been attached to a VPC.
Or it could be an EC2 instance or an instance behind a load balancer.
In either case maybe they're running an HTTP or HTTPS endpoint.
It can also be various other AWS services and also public endpoints as well.
You can also import swagger or OpenAPI 3.0 definitions in YAML or JSON.
Now, what are the API types?
Well, we've got REST APIs. These support OIDC and OAuth 2 authorization
and come with built-in support for CORS and automatic deployments.
And of course, CORS is cross origin resource sharing.
We've then got HTTP APIs.
These are designed for low latency cost-effective integrations with AWS services
such as Lambda and HTTP endpoints.
Then we have Websocket APIs.
These are deployed as a stateful frontend for an
AWS service like Lambda or DynamoDB or for an HTTP endpoint.
Rest APIs and HTTP APIs support authorizers for AWS Lambda,
IAM and Amazon Cognito.
And Websocket APIs support IAM authorization and Lambda authorizers.
So let's look at the deployment types for a
REST API. We've got a couple of options here.
The first one is what we call an edge-optimized endpoint.
Now, this actually uses the Amazon CloudFront network.
The key benefit is that you get reduced latency
for requests that are coming from around the world because it's leveraging
those points of presence that CloudFront has all over the world.
Next we have a regional endpoint.
This is optimized for when your services are all within a region
that are connecting to your API endpoint.
The key benefits would be reduced latency for
requests that originate in the same AWS region.
You can also configure your own content delivery
network and protect with the AWS Web application firewall.
And then lastly we have a private endpoint.
This is for services that are connecting in the same VPC as the actual endpoint.
So we can have a private endpoint for our API gateway that's connected to our VPC
and the service that's connecting to the API endpoint is also within that VPC.
This gives you the benefit of securely exposing your REST APIs
only to other services within your VPC
or that are connecting via a Direct Connect connection.
Let's look at a bit more detail about edge-optimized APIs.
These are best for geographically distributed clients.
API requests are routed to the nearest CloudFront point of presence.
And this is the default endpoint type for API Gateway REST APIs.
Edge-optimized APIs capitalize the names of HTTP headers.
Regional APIs are intended for clients in the same region.
This reduces connection overhead for connections from within that region.
Any custom domain name that you use
is specific to the region where the API is actually deployed.
And if you deploy a regional API in multiple regions,
it can have the same custom domain name in all of those regions.
Private REST APIs can only be accessed from within a VPC
using an interface VPC endpoint.
So that's how you're connecting to API Gateway
because API Gateway itself is a public endpoint.
But you have a private interface VPC endpoint
to connect securely from within your VPC.
Now you can also be connecting across VPCs when you're using a private REST API.
So let's say you have your API Gateway service deployed in the VPC on the right
and then you've got your customer's VPC on the left
and they have instances that need to connect to the REST API.
So what happens is an Elastic Network Interface is deployed
in a private subnet of the customer VPC
and using that they're then able to connect API Gateway
and whatever the targets are the integrations for that API Gateway.
Finally, in this lesson, I'm going to cover some key features for API Gateway.
So API Gateway supports RESTful APIs and Websocket APIs.
With RESTful APIs, you've got the choice of either HTTP APIs or REST APIs.
It also supports private integrations with Elastic Load Balancer and AWS CloudMap.
With metering, you can define plans that meter and restrict
third party developer access to the APIs.
With security,
there are various methods to control authorization and access control within
API Gateway. And we'll see more about that in this section.
For resiliency, you can manage traffic with throttling so that
the backend operations can withstand traffic spikes.
Another thing that we'll look at in this section.
The operations monitoring,
it provides a metric dashboard to monitor calls to your services.
And you get lifecycle management.
You can have multiple API versions and stages for each version simultaneously so that
your applications can continue to call any previous versions
after you've published newer versions.
In terms of authorization, there's support for signature version four for REST APIs
and Websocket APIs, we have IAM access policies,
and authorization with bearer tokens like Java Web Tokens
and security assertion and markup language SAML.
And that's when using Lambda functions.
And that's it for this lesson. I will see you in the next one.