In this lesson, you'll learn about API Gateway stages and deployments.
So deployments are a snapshot of the APIs, resources, and methods.
Deployments must be created and associated with a stage for anyone to access the API.
And a stage is a logical reference to a lifecycle state
of your REST or Websocket API.
For example, it might be a dev, prod, beta, V2 stage etc.
API stages are identified by API ID and the stage name.
Stage variables are like environment variables for API Gateway.
And they can be used in Lambda function ARNs,
HTTP endpoints, and parameter mapping templates.
So let's have a look visually to understand what I'm talking about here.
So we've got an API called My API.
It has some methods and resources.
We then create a stage from that API. And this is called our development stage.
And it has a specific endpoint URL.
For this particular stage we can then set up some settings
like the caching and the throttling settings and so on.
Then we might create a production stage.
This will have also its own individual unique URL for accessing this endpoint.
And it will also have its own settings
for things like caching and throttling and various other settings.
So as an example here we might want to turn off the cache on the
development stage to save cost but turn it on for production to increase performance.
So what are the use cases for stage variables?
Well you can configure HTTP endpoints
your stages talk to such as dev, test, prod and so on.
You can pass configuration parameters to AWS Lambda through mapping templates.
And stage variables are passed to the context object in AWS Lambda.
They're also used with Lambda aliases.
You can create a stage variable to indicate the
corresponding Lambda alias you want to connect to.
Now I mentioned earlier that you can import swagger and OpenAPI 3 definitions
written in YAML or JSON's API Gateway.
This is a common way of defining rest APIs using API definition as code.
You can also export your current APIs from API Gateway as swagger
or OpenAPI 3 definition files.
This capability uses the API Gateway import API feature
to import an API from an external definition.
And you specify the options using a mode query parameter in the request URL.
And just to finish off, here's an example of a template for a swagger 2.0 API.
So this could be imported into API Gateway to create a REST API from a definition
that you might have exported from some other API
that you're using that is based on swagger