Hi guys. In this lesson you're going to
learn about caching and throttling with API Gateway.
Firstly caching.
You can add caching to API calls by provisioning and API gateway cache
and you need to specify the size of the cache in gigabytes.
Caching allows you to cache the endpoints response.
Caching and can reduce the number of calls to the backend
And that can improve latency of requests to your API.
So let's say we have an API. Users are connecting. We then have a cache.
So firstly we're going to check the cache. The API
is going to see is the request response cached in the API cache.
If not then we need to pass on to the backend.
So that would then be the second stage.
So if it's not in the cache, that's a cache miss
then the API will still need to go to the backend,
get a response and then cache it for next time.
Of course the caching is enabled on the stage level. We saw that in a previous lesson.
So we enable our cache and we specify the size in gigabytes.
We can also put the encryption to on or off and we can set
a time to live for the items that are actually cached in that cache.
So API gateway caches will cache the responses for a specific amount
of time and that is the time to live or TTL.
The default is 300 seconds,
minimum is zero and the max is 3600.
Caches are defined per stage and you can encrypt your caches.
The cache capacity ranges from 0.5 gigabytes up to 237 gigabytes.
And it's possible to override cache settings
for specific methods.
You can also flush the entire cache. That means invalidating it immediately
if you need to.
Clients can invalidate the cache with the header cache control
max age equals 0. One to remember for the exam.
So next let's look at throttling.
API Gateway sets a limit on the steady state rate
and burst of requests submissions against all APIs in your account.
So let's look at the limits.
By default
API Gateway will limit the steady state request rate to 10,000 requests a second.
The maximum concurrent requests is 5000 requests
across all API within an account.
And if you go over those limitations you will receive a 429
too many requests error response.
Upon catching these exceptions, the client can then resubmit the failed requests
in a way that's rate-limiting while complying with the throttling limits.
So that means you need the logic in your application to sort of back off and
not send the requests at such a high rate because API Gateway can't keep up.
API Gateway has two basic types of throttling related settings you can configure.
First we've got server-side throttling.
These limits are applied across all clients.
They exist to prevent your API
and your account from being overwhelmed by too many requests.
Then we've got per client.
These throttling limits are applied to clients that
use API keys associated with your usage policy
as client identifier.
The throttling related settings are applied in the following order;
Per client per method limits that you set for an API stage in a usage planner first.
Then per client limits that you set
in a usage plan.
Then default per method limits and individual per method limits that you
set in API stage settings and finally the account level throttling.