Hi guys. In this lesson, we're going to have a
look at the caching and throttling settings for our API.
So back in API gateway, I already have my Lambda simple proxy REST API.
So let's choose the REST API here.
And if I go down to stages,
we've got the prod stage.
And here we can enable an API cache.
Now this is the stage level so, for example, we can go up and deploy another stage.
So let's create a
test stage,
deploy
now we have two stages so we can configure
an API cache on one stage but not another. So all of these settings are tage-specific.
And as you'll see
the stages each have their own invoke URL.
So here we have /test on the end whereas for our prod stage we have /prod.
So to enable an API cache we simply enable this option here.
And then we specify
the capacity settings. So for example 0.5 gigabytes
in terms of the capacity of the cache.
And note that the API
cache does increase costs and it's not covered by the free tier.
So I'm not going to enable it.
You can encrypt your cache as well
and you can specify the time to live, so how long something should remain in the cache.
So maybe I'll set that to five minutes
or 300 seconds. Under pair key cache invalidation,
we can require authorization.
And we've got some settings for handling unauthorized requests.
We can then enable or disable throttling.
So this will set the rate of requests that are allowed to our API.
Now we've enabled here 10,000 requests per second.
That is the account level throttling rate.
And also
There's a burst limit here of 5000.
So you'd have to go to WS if you wanted to exceed that.
You can easily reduce it here if you want to as well.
And then you'd simply save changes if you wanted to save these changes,
which I'm not going to.
So that's all I wanted to show you in this lesson.
It's quite simple to enable caching and throttling.
And again for the exam,
just make sure you remember that the settings are specified at the stage level.