In this lesson,
we're going to have a look at the settings for usage plans and API keys.
So back in API Gateway first I'm going to go down to API keys.
This is very simple. What we're gonna do in here is literally just create API key.
We're gonna give it a name so I'd suggest customer name.
So, you know, this could be sort of customer A.
And then we can allow it to auto generate. So let's click on save.
And now we have an API key.
So if we just go back to our API
and now choose usage plans, we can create usage plans.
And it's given us an example here of basic. So let's create one called Basic.
So we have Basic and we can enable throttling.
Maybe for our basic plan we only want to enable 500 requests per second
and a burst of 50.
We can also enable a quota of requests per month.
So maybe that one will be 10,000.
Let's click on next.
You can now associate with a stage, we'll skip that for now and click on done.
Then let's create another usage plan and this one is going to be advanced.
So this could be another tier that you're selling to your customers.
So perhaps this time we've got 1,000 and 500
and here we have 50,000 per month.
So now we've given
more resources or more ability to consume resources to this particular customer.
So click on skip and then done.
So we now have our two usage plans. One is called basic.
That's going to be for our customers who are paying a lower rate to us
and then advance would be for our customers who are spending a bit more money.
and they get more resources available to them.
We can add API keys in here now.
So you can add an API key to your usage plan.
If I just type space
it will then show the keys I have available.
So I'm going to use the tick box to select that key.
Come back.
Also I can add a stage.
So if I add a stage then I can choose the Lambda simple proxy API.
And then choose the stage within that API. So let's say prod.
And click on the tick mark.
So there you can see that we have now associated
our usage plan with an API and an API stage.
There's also method throttling.
So you can configure throttling at the method level as well.
So for example here we can add
the resource and the method, so we have star or we have /Hello world.
And then you can choose the methods from the list of available methods
that you want to set your request rate and burst rate to.
So here we only have one method but if
we had multiple methods we could choose one of them
and say well, for this specific method I want to have a different rate
like a lower rate for example.
So that's method specific throttling.
So that's it. I finished with this API.
And what I'm going to do is I'm just going to go and delete the API.
So just choose actions and delete
and it will delete our API.
That's it for this lesson. I hope you enjoyed it. I'll see you in the next one.