Hi guys. In this hands-on lesson,
we're going to create a microservices application that uses
API Gateway with a REST API, AWS Lambda, and a DynamoDB table.
So this is the simple diagram of how it looks. We have our REST API.
We can use that to post a request and that is sent then to Lambda
through in this case, a non-proxy integration.
Lambda is then going to create an item in our DynamoDB table.
So very simple, let's go over to the console and start building this out.
Now, the first thing we need to do is create a role for our Lambda function to use.
Now, I've actually created a file that has all of the instructions and steps
for performing this exercise.
So in the file, it's in the code directory of course, Amazon API Gateway
and it's called API Lambda DynamoDB HOL.
So the first thing is we need to create an IAM policy for the Lambda execution role.
And it's going to use this JSON information.
So we can copy all of this JSON code to our clipboard.
Now this is going to provide
access to use certain API actions. So it's going to allow our function
to speak to DynamoDB
to Get items, Put items, Delete items, Query, Scan, and also Update items.
And the resource is Any.
Of course you could filter that down to your specific table if you wanted to.
It's also allowed to talk to CloudWatch logs to create
a log group, stream, and to put log events.
So let's copy that information and go and create the policy.
So I'm going to go to policies,
create policy,
choose JSON,
delete all of this code,
paste my code in.
And this is the policy name I'm going to provide.
So coming back, let's choose next,
review,
give it the name,
paste that in,
and let's create this policy.
We're then going to create a role
and the role is going to use that policy.
So let's create role.
It's going to use Lambda. So it's gonna be for a Lambda use case. Choose next.
We need to find the permissions policy we created.
So I'm going to paste that in.
Now, I found my policy.
Choose next.
And I'm going to call this almost the same but we
backspace and just put role on the end rather than policy.
So then let's create that role.
And that's being created.
So back in our file,
the next thing to do was to create the execution role. We've just done that.
So the next thing is going to be to create the Lambda function.
And the name of the function is specified here and you should use this name.
It's going to be Node.js and we're going to use the Lambda API Gateway role
as the execution role.
So in Lambda, I'm gonna create my function.
Give it the function name that I copied,
choose change execution role,
choose use an existing role,
and then we're going to find our role.
And we can see it here. It's called Lambda Api Gateway role.
And then let's create our function.
So that was nice and quick because it didn't create an execution role.
We already gave it one.
We're going to remove this code and go and copy the code from our file.
So the code is here in your file, it starts with the words console.log
and it comes all the way down here
to just before where it says for test the function.
So copy that to your clipboard.
Back in Lambda. Let's paste that in
and click on deploy.
And that's done.
Now you can optionally test the function so you can use this as some test code
or even do it from the command line here using the AWS Lambda invoke command.
I'm pretty sure it's gonna work. So I'm just gonna move on to create my REST API.
Now my REST API is going to be called DynamoDB Operations
and it's going to be a new API with a regional endpoint.
So back in API Gateway, let's choose REST API,
click on OK, let's go to new API, give it a name,
leave it as regional and create the API.
Now back in our file, you can see the next thing
to do is to create a resource called DynamoDB Manager.
So I'm gonna copy that name and that will create
a resource using /DynamoDB manager as the URL.
We're then going to connect to our Lambda function using a non-proxy integration.
So let's create our resource.
Paste in the resource name we just copied.
Click on create resource.
And then we're going to create our method and that will be a Post method.
So choose create method,
choose post,
click the tick.
It's going to be a Lambda function.
We'll find our Lambda function in here.
It's called Lambda function over HTTPS.
We're not going to enable it as a proxy integration this time.
Let's click on save,
and OK.
So that's done. Our REST API is now ready.
And what we're going to do shortly is use the
test function to actually submit requests to our API through here
rather than doing it from an external invoke URL.
But first we need to go and create our DynamoDB table.
So back in the file, you will see the name of the table we need to create.
And for the partition key, we're going to use ID.
So in DynamoDB I'm going to create a table,
give it that name, choose ID as the partition key.
We're not going to specify a sort key.
We're just going to create the table.
And that's done.
So now, all we need to do is actually test our configuration.
So what we're going to do is go to the DynamoDB manager resource,
choose the Post method, and in the execution pane,
we're going to use that test function.
So I'm gonna copy this code here.
And let's go back to API Gateway.
So back in API Gateway, we're in the right place here,
so we're in the DynamoDB Manager resource post method, and I'm going to choose test.
Don't put anything in the query strings or the headers.
We're just going to paste this code into the request body
and choose test.
And we can see here that we have a status code 200.
That's successful, you can see the latency.
And you can see the execution log here.
Now the test is now to really go over to DynamoDB.
We're going to explore the items in our table.
And now we have an item that has been created
From the api Gateway.
So for example, you could come in here and change this to something else,
give it a different value,
click on test,
come back,
and we'll see
that we now have another item.
So that's how that works.
Now, you can also test updating an item as well. So here what we have is this code
is essentially talking to the same item but rather than creating the item
it's updating the items.
So the ID is the same as the ID here but the number of value has changed to 999.
So let's copy that code.
Back in API Gateway, we're going to paste that in.
Click on test.
Looks like it was also successful.
Come back,
and now when we refresh it should change that value.
So that's it. That was a successful test. We now have a REST API.
And when we submit certain information to the REST API
it sends out through the Lambda. Lambda, processes the data
and then writes an entry to DynamoDB.
So I'm done with this. Now what I'm going to do is go back to tables.
I'm going to delete my table.
And I'm going to go back to API Gateway
and I'm going to delete my API.
So those are the only two things that potentially can
cost you some money if you're not in the free tier.
And let's just get rid of those. The Lambda functions won't cost anything.
So I hope that worked well for you and I'll see you in the next lesson.