Hi guys and welcome to this section on the AWS developer tools.
I think this is one of the most interesting and fun sections in the course.
I enjoy working with these services a lot.
The developer tools are used for
continuous integration and continuous deployment.
Now, if you've been working in a development environment,
you know exactly what that is
and if you haven't, you've probably heard of it
and we will go into a description in one of the very first
lessons to help you make sure you understand what those concepts are.
And we're gonna look at these tools provided to us by AWS for managing our code,
for testing our code, building it and deploying it to our applications.
So those are services such as
CodeCommit,
AWS Codebuild,
AWS codedeploy and AWS Codepipeline,
and it's not just theory. Of course, we're going to get hands on with these services.
So I hope you enjoyed this section and I'll see you in the next lesson.