Welcome to this lesson. I'm going to cover Continuous Integration and Continuous Delivery
in this particular lesson, just to talk a little bit about how it works and what tools we might use.
And then we're going to go into the specific tools for AWS in the next couple of lessons.
So with continuous integration
we have our developers and we have a repository where they're going to commit their code.
So in this case, it's CodeCommit.
Now, it could be GitHub or CodeCommit.
These are just a couple of the options available.
And GitHub is obviously the most popular.
It's very well known.
CodeCommit is an AWS option.
And CodeCommit is based off Git as well.
So the developer is writing their code and then is committing that code to CodeCommit.
Then we have something like CodeBuild.
So CodeBuild is a service which actually performs build and test for the code.
So the code goes from the repository.
Automatically the CodeBuild service will pick those changes up, whatever is being committed to
the code repository.
It's then going to build that code and test the code.
Then the results are actually returned back to the developer.
So continuous integration really just means that you've got this ongoing cycle where the developer
can then work out what happened in the results, determine what they need to change, change the code,
commit the code, and then it goes back through the process and gets built and tested again.
We then have continuous delivery.
So again, we have our developer, our code repository.
The developer commits their code.
The code then gets built and tested.
We have the results returned back to the developer, but we then have the extra piece here, which is
to actually deliver or deploy that code to the end
resources.
In AWS we can use AWS CodeDeploy for this.
So the code gets released for deployment and then you have your application and actually gets deployed
on the application.
Now, all of this can be automated through what we call a pipeline.
So we have these three particular phases.
We've got the code where it's being written and then committed to a repository,
the build and test, where we then have a service for building and testing the code
and then the deployment where it gets actually deployed out to the actual end resource,
the end application.
Of course, we don't have to use AWS for these services.
We can use GitHub as a code repository, Jenkins to build and test, and Ansible for deployment.
And those are just a few of the most popular options.
Now, we can wrap all this up into our pipeline.
So we have our three phases.
And in the AWS world, if you're using AWS developer tools, you can then use AWS CodePipeline.
Now, CodePipeline can also work with third party services like GitHub as well.
So the Code pipeline will help to automate the entire process from where the code is committed through to
the actual deployment with the build and test in the middle.
And you could have stage gates as well.
So you can approve or have some kind of checks and balances going on before you actually have your code
pushed right out to the end resource.
So that's the basic process of the CICD and we're going to see how we can use these AWS tools
over the next couple of lessons.