In this lesson, we're going to cover CodeCommit and CodePipeline.
So we saw the basic process before.
We have developers, we can have multiple developers working on a repository and committing code to
CodeCommit.
So CodeCommit is a fully managed source control service and it hosts secure Git-based repository.
So it's fully compatible with Git. You can use Git on the client side.
Git is an open source distributed source control system and it's the most popular option available.
It has a centralized repository for all your code, your binaries, your images and your libraries,
and it can track and manage code changes and maintain version history as well.
It will also manage updates from multiple sources.
So again, we can have multiple people working on a project and it will manage all that for you.
And that means you can have collaborative work being done in a team of developers.
CodeCommit repositories are private and it scales seamlessly.
It's integrated with Jenkins, CodeBuild and other continuous integration tools as well.
And you can transfer your files to and from CodeCommit using HTTPS and SSH.
Your repositories are automatically encrypted with AWS KMS and you can have your own
customer specific keys for that as well.
You have to configure your Git client to communicate with CodeCommit repositories and we'll see how
to do that in the hands-on.
IAM supports CodeCommit and there's a couple of different types of credentials.
You've got to Git credentials which are generated by IAM and has a username and password pair,
and that's for use over HTTPS.
We've then got SSH keys, which can be associated with your IAM user accounts and that's for using SSH
obviously.
We then have AWS Access Keys as well and those can be used with HTTPS.
CodePipeline is a continuous delivery service.
So this is going to automate the entire release pipeline for your code from commit right the way through
to deployment.
So it'll automate, build, test and deploy phases and every time you make a code change, it will automate
the entire process for you.
We'll see this in the hands-on.
It can also work with multiple third party options.
Things like your source stage could be S3, CodeCommit, GitHub, ECR or Bitbucket.
For build you can use CodeBuild or Jenkins and for deploy you can use CloudFormation,
CodeDeploy, ECS, Elastic Beanstalk, AWS Service Catalog and S3.
Let's look at some of the concepts for CodePipeline.
Pipelines are the workflow that describes how software changes are released.
You'll see how it works.
We connect the different phases, so the source control to the build and test and then to the deployment.
We then have artifacts and these are files or changes that get worked on by the actions and stages
in the pipeline.
Each pipeline stage can create some kind of artifacts and they're passed and stored in S3
for the next stage.
Then we have the stage.
So the pipeline is broken up into multiple stages and each one can be a sequence of actions and parallel
actions.
And obviously a good example of this would be build, test and deploy.
And then you might have some kind of load testing in there as well.
You could also define manual approval steps at any stage.
We then have the actions.
Stages contain at least one action and they can affect the artifacts and we'll
have artifacts as inputs or outputs.
And we then have transitions, which is about progressing from one stage to another.
Now, what we're going to do in a hands on very soon is CodePipeline with Elastic Beanstalk.
So let's look at what that would look like.
We have our developer, CodeCommit, and then Beanstalk and we put that into a pipeline.
So the developer will commit some code and the code gets pushed through to Elastic Beanstalk.
And we'll see how we can automate this entire process.
Beanstalk will then update the application and deploy whatever update we've made in our code through to
our application.