Hi guys. In this lesson, we're going to go into AWS CodeCommit.
I'm going to show you around and we're going to create a repository.
And then we're going to clone that repository down to our computers.
So I'm logged on and I'm on the dashboard for AWS CodeCommit.
Now, as you can see on the left hand side here,
we've got the developer tools and we're actually focused on CodeCommit,
which is dealing with source code.
But then we've got CodeArtifact for artifacts,
CodeBuild for running builds and tests, CodeDeploy for running deployments,
and CodePipeline for creating pipelines.
So we're going to work with multiple of those services in this section.
For now, all we're going to do is focus on AWS CodeCommit.
I've clicked on repositories and I'm going to create a new repository.
And I'm going to call this one Developer-Labs and click on create.
So that's all there is to actually creating a repository.
Now we can see there are some connection steps.
We've got HTTPS, SSH, or HTTPS GRC.
With HTTPS, this is the URL for cloning.
In fact this is the entire command for cloning the repository down to our computers.
And we will go ahead and do that.
But first, we need to go to IAM and we need some credentials.
So I'm going to click on users, choose my user account.
On the security credentials page, we just scroll down.
You'll see here we have HTTPS Git credentials for CodeCommit.
So what we need to do is generate credentials.
And just like with access keys, we're going to copy the access key
and the password somewhere so we can enter it when we're cloning our repository.
Back in CodeCommit, I'm going to copy
the command to clone the repository.
And on the command line I'm going to run this command.
So it's now cloning our repository.
And it wants my username.
So I've entered my username and now it needs the password.
Once you've entered the password, hit enter.
And then it just warns us to let us know that we've cloned an empty repository.
And that's expected. We don't have any code in our repository at this point in time.
So now I should be able to change into that repository.
And there it is.
So I've changed directory to Developer Labs
because that's the name of the repository.
So it's created that directory when I did the cloning.
So now I have my master branch for Developer Labs.
But there's nothing actually in there at the moment.
So let's test creating a file and then committing
that file and pushing it up to our repository.
So I'm going to create a file. Just like before I'm going to call it my test file.
So now, if I run Git status we know that we have an untracked file.
I'm going to run Git add -A
That's going to add the file.
Then I'm going to run Git Commit -m and I'm going to call this first commit.
Hit enter.
And now let me just bring this back up to the middle of the screen.
What we can now do is run Git push.
And that's going to push it up to our repository
And we can see that's happened.
So let's go back to CodeCommit and have a look.
Back in CodeCommit. I'm going to refresh the page.
And now we can see that we have our test file.
So very simple test just to add a file.
While we're here, let's go to settings and have a look around CodeCommit.
So first we have the repository name here. So I'm in the settings for my repository.
You'll see that we also have notifications so we
can actually create notifications based on certain triggers
like commits, on pull requests, on status changed and so on.
And then for targets we've got SNS topics or AWS chatbots slack.
Then we have triggers.
If I choose to create a trigger here, we can give the trigger a name.
Choose the event that we want to actually cause the trigger to be executed,
And then the service to use. So either SNS or AWS Lambda.
You can also add tags to your repository and use code guru reviewer
to give you some recommendations on improving your Java and Python code.
And that's all there is for this lesson. Don't delete your repository.
We will be using it again.