Hi guys. In this lesson, we're going to create a CodePipeline
and we're going to integrate it with CodeCommit and Elastic Beanstalk so that we can
deploy updated code to a Beanstalk application.
Now you saw this diagram before and this is exactly what we're going to be using.
So we're going to have our cloned repository on our computers.
We're going to make changes to code.
It's going to push that code up to CodeCommit, using Git push.
And then CodeCommit and Elastic Beanstalk are both in this pipeline.
So the pipeline will then automate the movement and the deployment of that code
into Elastic Beanstalk.
So I'm in the console and the first thing I'm going
to do is create a new environment in Elastic Beanstalk.
It's going to be a web server environment
and I'm going to just call this Developer Labs.
Now, all I really need to do, it's going to give me a default environment name.
I'm happy with that.
All I need to do is change to Node.js,
use the sample application, and create the environment.
So that will start with a default sample application.
It's going to take a few minutes.
And while that's happening we can go and create the rest of our configuration.
Back on the command line, I deleted the test file that we used
in the previous lesson.
And what I'm going to do is just commit that change. So I'm going to run Git add -A
and then Git commit -m and then just
put in the description here that says deleted file.
That's done.
Let's just push those changes.
I just want to make sure we got a clean repository before we get started.
So that is ready.
Now, in my file system I have the course download the code directory.
And if you go into developer tools you will find this Node.js-Blue.zip.
I'm going to double click that.
Open it up.
And then I'm basically just going to select all of these items,
copy those to my clipboard and then go to the directory that our repository is in.
So my repository directory is developer-labs in my documents directory.
And so I'm going to paste in all of these files.
So now back on the command line, if I run Git status,
we can see that we have these untracked files.
Now we're not going to do anything about that yet.
We don't want to commit them at this stage
because we haven't created our pipeline.
So those are there. Let's go over to the console and create our CodePipeline.
So back in the console here,
I'm going to head down to pipeline,
choose pipelines.
We're going to create a pipeline.
Just keeping the developer labs as the name for everything in this particular lesson.
So let's just call that Developer Labs.
We're going to allow AWS to create a new service role
and it's given us the role name here.
We don't need to change any advanced settings. We can click on next.
Under source provider, choose CodeCommit.
Then you can find the repository and we're going to choose the master branch.
We'll leave the default settings here.
Click on next.
For build provider, this is where you can choose a build provider.
We're going to use CodeBuild a bit later on in this section.
But for now we're going to skip the build stage.
So I'll confirm that I'm skipping.
For deployment provider, I do need to select an option.
So you can see all the different deployment providers that are supported here.
Now we have our application in Elastic Beanstalk
so Beanstalk will be able to push the updates.
So we choose beanstalk.
It's automatically selected the region.
I can choose my app.
And then my environment name.
And click on next.
And that's everything. I just scroll down and create the pipeline.
So that's it. The pipeline has been created.
Now what you'll find happens is it's automatically going to
try and pull any changes from CodeCommit.
Now, we don't have any at this stage. So that process should actually fail.
And now we can see that that did fail.
And if we choose details, it says the process to upload the contents of
the repository failed for the following reason, null.
So there was nothing there,
And that's to be expected.
So let's go back to the command line
and we're going to commit our files and push them into the repository.
So back on the command line. I'm going to run Git add
-A
Git commit -m and add a description.
And those are being committed.
So now let's push those changes up to our repository.
And that's done.
So back in our pipeline,
what we should find is very soon it's going to start checking CodeCommit.
There we go.
It's checked. It succeeded.
And now we're in the deployment. That's in progress.
So it's going to deploy those changes to Elastic Beanstalk.
So in Beanstalk, before it changes
I should have shown this before but you click on here and it's green.
Okay so this is pre-change.
So the actual congratulations message has a green background.
That's the default when you use the sample application.
And we can see that there is an update happening and once that's complete,
the background should change to blue. So let's give that a moment.
So the update is complete.
Let's go to Beanstalk and let's just give this page a refresh.
And now the background has changed to blue.
So looking at our diagram,
what we've done is we've added the files which changed the background to blue
into our repository on our local computer, the clone
of the repositories in CodeCommit.
We then pushed those changes up to CodeCommit
and CodePipeline has then picked up those changes,
pushed them through the Beanstalk and Beanstalk has then updated the application.
So that's it for this lesson. And don't bring anything down.
We're going to use Elastic Beanstalk and our pipeline in another hands-on lesson.