In this lesson, you'll learn about AWS CodeBuild.
So CodeBuild is a fully managed continuous integration service.
What it does is it will compile your source code,
it can run tests and it can produce software packages that are
then ready for deployment.
It will scale continuously and process multiple builds concurrently.
And you only pay based on the time it takes to actually complete your builds.
It integrates with various source code repositories, including GitHub,
CodeCommit, CodePipeline, S3, and others.
You define your build instructions in code using the buildspec.yml file.
And we'll go over some more details about that file a bit later on.
Output logs can also be sent to Amazon S3 and Amazon CloudWatch logs.
So what are the components?
Firstly, you create a build project.
And this will define how CodeBuild will run a build and the settings include
the location of the source code, the build environment to use,
the build commands to run,
and where to store the output of the build.
Then you have the build environment.
Here you specify the operating system, language runtime,
and tools that CodeBuild will use for the build.
And then lastly here we have the build specification.
This is the YAML file that describes
the collection of commands and settings for CodeBuild to run a build.
And here's an example of a buildspec.yml file.
And as you can see, there are phases here.
And under the phases, we can see the individual phases themselves.
We've got install, then we have a command block,
Pre-build, another commands  block, build, and post build.
And there's a few more options as well.
And as you can see within each of these,
we in this case are using a commands block to actually run some commands.
In this table, you can see the various options for phases.
So firstly, we have run as. This is optional as are all of the phases in this list.
With the run as phase, you specify a Linux user that runs the commands.
In the on failure phase,
you can specify the action to take if failure occurs during the phase,
either abort or continue.
The finally phase runs commands after commands in the commands block
even if the commands in the command block fail.
Then we have install.
This is the commands to run during install.
Pre-build, the commands to run before the build.
Build the commands to run during the build and then post build,
which is of course the commands to run after the build.
So let's have a look at an example CI/CD pipeline with CodeBuild.
So we have CodePipeline.
We've got CodeCommit and CodeBuild and an Elastic Beanstalk application.
We then have our developer.
Our developer is going to add the buildspec.yml file to the CodeCommit repository.
Then CodeBuild is going to run some tests.
Now in our particular example, which we'll actually be performing in the hands-on,
we're going to test for the existence of a specific file.
Then we'll have an option for manual approval.
So nothing will continue until the approver goes in and approves
that the code can be deployed to the Elastic Beanstalk application.
Then Beanstalk is going to actually deploy the updates to the Node.js app.
So that's just one example of using CodeBuild. And in our hands on,
that's what we're going do.
We'll test for the existence of a file.
If it's there, then the build passes.
If it's not, the build fails.
Of course, in the real world, you'll often use CodeBuild to fully build out
your application for deployment.
So you could be running a lot more commands than we see in our example here.