CodeStar is another service that you don't need to know too much
about for the exam but it does come up here and there.
So just a basic understanding of what it is and how it works will suffice.
So, CodeStar enables you to quickly develop, build, and deploy applications on AWS.
And it's basically a pre-configured continuous delivery
toolchain for developing, building, testing, and deploying.
So it pulls together a lot of what we've learned about in this section
into one place so that with a couple of clicks,
you're building out your entire pipeline and it's deploying your
application for you based on some pre-configured options.
You can use project templates to develop applications on services like EC2,
Lambda, and Elastic Beanstalk.
You can also use code editors like Visual Studio, Eclipse,
or the AWS CLI.
With CodeStar, you use IAM to manage developer identities.
And there's built-in role-based policies for secure team access.
You get to share projects with your team with three different access levels.
You've got owners, contributors, and viewers.
Application code is stored in AWS CodeCommit.
And CodeStar compiles and packages source code with CodeBuild.
And a pre-configured pipeline is created for you using CodePipeline.
The actual deployments are automated as well
using CodeDeploy and CloudFormation.
So pulling all that together,
With CodeStar, you can connect your ID
to CodeStar, your integrated development environment.
CodeStar will then basically take care of everything for you.
So it will coordinate CloudFormation, CodeCommit, CodeBuild, and CodeDeploy.
And it will create things like buckets,
Lambda functions, API endpoints, or part of the application
deployment and all managed by CodeStar.
And that's it for this lesson. I will see you in the next one.