in this lesson, I'm going to cover AWS amplify and apps sync
and we'll get started with Amplify.
Amplify is a set of tools and features for building full stack applications on AWS.
That means it will build the web and mobile back ends
as well as the web front end user interfaces.
Amplified studio is a visual interface for building web and mobile apps.
You can use the visual interface to define a data model,
user authentication and fast storage without having the expertise
in building out the back end.
You can easily add AWS services not available
within amplified studio using the cloud development kit,
the AWS C D K.
You can connect mobile and web apps using amplify libraries for IOS,
android flutter react native and web using javascript.
Amplify hosting is a fully managed continuous integration,
continuous delivery and hosting service
for fast, secure and reliable static and service side
rendered apps. Next up we have apps sync
app syncs are fully managed service for developing graph QL. Ap eyes
applications can securely access,
manipulate and receive real time updates from different data sources
like databases or a P I. S.
And in the diagram here we can see a series of absent data sources.
We've got lambda dynamodb elasticsearch, Arora, a pub sub system.
So that's going to be the simple notification service and an http source.
And then on the front end we're able to unify this information
together with appsync so that we can deliver information to our clients
absent automatically scales the graph QL Api execution engine up and down to meet.
Api request volumes.
It uses graph QL,
which is the data language that enables client apps
to fetch change and subscribe to data from service
absent,
lets you specify which portions of your data should
be available in real time manner using graph QL subscriptions
and it supports lambda, dynamodb and elasticsearch.
As we saw in the diagram,
you can also have service side data cache and capabilities
reducing the need to directly access your data sources.
So that means better performance and fewer aPI calls to your back end.
Appsync is fully managed and it eliminates the operational
overhead of managing your own clusters as well.
Now let's see appsync in action with amplify as well.
So in this example we're using up sink
and amplify to simplify access to microservices.
Amplify is used to build and host the web
store application and create the back end services.
And then on the front end there we
have appsync creating a unified api layer for integrating
the various microservices running behind it