Hello and welcome to this section.
This section is all about the AWS command line interface, the Cli
So we will be using the Cli quite a few
times in the hands on lessons throughout the course.
So this section is about getting you prepared
now it is a short section but it's very useful.
So what we'll do is we'll look at how we can install the Cli on our computers,
whatever operating system you're running.
Then we're going to configure credentials that we
have authentication and access to AWS Resources.
I'll show you around the Cli teach you some
of these sort of fundamental ways you can navigate,
find help and use some basic commands.
And then lastly we're going to carry on from what we did at the
end of the previous section where we actually assumed a role using the console
in this section.
What we're going to do is assume a role using the cli a really useful technique.
So I hope you enjoy it and I'll see you in the next lesson.