In this lesson, I'm going to give you an overview of actually using the
command line interface and you'll get to practice some basic CLI commands.
I'm logged into my Linux instance and I have my CLI installed here.
And it's configured with Paul's credentials.
So we'll be able to run commands as Paul.
Now, you need to have the AWS configure
command run and you'd supply it some credentials.
We did that in a previous lesson.
And you can be on any operating system.
It doesn't matter if you're using Linux, Mac, or windows.
So let's run a couple of commands.
First, I'm just going to run AWS Help.
The help menu gives us contextual information about
the command that we're running, in this case, simply the AWS command.
So it tells us a description, synopsis, and it provides some of the options.
We can see some information here.
We can just keep hitting our space bar to go through
Then under available services, we can see the various services
that we can interact with using the CLI.
So you'll see there's hundreds of services in here.
Now typing Q, I'm able to quit.
And then I can run another command and in this case,
what I'm going to do is I'm going to choose to run the help command against AWS EC2.
So now I get the help menu specifically for the EC2 command,
so any of the commands that are related to the elastic compute cloud.
So again here, if we scroll through, we'll see quite a bit of information.
These are all of the options for how we can work with Amazon EC2.
So if I just keep hitting enter,
you can see lots of options to copy, to cancel, to create.
If we go down a bit further, you'll see that you can delete things
using the CLI, so you can do pretty much anything with the CLI.
If I just keep going down a bit further,
we'll get down to the describe.
So here we can see we've got the describe options.
Let's just scroll down a little bit further. We'll hit enter a couple more times.
And what I should find is the describe instances.
We can see it right at the bottom of my screen here.
So that's an interesting command that will
give us some information about the instances running in the account.
So let's quit.
And what I'm going to do now is run AWS EC2 describe instances.
Now, of course, this particular user does have
privileges to EC2, and I am actually running a couple of EC2 instances.
So if you're not you won't get any output.
But in this case I have two instances running.
And we can see some information here about those instances.
So lots of information is returned.
So that's EC2.
Let's now have a look at AWS S3.
So if I type AWS S3,
and then help,
we can see the various different command options.
Now S3 is the simple storage service
and it's an object-based storage system that you'll learn about later in the course.
So again we get quite a bit of information about the command,
and then we can see various options and examples of how we can use it.
Now, what I'm going to do is just quit out of there.
And we're going to run a couple of commands.
Firstly, I'm going to run the command AWS S3 mb.
Now mb is used to create a bucket and bucket is simply the container
into which you can upload files.
I then need to type S3://
and I need to put in a bucket name.
So I'm going to call it my test bucket.
And the name has to be unique across Amazon S3.
So I'm just going to put in a bunch of random characters to make sure it's unique
and then hit enter.
And that was unique.
So I was able to create the bucket.
So if I now run AWS S3 LS, we can then see that we have a bucket.
Now, what if I want to copy something to S3?
Well, let's create a file.
So I'll create a file simply called testfile.txt.
Of course it's an empty file but it does exist now on my hard drive.
So what I'm going to do then is run AWS S3 CP.
This is copy, so I'm going to copy the file.
So I gave the path to the file, testfile.txt and then S3://.
And I'm going to take my bucket name from here,
paste that in and hit enter.
So now that file has been uploaded.
So what I can now do is actually view the contents of the bucket.
So I'm going to copy the bucket name.
So S3:// and then the bucket name to my clipboard,
run AWS S3 LS, put in the bucket,
and we can see the contents of the bucket and it has the test file in it.
So that's super simple, very easy to work with S3 from the command line.
Now I finished with this particular test.
So what I want to do is actually remove my bucket.
Now, the way I do that is I type in AWS S3 RB for remove bucket,
and then I put in the bucket name.
Now we do actually have a file in the bucket.
So what happens is if we hit enter
it doesn't actually work and it tells us that it's not empty.
All we need to do to fix that is type --force, hit enter,
and now it's been removed.
So if we run AWS S3 LS, we no longer have any buckets.
So that's it for this lesson.
Really just a basic overview. Once you know how to
work around the commands and use the help menu, it's very easy.
Now I do highly recommend using Google anytime you get stuck
with using the CLI, you'll find lots of examples online.
And just to show you a quick example, if I had an EC2 instance and I wanted
to delete it using the CLI,
I could type easy to delete CLI,
and then we find some options here.
Now, the actual terminology for EC2 is terminate.
But even if you didn't know that and you put delete, you would find the answer.
Now you can see there is a delete instance but that's for ops works.
So by selecting the entry here I can then find
lots of information about how to terminate the instance,
the various different command line options.
And there's typically also an example which you can then use.
So that's it for this lesson. I'll see you in the next one.