Hi, guys. In this lesson, I'm going to give you a general overview of serverless services and how
we can use serverless services and what we call an event-driven architecture.
Now, an event-driven architecture is an architectural pattern.
Now, it leverages technology where we have an event happen in one service that then triggers something
that happens in another service.
Now, it's not exclusive to serverless.
You can use it with non-serverless services as well.
But as you'll see, there are some really good use cases when you're building cloud native applications
on AWS for combining serverless services into an event driven architecture.
Now, we have talked about serverless a few times in this course
already. Serverless is a concept in which you don't manage the underlying servers, which run the capability.
So, you can have serverless compute services, storage services, databases and so on.
Now, there will always be an underlying compute layer to it.
There will be a server that's processing the capability, that's providing the capability. But you don't
manage it. AWS will manage that for you.
So let's have a look how we can use serverless services in an event-driven architecture.
So, let's say we have a static website running on Amazon S3. Now,
as you know, Amazon S3 is an object-based storage system and it is serverless because you don't
have any servers to manage and you can scale this capability seamlessly.
So let's say a user is going to upload a file to our S3 static website.
Now, what we want to happen is we want a Lambda function to actually then process that file and do something
with it.
The Lambda function knows that there's a file to process because of an event notification. So, this
is the first example of how we have event-driven activities taking place.
File gets uploaded to S3, S3 uses event notifications to tell Lambda that there's a file to
process.
Lambda can then process the file, and maybe it puts some modified objects in another S3 bucket.
At the same time, it could also trigger an event and in an SQS queue. So, it could send the file to an
SQS
queue. And then another Lambda function might be looking at that queue and saying, okay, there's something
in the queue to process.
Or the queue can be configured to actually trigger the Lambda function. So, it can work both ways.
Either way, what will happen is the Lambda function will then look at the queue, process the message, and
in this case, maybe it stores a record in the DynamoDB table.
DynamoDB is also a serverless service.
It's a database service.
So in this case, we have a processed object in a bucket and we have a record of the transaction in
a database as well.
We might also send a notification via an SNS topic. And that could go to somebody's inbox as an
email to let them know what's happened.
So that's how we use serverless services in an event-driven architecture.
And the great thing about AWS is lots of these capabilities,
these serverless service capabilities are there for you to use and they have great integration with
each other.
So, it's very easy to create these kind of event-driven architectures.
You simply need to supply the code for your Lambda functions and configure the various services to work
together.
Let's go over a few key facts about serverless services. With serverless,
there are no instances to manage.
So, with other services that are not serverless, you often have EC2 as the underlying compute layer.
So, you'll have to launch an instance, choose the instance type, the family and so on that you want
to use,
and then you've got to patch manage that instance.
You've got to secure the instance properly.
There might be operational management, backups, and so on.
So, there's quite a lot of work to do. But with serverless, you don't have any of that operational
overhead.
You don't need to provision hardware.
Of course, there's no underlying instance and there's no hardware supervision. And there's no management
of the operating system or the software running on top of it.
All capacity provisioning and patching is handled automatically.
So, with services like AWS Lambda which we're going to cover very soon, that runs code in response
to events.
Now, Lambda will scale seamlessly.
There's a few configuration parameters you need to define, but it will scale.
There's no running out of compute capacity there because you're not actually working with that underlying
compute layer
as you are with EC2. You get automatic scaling and high availability with serverless services.
And it can also be very, very cheap.
So, depending on your use case, you have to look at the pricing.
But often, services like Lambda can be extremely cheap for processing data.
As long as your use case does support Lambda, then Lambda can be a great way to run your code instead
of running EC2 instances or containers.