AWS Lambda is AWS is serverless compute service, and it's a service that we can use in event driven
architectures for running code based on triggers.
So let's have a look at what that means.
Well, we have a lambda function here.
The lambda function is created for the console or using the Seelye or the API.
And once you have the lambda function, you then upload some code.
So in this case, a developer is going to upload a zip file, and that code is now part of the lambda
function.
Now, at this point in time, nothing is happening.
Nothing is actually running.
Your code is just sat there and you don't pay anything until your code actually executes.
So what we need now is for a trigger to happen and cause the code to actually run.
Now these come from event sources.
Those sources can be the Seelye, the API, the SDK or they can be coming from another eight U.S. service.
We can also run our lambda functions on a schedule, so when the lambda function executes, the code
is run and it performs whatever you have program that code to do.
Lambda is typically used for code that will complete in a fairly short period of time.
In fact, lambda functions have a maximum execution time of 15 minutes.
So if your application needs to run a specific instance of a function for longer than 15 minutes, then
it's simply not going to work with Lambda.
And then you might want to use EC2 with EC2.
You can run your code for as long as you want.
Now, this is an individual instance of a function running that this actually applies to, and we'll
talk a bit more of that in a moment.
But if you have code that needs to run for a relatively short period of time, less than 50 minutes,
or maybe just a few seconds.
As with many use cases of lambda, then it can be very cost effective and obviously you have no service
to manage here.
So that is another operational benefit that you get.
So Lambda will execute your code only when needed, and it scales automatically.
You pay only for the compute time you consume and you don't pay anything when your code is not running.
Now there's also another factor, which is the amount of memory you've assigned to your function, so
you pay more if you have more memory and that will actually proportionally add more CPU to your function
as well.
So benefits of lambda, all you have no service to manage, it scales continuously.
And that means it's really elastic for use cases where you need your scale, your application to scale
really quickly, you get millisecond billing.
It can be very, very cost effective to run your code using lambda.
It also integrates with almost all other AWS services primary use cases for AWS lambda or data processing,
real time file processing, real time stream processing.
So each of these you might have some data that needs to be analyzed or modified in some way, and that
can be coming in through various different ways.
It could be in a stream like a kinesis data stream.
It could be objects being uploaded to an S3 bucket and in an event driven architecture that will then
automatically trigger the function.
And you might also use it for building serverless backends for web, mobile, IoT and third party
API requests.
Now, there are a few different ways that you can actually invoke your lambda function.
The first is synchronous invocation.
This occurs from the CLI, the SDK or API Gateway.
In this case, you wait for the function to process the event and then it will return a response.
Success or failure error handling will happen.
On the client side.
This is things like retries is simply saying, Well, maybe it failed, so I'm going to try again.
Exponential back off is trying not to overwhelm the application.
So you might sort of back off for greater periods of time if it can't keep up with the processing.
We then have asynchronous invocation.
This is sources like S3, SNS and cloudwatch events.
In this case, the event is queued for processing and a response gets returned immediately.
Lambda will retry up to three times.
If there's any kind of issue, when actually performing the data processing.
The processing must be item impotent.
Now that means that if Lambda does retry multiple times, it cannot end up creating a different result
than the original intended result.
We then have event source mappings.
This is services such as SQS, Kinesis Data Streams, and DynamoDB streams.
In this case, Lambda does the polling, so Lambda is checking with these sources to find if there's
anything that needs to be processed.
So in the case of as it's looking into a Queue and saying, are there any messages to process with data
streams?
It's looking into a data stream and checking whether there are any entries DynamoDB streams, it's
looking for items in the stream and saying, Well, every time there's a new item, I want to pick it
up and process it.
So Lambda is doing the job of actually trying to find things to execute.
This is the other way round from synchronous and asynchronous, where you're actually triggering lambda
to do a job.
Records get processed in order, except for with Esquith standard, because Skews itself does not actually
order the records correctly.
Now, SQS can also trigger lambda.
So we an event source mapping lambda is actually check in and ask, ask you looking for messages and
if it finds them processing them.
But you can also configure a destination through SQS so that when a message gets added to the queue,
SQS is actually then forwarding that onto lambda, and lambda is processing that message.
So there's two different ways that you can do that.
Now, Lambda will actually scale concurrently.
So what that means is you execute your function, and multiple instances of the function can be executed
in parallel.
So if one execution hasn't completed all those different data to process, then Lambda will execute
multiple concurrent instances of your US lambda function.
Now these will be initialized up to the burst or account limit, and just to put a few here on the screen.
It's worth just understanding that they are different for different AWS regions.
So what happens if you reach your limits?
Well, if you reach a concurrency limit or exceed it, then throttling will occur, so it's not going
to allow you to continue scaling.
And you might get a rate exceeded message in your application or a 08:56.
Too many requests exceptions.
So watch out for those.
If you see those in exam questions, that means you've reached one of those limits and you can apply
to increase your account limits.