Hi guys.
Now, you are expected in the exam to have a solid
understanding of the different ways you can invoke Lambda functions.
So in this lesson we're going to deep dive into that subject.
So Lambda functions can be invoked directly
through the Lambda console, a function URL, HTTP or HTTPS endpoint,
and the Lambda API.
You can also invoke Lambda through the AWS software development kit, the SDK,
the CLI, the command line interface, and AWS toolkits.
Lambda can be invoked by other AWS services.
Lambda can also be invoked when reading from a stream or from a queue.
Functions get invoked synchronously or asynchronously.
So let's look into more detail on synchronous versus asynchronous invocation.
With synchronous invocation,
you wait for the function to process the event and return a response.
So your application is waiting for the function to
process that event and then get a response back.
With asynchronous invocation,
Lambda will queue the event for processing and returns a response immediately.
For asynchronous invocation
Lambda handles the retries and can send invocation records to a destination.
For synchronous invocation, your application will need to handle any retries.
A trigger can be configured to invoke a function in response to a lifecycle event,
an external request or on a specific schedule.
To process items from a stream or queue, you can create an event
source mapping, and we'll look at what that means shortly
and we'll see how it works in the hands-on lessons.
So now let's go deeper on synchronous invocation.
With this option,
you wait for the function to process the event and return a response.
Lambda runs the function and waits for a response.
And when the function execution ends,
Lambda returns the response from the functions code.
To invoke function synchronously with the AWS CLI, you use the invoke command.
So it looks like this. So here's an example of using the CLI to invoke a function.
We're using AWS Lambda and then invoke in order to do that.
We've defined a function name
and a payload which is some key value information.
And then response.json is for recording the response.
In this case, the latest version was actually executed and we get
a status code 200 so it is successful.
The payload itself is a string that contains an event
in JSON format, it's base64 encoded.
The name of the file where the CLI writes the response from
the function is response.json. We saw that in the command line.
To get the logs for an invocation from the command line,
you can use the --log type option with the AWS Lambda CLI command.
The response will include a log result field that contains up to 4 KB
of base64 encoded logs from the invocation.
Now, don't worry if a lot of this is just too theoretical,
we're going to do this in the practical exercises too.
Now, in this example here, we're using the AWS
Lambda invoke CLI command specifying a function
and then we've got out, and we've got log type and tail.
So we can actually see what's coming up in that log.
Now let's go back to asynchronous invocation.
Here Lambda queues the event for processing and returns a response immediately.
For asynchronous invocation,
Lambda handles the retries and can send invocation records
to a destination.
Lambda places the event in a queue and then
it returns a success response without any additional information.
To invoke a function
asynchronously using the CLI, you can set the invocation type parameter to Event.
And here's an example.
So now we're using Lambda invoke but we have
the invocation type of Event and that's for asynchronous invocation.
Now, let's move on to Event Source Mapping.
Lambda can process items from a stream or a
queue and you can create an event source mapping.
So this is an AWS Lambda resource that reads
from an event source and invokes the Lambda function.
You can use event source mappings to process items from a stream or a queue.
So I'm repeating this stuff quite a lot because you've got to remember this.
An Event Source Mapping will use permissions in the functions,
execution role to read and manage items
in the Event Source.
So for example, if you're reading from SQS,
then your functions
execution role needs to have the permissions for SQS
because that's where the permissions must be defined.
Event Source Mappings are used for processing events in SQS queues,
Kinesis streams, and DynamoDB streams.
So let's have a look at a diagram for an SQS Event Source Mapping.
So here we have an SQS queue, we've got our application
and our application is putting some items into the queue.
So, message has been added,
we've then got our Lambda function.
The Lambda function is going to poll the SQS queue.
So Lambda is doing the work of checking the queue.
We're not creating the Lambda function in this case as a destination.
What we're doing is getting Lambda to do the work of
monitoring the queue and seeing when there are records there.
Once it finds in processes a record, it might do something else.
So in this case, simply writing an event to CloudWatch logs.
Now, the services that are supported for this poll based event source mapping are
our DynamoDB, Kinesis, and SQS. Again, repeating myself,
but you've got to know this stuff.
The configuration of the event source mapping for the stream and queue based services
is made on the Lambda side.
For other services like S3,
and the simple notification service.
The function is invoked asynchronously
and the configuration is made on the other server side. So the S3 or SNS side
rather than the Lambda.
Next up, we have event notifications.
So for example, you can use Lambda to process event notifications from Amazon S3.
S3 will send an event to a Lambda function when
an object gets created or deleted and that's just an example.
It can be other actions as well.
You configure notification settings on the bucket side
and grant S3 the permission to invoke the function on the functions
resource-based permissions policy.
Amazon S3 invokes your function asynchronously with
an event that contains details about the object.
So that way you can process that object
using Lambda with the information that's supplied.
So let's look at a diagram.
Here, we have a user who is uploading a JPEG image to an images bucket.
We've then got Lambda.
Now our S3 bucket is going to send a notification
to Lambda to say that a new object has been uploaded.
Lambda is going to then process that image and resize the image.
So that's just an example
use case where we're resizing to create something like a thumbnail
of the image or processing it in some other way.
Lambda runs the code in response to the event.
So the event is the trigger for the invocation.
And now we have our resized image
in the bucket.
And then of course we could do something like write an Event to CloudWatch Logs,
save a record in a DynamoDB table or something like that.
So an event-driven architecture.
So that's it for invocation,
lots to take in there and it's all going to
make even more sense when we go into the hands-on.