Hi guys, In this hands-on lesson,
we're going to practice creating an event source mapping.
And we're going to do most of the configuration from the command line.
So in this case we're going to have a Lambda function,
an SQS queue, and we're also having CloudWatch where
we're going to record some information about what happens.
So our user
is going to add a message manually to the queue, that's us.
And then Lambda is going to poll the SQS queue. That's the event source mapping.
It then executes its function
and it actually writes an event to CloudWatch logs.
So that's essentially what we're doing.
Let's head over and build it out.
In your course download, you'll find in the code AWS Lambda,
and then the event source mapping directory you'll find
this event-source-mapping.MD file.
So we've got some of the commands that we're going to be running in here.
What we're going to do is we actually have an index.js file.
And we're going to zip that up as function.zip.
Then we're going to create the function from the command line.
We need to supply some information, we need to give it a name,
we need to supply the zip file so that's this command here.
We're then going to specify that the handler is index.handler for Lambda.
And the runtime is nodejs16.x.
And then we're going to supply a role ARN.
And we need to go and create that role now.
So let's go to the console and create our role and then we can add it to this command.
I'm in IAM.
I'm going to create a role.
So let's go create role.
And the service in this case is going to be AWS Lambda.
Then let's click on next.
And what we need to do here is find the permissions for SQS.
So I just search for SQS.
And we're going to use this one, AWSLambdaSQSQueueExecutionRole.
Click on next,
let's give the role a name.
Mine's called My SQS Role.
And we can see here that the trusted entities are Lambda.
So Lambda is gonna use this role and it's going to have permissions to SQS.
So that's great, let's create the role.
Role is created.
We're also going to need an SQS queue, so let's go and create our queue now as well.
So we're gonna go to the Simple Queue Service.
Now, we're going to learn a lot more about queues a bit later in the course,
but this is simply a message bus where we can add messages to the queue
and Lambda then processes them.
So what we're gonna do here is very simple, we just click create queue.
It's going to be a standard queue.
I'm simply going to call it My Queue.
And for now we can ignore all of this information
and simply come down
and create the queue.
So the queue is created.
We have our role as well, let's just find our role in the console.
Here it is, My SQS Role.
And I'm going to copy the ARN.
Back in my file here,
I'm going to add the role ARN in here. So I'm going to paste it over the top.
So now I have the complete command.
The first command we need to run is this zip function.zip index.js command.
So this is going to take our index.js and zip it up as function.zip.
Now you need to be in the event source mapping folder
in the course download.
So you should have unzipped this to your computer somewhere. Mine's in users,
Neal, documents. Yours will be
in a different location on your computer.
But then you'll be in the code AWS Lambda EventSource mapping.
Now in this directory we have this index.js.
If I actually just open this with cat, what you'll see
is it's simply the Lambda function code.
So what I need to do now is just create my function.zip.
If I run the command ls again, we now have our function.zip file.
So coming back, we can now copy this entire command to create our function.
I'm going to paste this in, I need to enter my profile information
and let's hit enter.
So we can see that we have a function that is being created
and the status is creating.
So let's quit out of there, and let's go to the console and see if it's there.
So in the Lambda console, I clicked on refresh and I now have my EventSource
SQS function.
So the next thing we're going to do is create the event source mapping.
We need to go back to Amazon SQS,
copy the ARN for our queue,
and then back in our file here,
I need to add that onto the end here.
So let's have a look at what this command does.
Here, we're going to create an EventSource mapping Using AWS Lambda.
We supply the name of our function,
the batch size is going to be 10, so it can look for up to
10 events at the time.
And the EventSource ARN is going to be the ARN of our queue.
Now, I also need to put that into the next command here.
So let's just paste that in there, so that's ready.
So let's just copy this first command
to create our EventSource mapping.
So let's paste that in, and I've cleared my screen to make things a bit neater.
I'll put in my profile information
and let's hit enter.
And we can see that it's being created.
Now note that there's a UUID here.
So that's an identifier for the EventSource mapping.
Let's quit out of here.
And back in our file, let's copy this second command
and this will list the EventSource mappings.
And there we go again,
we see the same information. So you can recall this information whenever you need to.
Now if at some point you need to delete your EventSource mapping,
you can do so here. So you can use this command,
AWS Lambda delete EventSource mapping.
And that's where you would use that UUID.
So coming back to our diagram here,
what we've done is we've created the Lambda function from the command line.
We've also created the EventSource mapping for SQS.
So the last thing to do is to add a message and see what happens.
So back in SQS, I'm going to click on send and receive messages
and here we can simply send a message.
And let's say, Hello from Lambda and click on send message.
So now let's go back to our Lambda function
and let's choose the function name here.
Go to monitor and then view logs in CloudWatch logs.
In here, we've got a log stream
and we can find our event.
So we have the start, we have the end
and in the middle here, you'll see the actual message Hello from Lambda.
So that's what we typed into SQS.
So we've submitted a message straight to the SQS queue,
Lambda has then polled the queue.
It's then executed the information that it found in the
message in the queue and then based on the code,
it's then written that to CloudWatch logs.
So that's it for this lesson. Now what I do want to do, I'm just going to come in,
I don't need this particular queue anymore.
So what I'll do, is I'll just delete my queue.
It's very simple and you just need to type delete and that's gone.
The Lambda function itself can always be cleaned up,
but it's not going to cost you anything,
so it's okay to leave it there if you want to do some more testing.