In this hands-on lesson we're going to
practice with versions and aliases in AWS Lambda.
Back in the Lambda console, I'm going to create a new function
and I'm going to author from scratch,
give it a function name, I'm going to call it myversiontest.
Node JS 16 is fine.
And I'm going to leave it to create its own execution role.
So let's create this function.
The function is created and in the code source here we can
see that we have that standard Hello from Lambda message.
Now I'm going to override this and I'm gonna put publish to Prod.
And let's click on deploy.
So what we've done here is we've simply saved the code and this is the latest.
Remember this is the code that you can modify at any time.
But once we've saved that code we might want to publish a version.
Now note that at this point in time the function ARN does not have a version number
and that's because we're on the latest.
So what we can do is go to actions,
publish a new version,
I'm going to call this V1.
And click on publish.
So now we have :1 on the end of the function ARN. So that indicates
that we're looking at a version.
You'll notice at the top of the console, we now
get in the functions myversiontest, version1.
So we're actually looking at version1.
And that means if we go to code
we won't be able to modify anything.
So, I can't actually type in there.
So we now have our version1 of our function and that says publish to prod.
If I go back up a level
and on the code editor,
I'm just going to save. So this is the latest version, remember.
So let's put this is latest.
And I'm going to deploy.
So now we have our main function code, the latest,
the one that we can modify, which says this is latest
and we have version1
under versions here.
And that one under code will say published to Prod.
So let's now go to our command line and invoke our function.
So we're going to run these commands, these two commands first.
We're going to run AWS Lambda invoke, give it the function name
and we're going to append :\dollar latest to execute the latest version of the code.
So that's the changeable version.
And then we're going to invoke the version1.
So I'm going to copy this command to my clipboard,
and on the command line I'm going to run this code.
So that returned a 200, which is good.
And let's have a look in the response file.
And it says this is latest. So that is the latest version of the code.
The next command we'll invoke version1 of our code.
So let's copy this to our clipboards
and back on the command line, I paste that one in.
And again we get a 200 code and let's go back and have a look at that
information and this time it says published to Prod.
So that worked exactly as expected.
So if we want to now, we can always execute the
latest version of the code or the versions that we've published.
Back in the console, I'm gonna go back up to the main
latest version of the code
and I'm going to change this to say this is
a new feature.
Let's click on deploy.
And this one is going to be then published as version two.
So I'll give this a V2 as a description.
Click on publish.
And we now see that we have
the function, myversiontest: 2. So that's the second published version.
Now what I want to do is actually create an alias.
Let's come back up a level here,
click on actions,
create alias.
I'm going to give it a name.
I'll simply call it Myapp.
I'm not going to put a description, don't need to
But what I will choose is version1. So that's the production version of my code.
And let's say I also want to send some traffic to version two.
Now of course if you're publishing a new feature,
you might send a few percent across to
the new version of the code so you can test.
For the purposes of this demonstration, I'm going to send 50%.
So we should see an even number of responses from version1 and from version2.
Let's click on save.
And we now have another function ARN.
This one has myapp after the colon at the end.
Back in the file, we have this simple invocation command
and this time we just give it the function name :myapp to indicate the alias.
And on the command line, I'm going to run the command
and we can see executed version2. So if we come back
and run cat response, we can see this is a new feature.
If I run the command again,
it's again two. So let's run it quickly twice in a row,
three times in a row. Okay, there we go. Now we got executed version1.
So this time we should get published to PROD.
So now we're cycling, it doesn't seem to be quite even but if you are sending a lot
of invocation requests in a short period of time it should pretty much be 50% to each.
So here we are using our alias
and were able to send traffic to two
different versions.
Until we've tested our feature completely
and then we can send all the traffic to the new version of the code.
And remember that the alias never needs to change.
So you can always update the configuration of the alias and where it points to.
You never need to change the alias.
If that's embedded in your application code that's okay.
It saves you from having to go and update your application.
And that's it for this lesson. I'll see you the next one.