Hi guys. In this lesson, we're going to go over Lambda
deployment packages and specifying environment variables.
So starting off with deployment packages.
The Lambda functions code
consists of scripts or compile programs and also the dependencies.
A deployment package is then used to deploy the function code to AWS Lambda.
Now, there are two types of deployment package. We've got container images
and we've got .zip file archives. Obviously container images
is if you're running some kind of container on Lambda.
Otherwise all your code is going to go in a .zip file archive.
So let's look at the container images.
A container image will include the base operating system, the runtime,
and the Lambda extensions.
Also the application code and it's dependencies.
Container images are uploaded to the Amazon Elastic Container Registry, ECR.
The image is then deployed to the Lambda function.
Moving on to the .zip archives.
So this is what you're commonly going to use for all other application types.
This includes your application code and dependencies.
And the deployment packages uploaded from S3
or directly from your local machine.
Now there are some limits to the size of zip
archives and it's worth knowing these for the exam.
Firstly, there's a 50 megabyte limit for the zipped for direct upload.
So when you zip them and you're directly
uploading them, it cannot be more than 50 megabytes.
250 MB is the largest unzipped.
And three megabytes if you're using the console editor.
So for anything larger than three megabytes,
you can't go in and directly add your code into the console editor,
you must zip it up and upload it.
Now, you can also deploy your Lambda function through CloudFormation.
The resource that you use is AWS::Lambda::Function.
And that will create the Lambda function for you.
The zip file must be stored in Amazon S3.
And the S3 bucket must be in
the same region where you're running CloudFormation,
so watch out for that in exam questions.
If you're using CloudFormation
in let's say, the US East region and your bucket is in the US West region,
then you can't have your code in that bucket and use it to create a Lambda function
in US East.
You also need a CloudFormation template file.
You can set the package type to image for container images
or zip If it's a .zip archive.
Next, we have something called Lambda layers.
You can configure your Lambda function to pull in additional
code and content in the form of a layer.
A layer is a zip archive that contains the libraries
that you're using, a custom runtime or some other dependencies.
This means you can use other libraries within your
function without actually including them in your deployment package.
A function can use up to five layers at a time.
And layers are extracted to the /opt directory
in the function execution environment.
Each runtime will look for the libraries in a different
location under /opt depending what language you're actually using.
If you want to add layers to your function,
you can use the update function configuration command.
The following example would add two layers,
one from the same account as the function and then one from a different account.
So you can see we're using the update
function configuration with the AWS Lambda CLI command,
and then we're specifying the layers here.
And we've got two different layers specified in the JSON
and each of them has a different account number. So these are in different accounts.
And we're specifying the name of the layer here.
So let's have a look at some examples.
The following example will set two environment
variables on a function named My Function.
So we can see here that we're specifying to update a function configuration,
we give it the name.
We then specify --environment,
and then we've got variables, and then we've got two
different variables here and both are a key value pair.
So we've got bucket equals my bucket and then key equals file.
If you then view the function configuration
by running the get function configuration command, this is what you would see.
And so now you can see that the environment variables are specified,
bucket equals my bucket, key is file.text.
Now lastly, there are some limits that are worth understanding for the exam.
Firstly, the memory allocation, it goes up in increments of one megabyte,
starting at 128 megabytes up to 10,240 megabytes.
The execution time out is 900 seconds, that's 15 minutes.
So that's really important to understand.
If you actually need to run some kind of long running code,
then if it's going to run longer than 15 minutes, Lambda is not the answer.
You would need to split the processing into separate executions
or you would need to run it on some other compute platform,
like a Docker container on ECS or Amazon EC2.
The maximum size of environment variables is four kilobytes
for all of the functions environment variables.
You get up to five layers.
Burst concurrency is 500 to 3,000. That depends on the AWS region.
For the invocation, payload, the payload for synchronous invocation is a maximum
of 6 MB or for asynchronous, it's 256 KB.
The deployment package, the .zip archive. We've seen this earlier on
50 megabytes for zipped when direct uploading
and 254 unzipped and three megabytes for the console.
The container, image code package size can't be bigger than 10 GB
and the /temp directory storage is again in one megabyte increments,
starting at 512 in this case going up to 10,240.
So definitely worth understanding some of those for the exam.