Hi guys. In this hands on lesson,
I'm going to show you how we can use environment variables with AWS Lambda.
And we're going to see an insecure way of doing it and then
a more secure way of actually storing that information in an encrypted format.
So I have this file in the course downloads.
So again we're in the AWS Lambda directory
and it's Lambda-environ-test.py.
So you'll find this python code.
And what this python code is going to do
is we're going to supply some information in environment variables and the
environment variable names will be DB_HOST USER and PASS.
And so then it's going to print to the screen and it's going to show us
that we're connected with whatever the values
are associated with each of these variables.
So if that doesn't make sense don't worry, it will in a moment.
Let's copy this information to our clipboards and go to Lambda.
In the Lambda console, I'm going to create a function.
I'm going to call it My Environ Test
and I'm going to change to let's just use the most
recent version of python.
And the execution role is fine, I'll leave that to create an execution role for me.
And then let's create this function.
Now that the function has been created,
what we're gonna do is we're going to delete all this code
and we're going to paste in that code which we just copied
and click on deploy.
Now, what we want to do is add in our environment variables.
To do that, we go to configuration
and just scroll down a little way and on the left hand side on these tabs,
you'll find environment variables
and then click on edit.
So we're going to click on add
and the first one will be DB_HOST.
And for the value, I'm going to add my fake database.
The next one is going to be DB_USER,
and for the value, I'm going to enter Neal.
And then lastly, the third one will be DB_PASS
and I'm going to give it a fake password.
Now, it is important that the keys are correct. So they have to be DB_HOST,
DB_USER, and DB_PASS because
remember that was actually specified in our code.
The actual values can be anything, you can put your name in there,
any password you want.
This is just for test purposes so it doesn't matter.
And of course we don't have a database for this test but if
we did this would be the string for connectivity to the database.
So let's just save the environment variables.
Now if we go to test,
and I'm just going to call this a Test Event T1.
Click on save.
Let's run the test.
It's successful.
Let's look at the details and it's obviously just a simple Hello From Lambda.
But if we scroll down to the log output, what we can see is we get this message.
So it says connected to my fake database as
Neal with, and then it's got the password here
in plain text for anyone to see who can execute this function.
But also if we go to monitor and go to CloudWatch logs,
of course, it's going to be recorded here as well.
So if we go into this log stream
and we can see that information.
So this would not be good.
Of course, you might not have code to actually write this into CloudWatch logs
but you get the idea this information could be seen some way or another.
All it takes is some kind of error or an oversight and this information gets leaked.
So what we want to do is we want to enable encryption
for this information.
We're going to use a KMS key, that's a Key Management Service key.
So that's going to be the key that's used for encryption.
On the KMS dashboard here, I'm going to click on create key.
I'm going to accept the defaults for symmetric.
And the usage will be to encrypt and decrypt information.
I'll give it a name.
I'm simply gonna call mine My Environ Test.
For the administrators, I will be the administrator.
So that gives me full permissions.
And if I click on next,
I might want to use this key myself but more specifically for this exercise,
we need to allow the role from the function to be able to use the key.
So what we need to know is the role name for our function.
So my function is called my environ test.
So let's have a look and see if we can find a role, it shouldn't be far away.
So I have a few rolls here that we can see that have been created for our services.
And this is the one, my environ test role.
So I select that, click on next,
and then we can click on finish. And you can actually see the full policy here.
The permissions that are applied for key administration,
and then usage of the key as well.
So I'm happy with that. Let's click on finish.
So we now have a key that we can use.
Now when you finish with this exercise you might want to remove these keys.
There is a small charge, maybe a dollar a month.
What you can do with your key once you've finished
is choose the key. I'm not using this particular one.
Go to schedule key deletion
and you can bring this down to seven days.
So they make sure that you don't accidentally delete a key.
They give you a waiting period.
So what I want to do is confirm, schedule deletion, and that key will be deleted.
So make sure that the key that you are using is enabled
and in our case we can now go back to our Lambda function.
Let's go to configuration
and click edit next to environment variables.
Expand encryption configuration.
We're going to enable helpers for encryption in transit.
We're going to use a customer master key, that is what we just created.
And then let's choose the key that we just created. Mine is called My Environ Test.
Then we need to enable the encryption for our specific variables.
So I'm just going to encrypt the environment variable for my password.
I'm going to choose the key. So the key is already chosen.
If it's not there, just choose it from the drop down box.
And there is some code here that we need. So you might want to copy this code.
I've actually got it in my clipboard, but this is useful code because it
gives us the extra code that we need for decrypting the environment variable.
So I'm going to choose encrypt.
I can save.
And let's go back and we need to make some code updates.
So I've made another copy of my code in the file here.
This will always be ready for you when you open this file.
So always make sure that for the first part of the exercise you just use the code above
and then we've got this code here.
In fact, I'll put a little line break in here just to make it clear.
So what's changed in the code?
Well we've imported the boto3 module and the b64decode.
And then you can see that we've added on
this encryption and decryption using the boto3 library.
It takes in the cipher text
and then it's able to decode into plain text. And we'll see how
we can both see the encrypted value and the decrypted value soon.
So what I need to do is simply copy all of this code
and let's go back to our function. So back on the function. Let's go to code.
We need to remove this execution result. We can delete everything here,
paste this in, click on deploy.
And then let's run a test.
And in the execution result, we can see the response
here saying connected to my fake database as Neal With,
and then the password is actually fully encrypted.
So that information is no longer being sent in plain text.
Of course, if we go over to CloudWatch logs,
we'll be able to see exactly the same thing.
So let's go into the latest stream here,
and we can see that the encrypted value is stored in CloudWatch logs.
Now you might also want to see that you can decrypt that information.
So let's go to underneath the print command here, put in a new line
and then we're gonna put in print decrypted.
Now, how can we prove that we are able to actually decrypt that information?
Well, what I'm gonna do is just in the editor here,
under where it says print,
I'm going to put in a new line
and I'm also going to print but this time I'm going to type in decrypt it.
And simply deploy.
And then let's go and test.
So this time in the execution result, we see the encrypted value.
But then also on this new line here we see the decrypted value as well.
So we're able to decrypt that information when we need to.
So that's it for this lesson.
Don't forget to go back and we have finished up with our KMS key.
So you can always disable key usage, and that means it's no longer usable.
And then of course as I showed you before, you can then schedule for key deletion.
So I'm gonna use seven days, confirm, and that one is gone as well.
So I hope you enjoyed that. I will see you in the next lesson.