In this hands-on lesson, we're going to create a Lambda function
and a destination for Amazon SQS
such that when we invoke the function, it's going to add messages to the queue.
Now, in the course download, you're going to find some code.
We've got the code directory AWS Lambda and then destinations and dlq.md.
So in here you're going to find some code.
We're going to copy this function
code to our clipboards and then create a function.
So back in Lambda, I'm going to create a new function. I'll give this one a name.
I'm going to leave it as Node.js
and just create the function.
Then on the code directory, let's remove all of this code,
paste our code in and click on deploy to save those changes.
This code is actually going to provide different output
depending on whether the invocation is a successful or failure.
And that depends on information we provide in the payload.
So you can see we've got console log success or console log failure.
The next thing we need to do is create an SQS queue.
So let's go to SQS, create a queue.
I'll just call it My Test Queue.
Leave all the defaults, scroll down and then simply create the queue.
So now we have our queue.
We then need to create our destination.
So back in Lambda,
if you just scroll up, you'll see
the options here to add triggers to trigger Lambda
or destinations so that when we invoke our function
information goes to the destination.
Under destination, we can choose asynchronous or streaming vocation,
we're going to leave it on asynchronous.
Then we have the conditions. So is it a success event or a failure event?
So let's leave it on failure for now.
Choose SQS queue and then choose our test queue.
Now is this going to work?
Well actually we don't even have to click save anymore.
It's straightaway before we even get there
tells us that our execution role doesn't have permission
to send results to the destination.
But the great thing is we no longer actually have to do this ourselves.
AWS will attempt to add those permissions for us.
So let's simply click save.
And that's our failure destination.
So you can see now under destinations, we have our asynchronous invocation.
If we go back to permissions,
let's just check that our role has the relevant permissions. So we can see
some information here but I like to go and actually look at it in IAM.
So here we can now see that we do have an additional policy.
So the Lambda basic execution was created when we created the Lambda function
and this one was added by Lambda.
So this is the SQS queue destination execution role.
So that gives us the permissions to SQS.
So coming back to Lambda,
I also want to go back to destinations
and we're going to add another destination.
So you can do it up here or you can do it here.
So this time it's going to be the on success destination.
We're going to choose our SQS queue again.
And this time there's no error because we already have the permissions.
So now we have these two
destinations for asynchronous invocation.
So next we need to run the invocation command.
So the first one generates a success message
and the second one here a failure message.
And it does so because we add this information into the payload.
So success true or success false
to actually simulate a successful or unsuccessful invocation of our function.
Now we need to base 64encode that information.
I already used the same utility we used earlier on in this section.
So that information is already here. You can just copy
and paste this command straight into your CLI.
So back on the CLI, I'm going to paste that in, give my profile information,
and hit enter.
We get a status code 202, which is a success for asynchronous invocation.
So that's good.
And if we go to the response information, let's see if there's any output.
And of course, there isn't any output because it's asynchronous.
Remember only the synchronous invocation provided the output into the response JSON.
But what we really need to check is the SQS queue.
So back in the console, let's go to SQS,
click on send and receive messages,
just scroll down and then poll for messages.
And here we have a message.
If I click on view details, we can see some information.
And here we can see that message, where it says success true.
So that was the first test that was a simulation of a successful invocation.
So let's just close that one
and let's go back and simulate an unsuccessful invocation.
So now I simply need to copy this second command which already has success false
in the payload here as a base 64encoded value.
So let's run this command.
Again, we get a 202, which is good.
So back in SQS, I'm polling for messages.
And it hasn't come through yet. This is my original message.
So I'm waiting for the new one to come through.
Now, don't worry if that takes a couple of minutes with the failure simulation
it typically takes a little bit longer.
Okay, that took a few minutes actually.
And you can see that we now have our message here.
So I'm going to select that message, click on view details
and this time we get a different message, we can see it's the failure
and you can see the success equals false I am failing message.
So that was the simulation of a failure event.
Now, as you can see each time we poll for messages it actually receives the message.
So you can see the received count has gone right up for this message here.
And that's because I kept polling and each time you do that,
it is actually executing some API actions to
check the queue and receive those messages.
So anyway, that's good.
That has worked and we've done our test of using a destination.
And what we're going to do now is I'm just going to actually remove these
and we're going to set up a dead letter queue.
So let's remove these two asynchronous invocations and we're going
to go down to where it says asynchronous invocation here.
Click on edit,
And we're going to add our SQS queue as a dead letter queue.
So this means that messages that are not successfully processed gets sent to the
dead letter queue so that we can then check them later on.
And we have the maximum number of times to retry when the function returns an error.
So let's save.
We now have
our dead letter queue configured.
And let's go back and run the same command we just ran before.
So I'm going to rerun this command.
Let's just run it a couple of times.
And now that should generate some messages.
So back in our queue we can poll again
and again this could take a few minutes.
But then we should start seeing some new messages come in.
To clean things up, I'm just going to delete these existing messages
so then I know when the new messages come through.
So it's been a few minutes and I now have my messages coming through.
Let's click on one of these.
And we can see that this time the body does not have much information in it.
So you've got obviously write your code in a certain way if you want
to make sure that you have code that's useful for troubleshooting purposes in here.
Otherwise, you might just get something like this payload information here.
But that's how a destination works and DLQ.
So I'm happy with that. I've finished with this particular lesson.
And so what I'm going to do is just delete my queue
and that will take all of the information with it, such as the messages.
And that's it for this lesson. I will see you in the next one.