There are a couple of options for how we can control
the concurrency with our Lambda function.
So you remember from earlier on in this section, we looked at function invocation.
And what happens is, when a function is executed,
Lambda can invoke more instances of that function.
And so they're all running in parallel if they need to
so that you can process multiple events at the same time.
Additional functions are initialized up to the burst or the account limit.
Now there are some quotas
and they are region specific and I'm showing those on the screen for you here.
If the concurrency limit is exceeded,
then throttling will occur and you get this rate exceeded error
and a 429 too many requests exception.
So that often comes up in exam questions and so you'll know that
if you see that what's happened is the concurrency limit has been exceeded.
Now, how can we control concurrency limits?
Well, firstly, the default concurrency limit per region
is 1000 invocations at any given time.
And the default burst concurrency quota per region is between 500 and 3,000.
And we saw on the previous slide how that's dependent per region.
There's no maximum concurrency limit for Lambda functions,
it really depends on your use case.
So, for example, if you want to apply for an extension and increase in the limit,
they'll ask you some questions about your use case
and they'll determine based on that, what they want to allow you.
To avoid throttling, request limit increases at least two weeks ahead of time.
So if you have an event where you know you're going to need an extra a higher limit,
then make sure you contact AWS ahead of time to arrange that.
Now, there's something called reserved concurrency.
This guarantees a set number of concurrent executions will
be available for a critical function that you're running.
You can reserve up to the unreserved account concurrency value
minus 100 for functions that don't have reserved concurrency.
So we can see here that what we've done
is we've reserved concurrency for a function of 100.
So we've got 100 executions that's decremented our
unreserved account concurrency from 1000 down to 900.
So all other functions will be able to use these 900
And we make sure that we've got a minimum of 100 available for our critical function.
If you want to throttle a function,
you can actually set the reserve concurrency to zero.
So if we specified a zero value here,
then we wouldn't be able to actually process any events with that function.
We also have provision concurrency.
If you specify some configuration for your provision concurrency,
then the function will scale with the same burst behavior
as if you had standard concurrency.
And after it's allocated provisioned concurrency,
serves incoming requests with much lower latency.
And if all provisions currency is in use, the function
will scale up normally to handle any additional requests.
Application auto scaling can also be used with provision concurrency
to provide auto scaling for the amount of
provisioned concurrency that you actually have configured.
So you can specify it here.
And this is what's available in terms of executions.
And we can provision a certain amount to reduce the latency
associated with scaling our function.
And of course, there is a cost associated with this.