In this lesson, we'll explore some of the options for securing our Lambda Functions.
So, let's have a look at the diagram and explore the security options.
So firstly we have a Lambda Function.
And let's say we want to write something to CloudWatch logs,
and store items in a DynamoDB table.
Well, to do that we need an IAM role known as the function execution role.
And this is where we specify the permissions that we're giving
to our Lambda Function.
If we don't have the right permissions, it's going to fail.
Now, we might also have code and environment variables.
Files, deployment packages, and environment variables are encrypted at rest using
a KMS key, so that data is also stored securely.
As you know from the previous lesson, you can also use Secrets Manager to
store things like database connection credentials or
other things that you might need to store securely, any kind of secret.
Now, AWS recommend that you use Secrets Manager
instead of environment variables whenever you can.
So let's say our developer is now connecting to Lambda.
The Lambda API endpoint
only supports TLS connections, so you can't have an unencrypted connection.
Of course we need to ensure that our
code that we're deploying to our Lambda Functions is secure.
And we need to be able to guarantee the integrity of that code.
If somebody wrote some malicious code or they modified the code in certain ways
that could be a real serious issue.
So we can use AWS Signer which is a fully managed code signing service.
It's used to ensure the trust and integrity of the code.
The code is validated against a digital signature.
With Lambda, you can ensure that only trusted code runs in your Lambda Functions.
Signer is used to then create the digitally signed packages for deployment.
The IAM policies are used to enforce that the functions can be created only
if code signing is enabled.
So with all this in place,
if a developer leaves your organization and you're
worried about what they've done with their code,
you can revoke all versions of the signing profile
so the code cannot run.
And watch out for that because it pops up as an exam question.
So now, you're well prepared.