In this lesson,
I'm going to cover the AWS Serverless Application Model known AWS SAM.
The Serverless Application Model gives us a shorthand syntax
to express functions, APIs, databases, and event source mapping.
We can use it to create Lambda functions, API endpoints,
DynamoDB tables and other resources.
Now by shorthand syntax, what we're talking about is we have a much simpler syntax
or much simpler way of expressing what we want to create compared to
say a CloudFormation template.
Now it looks something like this. So here we have a SAM template in YAML.
And what you'll notice at the top here was we got transform AWS serverless
and then this date.
Now make sure you know that because you will be tested on the exam.
It will look for your ability to recognize a SAM template.
So that will tell you that this is a SAM template.
And then for resources, we've got our function called Hello World Function.
The type is a serverless function.
And then we've got properties code URI, so where the code is actually coming from,
the handler, and then the runtime.
So very simple.
So we have our template and we have our application code.
And then we can run some simple commands. Now we've got our S3 bucket.
What we do is we run SAM package, so we're running this
on our local machine where we've got our code and our template file.
After SAM package, we run SAM deploy
and the information gets uploaded to an S3 bucket.
SAM will upload the source files to the bucket
and then initiate CloudFormation for us.
So then CloudFormation will then create a stack
based on our simple SAM template
and deploy that stack.
And you can then use change set to actually
update the stack if you need to make changes.
A SAM template file is a YAML configuration
that represents the architecture of a serverless application
and you use that to declare all
the resources that comprise your serverless application.
They're an extension of CloudFormation templates and typically
much simpler than your average template in CloudFormation.
Any resource that you can declare in a CloudFormation
template can also be declared in a SAM template.
So let's look at the SAM commands in a bit more
detail as they do definitely come up in exam questions.
So firstly we run SAM package.
Here, we specify the template file template.yaml,
the S3 bucket, we've called that dctlabs for my account,
and then the output template file,
we've given that a name and then .yaml on the end.
Next, you run SAM deploy with the template file specified
and the stack name that we want created.
Alternatively you can run
this command. So rather than using SAM package and SAM deploy,
you can use CloudFormation package and CloudFormation deploy.
Now be aware that in the exam both options might come up
and both will help you to achieve the same outcome,
you're still using SAM whichever way you run it because your template file
is configured with that transform AWS serverless.
So firstly we have SAM package then SAM deploy, otherwise
CloudFormation package or cloudformation deploy.
Now, it's key to remember this transform header.
So the transform header will indicate that it's a SAM template.
And we saw that earlier, it's transformed AWS serverless.
There are several resource types.
We've got a Serverless function so we can deploy a Lambda function.
We've got Serverless API, if we want to deploy an API  Gateway API,
and serverless simple template is a DynamoDB table.
And then we've got Serverless application which is
where we're using the serverless application repository.
We can also deploy an HTTP API rather than
a REST API with API gateway by using AWS Serverless HTTP API.
And then lastly we can specify Lambda layers by using AWS serverless layer version.
That's it for this lesson. I'll see you in the next one.