Hi guys. in this lesson,
we're going to use AWS CloudShell to practice with the AWS SAM CLI utility.
Now I've also added a URL to this lesson
where you can actually learn a bit more about AWS SAM.
And you'll see in here there's a getting started guide.
It shows you how to install the SAM CLI on various different operating systems.
Now, I'm using CloudShell because
it is a little bit tricky to show people how to do this
using one operating system because if you're using a different one to me,
then it's going to get a bit complicated.
So there are a few prerequisites and programming frameworks and so on
that you have to have installed before you can actually run SAM.
Hence I'm going to do it in the CloudShell.
But if you want to actually practice
running these commands locally on your machine,
you can actually use Docker and actually run some
AWS utilities and applications locally on your machine like Lambda
and DynamoDB, then you can use the documentation and the tutorials here
to actually do that and it's really worthwhile practice.
So what I'm gonna do is go back over to AWS,
I'm going to click on the CloudShell icon here
and that should launch CloudShell for me.
Now, while that's launching,
let's go and have a look at the commands we're going to run.
So in your course download in the Lambda directory,
you'll find this SAM-CLI-commands.md file.
And there's just a few commands we need to run.
And what it's going to do is it's actually going to deploy a Hello World application
that uses an API Gateway API endpoints and an AWS Lambda function.
So we can deploy all of that with just a few very simple commands.
The first one is this one here, so SAM init.
We provide the runtime.
The dependency manager is PIP,
and then the app template is one of
the templates that AWS provides with the SAM utility,
and that's called Hello World.
And then the actual name of the app will be SAM app.
So all I need to do here is simply copy this entire command.
And my CloudShell is ready so let's paste this command in
and hit enter.
And this will use the permissions assigned to my user account.
And we can see that
what it's done is it's cloned some information from a GitHub repository.
So back in our command here,
what we want to do is we want to change directories suit to SAM app
and then run SAM build and then SAM deploy --guided.
So let's change directory to SAM app.
And that's our directory and in here you can see
that we have these various files and directories.
Next we want to run SAM build
and that ran very quickly.
And it now suggests some commands we can use but we already know what we need to run.
We're gonna use SAM deploy --guided.
Now this is showing the information here at the bottom of my screen.
So what I'm actually gonna do is I'm just going to close out of that,
clear the screen, bring it back up to the top and just run that again.
So it's going to be a bit easier to see.
So the stack name is going to use CloudFormation.
So it provides a stack name which is SAM-dash app, I'm happy with that.
The region, that's okay,
I'm going to leave it as us-east-1. So if you just
hit enter essentially you're accepting
whatever the default is in the square brackets.
So next it's asking me to confirm changes before deploy. That's okay.
I don't need to do that.
SAM needs permission to be able to create roles
to connect to the resources in your template.
Well in this case the default is yes, let's make sure.
And then it says it's going to
preserve the state of previously provisioned resources.
Not really interested. So the default of No.
So the capitalized N means the default is No.
And then it says Hello World function may not have authorization defined.
Is this okay? Well no, it's not. So let's put in a Y.
We do need that.
And then I'm going to accept the defaults.
Accept the default for the SAM configuration file,
the environment
and there we go. So that's now creating this application for us.
And we can see what's actually happening on the screen here in CloudShell.
But I've also opened CloudFormation, so we can see what's going on here
or we can head over to CloudFormation. We've got this create in progress.
And if you go to the events tab here, you're going to see
the various components of our application being created.
Back in CloudShell,
I can now see a message at the bottom of
my screen that says that it has completed successfully.
So if I refresh back in CloudFormation, it's all complete.
And if I go to outputs, we now have the Hello World API.
So we can actually see the API execution URL here.
And if I run that it's simply going to come back with Hello World.
So what has been created?
Let's go and have a look at a couple of the resources that have been created.
So we've got API Gateway.
That's the API that's been created and AWS Lambda.
Now, those are the main two resources.
So if I go to API Gateway, we can see that an API has been created.
If I go into that API,
We can see that the resources here, there's the /Hello and GET.
And that has an integration with Lambda.
Now you'll learn a lot more about API Gateway a bit later on in the course.
But in this case what's happening is the information we
supply in our API request gets proxied straight through the Lambda.
And we can see our function.
And our function is actually part of an application so we can click
on this link here and it's going to take us to the application.
So note that you have functions.
We've got several functions now.
But functions can also be part of an
application which then has additional configuration information,
such as with this one, it shows the API endpoint.
And you can also configure your deployments using code pipeline tools as well.
So that was all created very simply through the AWS SAM CLI utility.
We've finished with the lesson now.
So what I can do is simply come back into CloudFormation and delete my stack,
and that should delete all of the components of the application we just created.