Hi guys and welcome to the exam cram. For lambda and AWS SAm.
With serverless, there are no instances to manage,
you don't need to provision hardware and
there's no management of operating systems or software
capacity provisioning and patching is handled automatically for you.
It also provides automatic scaling and high availability
and can be very cheap.
Lambda executes code only where needed and scales automatically.
You pay only for the compute time you actually consume
with lambda. There's different types of invocation.
We have synchronous invocation using the cli the SDK
and a variety of services including api gateway.
In this case you wait for the function to process the event and return a response
error handling happens, client side
re tries exponential back off and more.
We then have a synchronous in vocation.
This is where you have S three s and s cloudwatch events and other services.
A synchronously invoking your function.
In that case the event is queued for
processing and a response is returned immediately.
Lambda will retry up to three times
and processing must be item potent.
Lastly we have event source mapping.
These are using sqs
kinesis data streams and dynamodb streams.
Lambda will do the polling in this case. So it's polling. The source
records are processed in order
Except for with sqs standard,
you can use lambda to process event notifications from S three
S free can send an event to a lambda function when an object is created or deleted.
S three invokes your function.
A synchronously with an event that contains details about the object
versioning means you can have multiple versions of your function.
You can use versions to manage the deployment of your
lambda functions
you work on dollar latest. That's the latest version of the code. And it's mutable.
That means you can change it.
When you're ready to publish a lambda function,
you create a version and they are numbered.
Each version will have its own R N.
Lambda aliases are pointers to a specific lambda version
using an alias.
You can invoke a function without having to know which version of the function
is actually being referenced.
And aliases are also mutable so you can change them.
A deployment package is used to deploy function code to lambda.
Lambda supports two types of deployment packages,
container, images and dot zip file archives.
A zip file archive includes your application code and its dependencies.
The deployment package is uploaded from Amazon S three or your computer
and there are limits to the size of ZIP Archives.
50 MB zipped for direct upload to 50
unzipped and free megabytes for the console editor.
You can configure your lambda function to pull in
additional code and content in the form of layers,
layers of zip archive that contains libraries,
a custom runtime or other dependencies
to add layers to your function. Use the update function, configuration command,
environment variables can be used to adjust
your functions behavior without updating the code.
An environment variable is a pair of strings that
is stored in a functions version specific configuration.
Environment variables are defined on the unpublished version of a function
and when they publish a version,
the environment variables are locked for that version.
The default concurrency limit per aws region is 1000 invocations
at any given time.
There's no maximum concurrency limit for λ functions.
It really just depends on your use case.
Reserve, concurrency guarantees.
A set number of concurrent executions will be available for a critical function
when provision,
concurrency is allocated the function scales with the same burst behavior
as standard concurrency.
Lambda sends metrics to cloudwatch for performance monitoring
and execution logs are stored in cloudwatch logs.
The lambda function execution role always must have permissions
to write to cloudwatch logs or to use any other service.
You can use x ray to visualize the components of your application.
You can connect your functions to a VPc as well.
And in that case you must connect to a private subnets with
a nat gateway for internet access because there's no public I P.
Be careful with DNS resolution of public host names as it can add to function.
Running time and that means cost
to connect to a VPc.
Your functions execution role must have the permissions
to create the network interface in the VPc.
AWS Signer is a fully managed code signing service.
It's used to ensure the trust and integrity of code
and code is validated against a digital signature
with lambda. You can ensure only trusted. Code runs in lambda functions when using
AWS Signer.
Some best practices for writing function code include
separate the lambda handler from your core logic.
Take advantage of execution environment reused to
improve the performance of your function.
Use a keep alive directive to maintain persistent connections.
Use environment variables to pass operational parameters to your function,
control the dependencies in your functions, deployment package,
minimize your deployment package size to its runtime necessities
and lastly avoid using recursive code
in your function.
That's it for this exam, cram see you in the next lesson.