Amazon CodeGuru is one of those services that may come up in
the odd exam question or you might not see it at all.
If it does come up, you probably only need to know the fundamentals.
It's unlikely you'll be tested on the implementation.
So let's go over the basics of CodeGuru.
So what is it?
Well, it's a service that provides intelligent
recommendations for improving application performance,
efficiency, and the quality of your code.
It's made up of two services.
The first is CodeGuru Reviewer and the second is CodeGuru Profiler.
So let's start off going over Reviewer.
This review's your Java and Python code
and offers suggestions for improving your code quality.
Suggestions are based on best practices.
It finds complex issues such as resource leak and security analysis issues.
It also integrates with AWS Secrets Manager
so that you can use a secret detector that finds unprotected secrets in your code.
So if you add something that should be secret into your source code,
then it can identify that and hopefully help you to close a potential security hole.
It supports the following source providers. So CodeCommit, Bitbucket, GitHub,
GitHub Enterprise Cloud, GitHub Enterprise Server, and Amazon S3.
Next we have CodeGuru Profiler.
What this service does is it collects
runtime performance data from your live applications
and then provides recommendations that you can
use to fine tune application performance.
CodeGuru profiler provides various visualizations to help you identify
things such as what code is running on your CPU, how much time is consumed,
ways to reduce your CPU utilization.
Profiling also includes latency and CPU utilization issues in your application
and offers recommendations for ways you can reduce
your infrastructure costs of running your application.
It will also identify application performance issues and help you
understand your applications heap utilization over time.
So those are the basics. I doubt you'll need to know any more than that.
So that's it for this lesson. I'll see you in the next one.