In this hands-on lesson,
we're going to add a build stage and an approval stage to our CodePipeline.
So you've seen this diagram before in the theory lesson.
What we're going to do is add the buildspec.yml file to codecommit.
And we're also going to modify the index.dot html
so we have a different message on our Elastic Beanstalk Application.
We're then going to add a stage to the pipeline using AWS CodeBuild.
CodeBuild is going to test for the existence of a specific file.
So it's going to look for that file and if it's there then the test passes
and if it's not there, then it's going to fail.
We'll also then have the approval stage so that an approver can say, yep, okay,
the test has passed and I'm happy to now push these changes through
to the application.
Now, there's a couple of files that we're going to use.
The first one is the buildspec.yml.
So this file has various phases in it.
So you can see we have install and then we can run commands,
prebuild and then we can run commands then build and our build commands
and then post build and our post-build commands.
Now we talked about these a bit more in the theory
and they're also mentioned a lot more in our cheat sheets.
Now, most of these commands are simply echo statements.
The one which we've added here that's the actual test for this particular exercise
is to find production.txt.
So if production.txt is a file that exists in the source code,
then this test will pass.
If it doesn't exist then the test will fail.
Now I've then opened up my index.html.
So of course the build spec is in the code download in code developer tools,
but the index.html I've actually opened in my repository.
So if you go to your developer labs repository and open index.html.
And all we're going to do is scroll down to where we have
the congratulations message.
And I'm going to change this to say production, deployment complete.
And I'm going to save that file.
So I've saved that file in my repository.
And I'm also going to go and copy this file.
So copy your file from code developer tools, buildspec.yml
into your developer tools repository.
So back on the command line here, if I run get status,
we should now have two changes. One is we've modified our index.html
and the other is that we have an untracked file which is buildspec.yml.
So we're not going to change anything there.
We're going to leave those as they are.
And we're going to go and configure our stages.
So let's go back to the console.
We're going to create our codebuild project and then add the stages to our pipeline.
Back in the console I'm going to choose build.
And choose build projects.
So now we're working with AWS CodeBuild. Let's create a project.
Again, I'm just going to call this Developer Labs just to make things easy.
Scroll down. We don't need to make any changes up here.
We're just going to choose the source provider as codecommit.
The repository is developer labs.
The branch is going to be master.
Scroll down again.
Now it's actually going to use an image in the background.
It uses a container and you can choose the operating system.
I'll choose Ubuntu. Choose standard.
And then I'm going to choose the latest image.
Then we have new service role. It's going to create a role for us.
Now we have our buildspec.yml.
So it's going to say use a buildspec file here.
As long as we have that in the directory already,
we don't need to specify the buildspec name.
We only do that if we have a different name for our buildspec file.
So I can leave that as it is.
We're not going to add any artifacts. I don't need to log at this stage.
So I'm just going to create my build project.
So my build project is being created.
Now, I'm going to go down to pipeline,
choose pipelines,
developer labs,
and I'm going to click on edit.
And now we can add a stage. So I'm going to add a stage between the source
and the deployment.
So let's add stage. I'm going to call this test.
Click on add action group.
The action name is going to be Test again.
For action provider, we're going to choose AWS CodeBuild.
Choose source artifact for the input artifacts.
And then for project name it's Developer Labs.
And we don't need to change anything else.
So let's choose done.
We'll now create our approval stage underneath our test stage.
I'll simply call this Approval.
Add the stage.
Click on add action group.
Call this approval again.
Under action provider, we choose manual approval.
And all of the other options here are optional. We're not going to fill those in.
Let's just choose done.
And that's it. We now have our test stage using AWS CodeBuild
and our approval stage using a manual approval process.
So going back to the top, we can click on save.
And save again.
So now let's go back to the command line and we're
actually going to push the changes we made to our repository.
So back on the command line, what we want to do is run git add -a, git commit,
with the message added buildspec.
And then I'm going to run git push.
So I'm just pushing those changes up.
Now, we have not added our production.txt file.
That does not exist. If I just clear the screen,
run ls, we can see we do not have production.txt.
So our testing stage using CodeBuild should fail because our buildspec.yml file
is actually looking for the production.txt file.
Back in the CodePipeline, we can see that the source code was updated.
We can now see that the testing stage is in progress.
And it shouldn't take too long. We should find that that fails very quickly.
And now we can see that that did indeed fail.
So let's go back and we're going to add the production.txt file,
push that up to our repository and then we should
find that our build stage does pass the test.
So back on the command line, I'm going to create the file using touch.
Of course if you're using Windows just go in
to the directory and create a production.txt file.
Then I'm going to add this to our repository.
I'm going to commit it to our repository.
And then I'm actually going to push that up to our repository.
So that's been pushed to AWS CodeCommit.
Let's go back to our pipeline and see if our build stage succeeds.
Back in our pipeline,
we can see that the build stage is currently running, it's in progress.
So let's see what happens.
And there it is. We can see that our build stage has succeeded.
So the test did pass this time.
And now the pipeline is waiting for the approval.
So I'm going to come in here and just put yes
and click on approve.
And that's going to now push the changes through to Elastic Beanstalk.
So let's go and see what's happening in Beanstalk.
And back in Beanstalk we can see that the environment is being updated.
And that's completed really quickly.
So let's click on the hyperlink again.
And this time we can see the message, production deployment complete.
And we know
that our production deployment code did get pushed through to Elastic Beanstalk.
That's it for this lesson.
And we have actually finished with this Elastic Beanstalk application now.
So feel free to go back and terminate your Elastic Beanstalk Environment.
And once you've done that, we're all done for this lesson,
I'll see you in the next one.