Hi guys and welcome back to the part four of the ec.
S labs that we started in the previous section.
So make sure that you've done part one,
Part two and part three and that you have all of the resources we created running
and then we can continue in this lesson.
So what we've done so far is we created an elastic container registry repository.
We uploaded an image of engine X to that repository.
We then created a task definition that referenced the
image in the repository and an application load balancer.
And then we created a Fargate cluster and a service and that service
used the task definition that pointed to the image in the repository.
So all of that should be running now you should have an
application load balancer that if you connect to the DNS name,
it should connect you to an engine X web page.
So in this lesson we're going to create a
code deploy application and a pipeline in codepipeline.
We'll also have a codecommit repository as well.
So our configuration so far looks something like this
with the Fargate cluster, the CS service,
the CCR registry.
The task definition that references the image and we've got an A L B with a primary
target group and listener which is poured 80 and
target group one at this point in time.
And then we've got 80 80 which is our secondary test listener.
We have target group too
And we've got a task running in Target Group one at this point in time.
So now we're going to create the codecommit repository.
It's gonna have these two files. The aspect dot Yeah mo
And the task def dot Jason.
Then we're going to create a codepipeline so that it uses
the codecommit repository
and pushes the code through the pipeline to code deploy.
Codedeploy is going to speak to e c s and the A L B
and it will swap the listener
to the target group too. So this is the blue green deployment.
So we'll see that in action in a moment.
Now, back in our instructions were now here in part four. There's quite a lot to do.
Lots of instructions in here and I'm going to do
all this through the console in the command line.
So the first thing to do is create a codecommit repository called
Lab. So let's copy that to our clipboards
and go over to codecommit.
So here we are in codecommit,
I'm going to create a new repository, give it the name
and then just create,
we now want to clone the repository. So I'm going to copy
the Git clone command and go back to a command line
and I'm just going to paste that in here.
So it's going to clone into e CS lab. It is an empty repository.
That's okay if I change into pcs lab here, we are in the Git Master.
Next we want to edit the task def dot Jason file.
So that file is this one here in the code directory. Tcs Task def dot Jason.
And what we need to do, remember this is actually using the task execution role A R N
and it has an engine. X. Image. Okay.
So what we're going to do now is we're going to update the image name to image one.
This is a placeholder
that's going to be updated by codedeploy.
So we literally just come in
and replace
the image name with
image underscore name with the with the arrows either side to make sure
it's exactly like this with the quotation marks either side as well.
We're then going to save a copy of this
in our repository.
So the way we're going to do that, I'm gonna just go to the command line
and what I'm gonna do is copy
the file.
Task F dot Jason
into this folder.
So now we've got task def dot Jason in the folder so you can do that through the,
you know, through your file Explorer, however you want to do it.
But just copy that fall into your Git Master branch like this.
There's also a far called app spec dot Yamil.
So again, that will be in your code pcs directory. Now don't change anything here.
The task definition is again a placeholder and
that will be updated when the pipeline runs.
So we don't want to change that.
So I'm gonna go back to my command line
and run cp
and this is in the
directory above
and I'm just gonna copy that here.
So I should now have both of these files
in my
repository branch here. So I'm going to run get
at dash a
and then going to run GIT commit
and give it a message
and then I'm gonna run GIT push
so that should push those objects up into our repository.
So back here in codecommit, if we click on code we should now see our app spec dot Yamil
and our task def dot Jason files so you can view those,
make sure yours has got this image name and your aspect dot Yamil
should
look like this.
Remember with task definition should look exactly like this, nothing changed.
We're now going to go to I am and we need to create a role
and this role is going to be used by codedeploy
So let's go into I am go to roles.
Create role.
The use case needs to be codedeploy so I'm just gonna scroll down, choose codedeploy
and then codedeploy dash E C s
click on next
for policies we can see it has the AWS code deploy role for
selected by default
that gives us all the permissions we need
let's click on next
let's give it a role name,
you can find this name in the file and the instructions codedeploy E C s role
and that's all we need to do.
So let's create the role.
We can now go and create our application
In codedeploy
So back in the developer tools here, let's go down to codedeploy.
Let's go to applications,
we don't have any at the moment. So let's create an application.
I'm gonna call this one pcs
lab, you should use the same naming convention as me.
We're going to choose
amazon ec s as the compute platform and then choose create application,
then we can create our deployment group. So just choose create deployment group.
This will be called
codedeploy dash E C s
for the service role. We can choose Codedeploy E CS role that we created previously.
The vcs cluster name,
choose my e CS
lab cluster
for service name. It should then be my service
then for low balances. We're going to choose my e C S A L B,
We're gonna select the production, this Nepal, which is 80
And then we've got our test listener port which is 80, 80
And we've got target group one
and target group too.
So that's the configuration there.
We're going to leave traffic rerouting on reroute traffic immediately
And you can reduce this if you want. So it takes
an hour before the original revision is terminated.
That can be quite a long time if you want to sort of
hurry things up and get on with it and run some more tests.
So I'm gonna just drop mine down to 15 minutes
and then let's create our deployment group.
Next under Codepipeline, we're going to create our pipeline.
So let's click create pipeline,
it's going to be called my image pipeline. You can create a new service role.
I've created one with this name before so I can actually select the one I created.
But you can allow code pipeline to create it for you.
Let's click on next the source provider, it's going to be codecommit.
I'm gonna select my ec. S lab,
my master branch,
click on next,
skip the build stage,
skip.
And then for deployed provider,
what we want to choose is amazon ec?
S blue green, make sure it's the blue green option.
We're then going to select pcs lab as the codedeploy application
and then the deployment group
for source artifact.
It will be task def dot Jason.
So I've typed in task def dot Jason
for source out artifact here.
We want to choose aspect dot Yeah, most to type that in.
We can then click on next
scroll down and create our pipeline.
We now need to make some changes. So what we're gonna do is edit
the pipeline here,
click on edit stage next to source,
click add action.
We're going to call this image.
And then for action provider we're going to scroll down to source and choose amazon.
Ec. Are we're gonna give it the repository name, engine X
and for image tag. In fact we leave that one
as as unpopulated there
and under output artifacts.
We want to type my
image
just as you see it there.
Then we can click on done
and save
and save again.
Now we do want to go back in now and make another edit to the deploy.
Don't worry if it's failed. That's okay. We're going to click on edit
well then click on edit stage
and will choose this option to edit the existing action
under input artifacts. We want to click on add
and they will want to choose my image
scroll down now
to where it says sought artifact. Make sure that task def dot Jason has entered
and under the next one aspect dot Yamil should be entered
in dynamically update task definition,
choose my image.
So now we select my image
and then enter the placeholder text
that we put into the task def dot Jason.
So what we used was image 1 _ name.
Now we can click on done
and save
and save again.
What we can do now is click on release change
and then release
to get the pipeline to actually run.
So let's see what happens. We can see
that were
in progress now for pulling some changes from codecommit
and let's just give this a couple of minutes and see what happens.
So now we've gone to the deploy stage so this is in progress
and you can actually view the details here so I'm gonna click details,
we can see that we're deploying a replacement task set
so we can watch this, it's gonna take a few minutes.
What you might want to do is go over to EC
two as well and have a look at your load balancer.
We're gonna watch as the configuration is updated.
So a few minutes have passed for me and we can see that we've
now gone to 100% of the traffic being served by the replacement task set.
We've gone through step two and step three. So if I now go to ec two
and let's refresh this page. Now of course what we had was
Port 80 is the primary listener on Target Group one. Let's refresh this page
and now you can see that target Group two is
and we're in the process of having this updated.
So target Group One should be associated soon with the test listener,
but now we're forwarding traffic to Target Group Two
for any applications that connect to our load balancer.
The next thing that will happen is step forward to wait for 15 minutes
and then it will terminate the original task set.
Now you can wait for the 15 minutes to happen or you can actually stop and roll back.
We've kind of proven what's happening here.
Now I don't want to wait because I want to get on to the next
lesson where I'm going to show you how to make changes to your source image.
So I'm just gonna choose stop and roll back
and that's really fast. It's quite a quick process.
We can watch this happening in real time.
You can see we now have the rollback
status in progress and we're gonna roll everything back
and this usually happens within a couple of minutes.
So that's really fast.
That's why it's really easy to roll back with a blue green update.
If I now refresh, we can see we're back to normal,
we're back to where we started from with our traffic going to target group one.
So that's it for this lesson. Leave everything running.
We're going to do another blue green update in the next lesson.