Hi guys and welcome to the last of the E C S lab,
five part series in this one we're going to implement another blue green updates.
Pcs
and there's a couple of ways we can do this
one is to delete our image from the repository.
Another option is to modify it.
Now I'm just gonna choose to delete our image from the repository and then
upload a new one and that's going to trigger a change in our pipeline.
So back in the instructions file here, as I mentioned, there's two options,
make a change to the source image,
You might want to customize it and then push the image up or just
delete the image from PcR and then we'll push it back up again.
So we're going to do the second option here.
So let's go back to the console and delete our image first.
So back in the console I'm gonna go to elastic container registry.
Let's find our repository.
I'm going to go into the repository. I don't want to delete the repository.
I want to delete the actual image here. So let's just choose delete
And that will get rid of our image nice and fast.
And then I'm going to go to my ec two instance
and we're going to run the commands that we ran earlier on to push our actual image up.
So firstly I might need to use Sudo S. U. For this.
So I'm just gonna switch to get some privileges
back in our file. You remember what we had to do is run a series of commands.
Now we've already tagged our image just to log in again.
We're going to need to run this command, the ec are get log in password.
So on the command line here I'm going to paste that in
that gets us logged in
and then I'm gonna run this docker push
so we already have the image.
We should just be able to push it up to our repository
and so it's saying layer already exists but let's
go back into our repository and see what's happened.
Have we now uploaded a new image? Yes.
So let's go back to Codepipeline
and let's see what's happening
so we can see it happened really fast so we had an update
and now it's pushed into the deploy stage we can go to details again
and have a look at what's going on
and so it's deploying the replacement task set and much like before it's
gonna do the same thing it's just gonna make those updates for us.
Now another thing you'll notice if you come back to let's just go to E. C. S.
You will see here that our task definition
now has multiple revisions.
Now we didn't make those ourselves that was done
for us so those are automatically being updated by codedeploy
So let's go back and have a look at our progress so not that one
let's come back to here
so this is our update that's happening
and so obviously that will take a few minutes and we
should see our traffic getting rerouted to the target group too.
So while that's happening, just coming back to the slides were on the last part here.
So this is where we're actually at.
And so what we did was we actually deleted and replaced our image.
That kicks off the codepipeline and Codepipeline then talks to E C S
and the A L B.
And it swaps over to target group too. So that's the replacement target group.
That's uh
that we can actually see in the console.
So hopefully that's all work. Let's go back and see where we're at.
So it's happening pretty fast.
We can see that the rerouting production traffic
to the replacement task set has indeed happened.
So there we are.
And of course if we go back to EC two
and let's just go to our elastic load balancer
and we should be able to see now. Yes, it's forwarding traffic to target group too.
So that is a blue green update.
We've now utilized several different components of AWS to make this work.
So hopefully that will work well for you and you should see something like this
If you leave it now, what will happen is after 15 minutes, it's going to terminate
the original task set and then we'll be running on the target group too.
So that's it, that's how everything works now,
of course we have launched a few things here,
so you'll want to go through when you're finished and actually clean things up
so the things to clean up of course are are elastic load balancer.
Don't forget to take that away.
We have an ec two instance running so you can terminate your ec two instance
now we have a Fargate cluster running so you'll
want to go in and just delete your service.
But of course
as I showed you before, you'll have to go in and edit
knock that down to zero tasks.
Once you've updated, you can then remove your service.
The Fargate cluster itself doesn't cost you anything
and you might want to go and clean out your repository as well.
So that's it for this lesson.
Hope it will work well for you and I'll see you in the next lesson.