In this lesson, you're going to learn about AWS Cloud nine. So what is cloud nine?
It's an integrated development environment I. D.
That means developers can use this environment
to write code and validate their code.
So it's used by developers to write run as well as debugging code.
The editor provides syntax highlighting, code completion and error checking.
So it helps developers to make sure that they are writing good code.
The terminal is used to navigate the fastest.
You can run commands
and you can manage code.
It also provides collaboration features that allow multiple
developers to work on the same code base,
so you can invite other developers into your project and
then you can each work on the same code base.
It also provides a range of debugging tools to
help you identify and fix errors in your code.
AWS Cloud Nine integrates with lots of AWS services, including AWS lambda
amazon Ec two
and AWS Codepipeline.
Now, there's not too much that you need to understand about this for the exam,
other than what's here,
but we'll go over to the AWS console and just do a really quick hands on to
show you how to create an environment and then run a really simple piece of code.
I'm logged into AWS on the Cloud Nine console here and all I need
to do is create an environment and I'll just call this my demo environment.
We now have a couple of options for where the Cloud nine I. D. Is going to run.
You can choose
to launch a new Ec two instance or select an existing compute instance for me,
I'm going to create a new ec two instance.
I'm going to leave the instance type as T two micro.
It's amazon Linux two for the am I got a time out here so that it will auto
hibernate after 30 minutes if there's no activity to
save you some costs on run in that instance.
Next we've got network settings.
So how are you going to
one option is systems manager and the other option is secure.
Shell, probably more secure to use systems manager and optionally you can define
the Vpc settings.
I'm just gonna leave all the defaults now notice
at the bottom there are some service rolls through.
I am going to be created for your account so I'm happy with that.
Let's create our environment.
So now it's creating the environment and as it says,
it will take several minutes potentially.
And once it's ready we'll go in and have a look at how to you use the editor.
So that just took a couple of minutes and now my environment has been created.
So let's click on the open button here to open the Cloud nine I. D.
So here we are,
there's a bit of a welcome page there which
you can obviously use and read some information.
I'm just going to close out of that one.
So this is the editor environment and we have the terminal at the bottom here.
So with the terminal, I can do things like create a script.
Let's create a script using python that creates the file up in the top left here,
you can see the the file system that you can browse, we can select our file,
we can put some code in here,
like maybe a simple Hello World function and then you can always
go and run that code and you get a simple Hello World.
So really that's it past that.
It's all about using this tool to actually write code, edit code. Debug code.
So that's outside of the scope of this course, so I'll leave it there.
But if you're a developer obviously this is a really useful tool that you can use.