Welcome to the exam cram for developer tools and c i C D.
Codecommit is a fully managed source control service that hosts secure.
Get based repositories
gets an open source distributed source control system gives
you a centralized repository for all your code Binaries,
Images and libraries.
It tracks and manages code changes
and maintains version history.
It also manages updates from multiple sources
and enables collaboration.
Codecommit. Repositories are private.
Codecommit is integrated with Jenkins Codebuild
and other continuous integration tools.
You can transfer your files to and from Codecommit using https or ssh.
You need to configure your get
client to communicate with codecommit repositories.
I am supports co commit with three types of credentials, get credentials.
Ssh keys and also access keys.
Codepipeline is a managed continuous delivery service
that helps you automate release pipelines,
it automates the build, test and deploy phases of your release process
every time a code change happens.
Codepipeline provides tooling integrations for many aws
and 3rd party software.
Code Guru provides intelligent recommendations for improving
application performance efficiency and code quality.
Code Guru reviews, java and python code and offers suggestions for improvement
suggestions are based on best practices.
It finds complex issues such as resource leak and security analysis
is made up of two services.
Code guru reviewer
and code Guru. Profiler.
Codebuild is a fully managed continuous integration service.
It compiles your source code
runs test and produces software packages
that are ready to deploy.
Codebuild takes the source code from github
Codecommit Codepipeline. S free etcetera
build instructions can be defied in the code
using the builds back dot y mel file,
Output logs can be sent to S three
and cloudwatch logs.
Codedeploy is a deployment service that automates application deployments.
It deploys to ec two instances on premises instances.
Lambda functions
and DCs.
You can deploy a nearly unlimited variety of application. Content
codedeploy application contains information about what to
deploy and how to deploy it.
You need to choose the compute platform so easy to slash on premises or lambda or E C s
if you use easy to or on premises,
traffic is directed using an in place or blue
green deployment type to a replacement set of instances.
For lambda traffic is shifted using a canary linear or all at once configuration
and that's to a new version of the function.
For e C.
S codedeploy performs a blue green deployment by installing an
updated version of the application as a new replacement task set
for e C S,
traffic is shifted using canary linear or all
at once configuration to the replacement task set.
Note that all lambda and CCS deployments are blue green and
easy to on premises deployment can be in place or blue green
code star enables you to quickly develop, build and deploy applications on AWS.
It's a pre configured continuous delivery toolchain for developing building,
testing and deploying.
You can use code editors such as Visual Studio Eclipse or the AWS Cli
It uses I am to manage developer identities
and has built in role based policies for secure team access,
Application code is stored in codecommit.
It compiles and packages. Source code using codebuild,
and a pre configured pipeline is used through codepipeline.
It also has automated deployments with codedeploy and cloud formation.
That's it for this exam, cram. I'll see you in the next lesson.