Hello and welcome to our AWS Certified Developer Associate course
in this course along with our practice discourse and our cheat sheets,
you're going to learn absolutely everything you need to know to pass the exam.
So who is this course for
this course is for anyone who wants to pass the Developer Associate exam.
Now it doesn't matter if you come from a development background or not.
I will provide all code samples and provide lots of
instruction to help you deploy infrastructure and code on AWS.
There'll be lots of hands on lessons
and lots of theory to back it up. So you really understand the concepts.
The developer Associate is one of free Associate level exams.
The other two are the Solutions Architect
Associate and the sys ops Administrator Associate.
I typically recommend that if you're going to work with
AWS or you're looking to get a job in AWS
then you should do all free Associate level exams.
Most people will start with the solutions architect Associate first
and for that reason I go into more depth on some topics
in that particular course.
In this course I do start at the basics but then
I move very quickly through to some of the more advanced topics
that are specific to this exam
That way I keep the course nice and
efficient and it's an easier learning experience for you
in terms of how to use the course.
I recommend that you follow from the beginning, right the way through to the end,
make sure you create your own free tier account
and follow along with the numerous hands on lessons
That way you get lots of hands on practice which is really
useful for building your knowledge and making sure you remember the concepts.
There's also a free study plan included with the course that gives you a structured
approach for planning out your training using
the video course and the practice tests.
Now that's it for my quick introduction.
I really hope you enjoy the course and I wish you the best with your exam.
Now please before you move onto section to make sure you download your
course download you're gonna need that as you do the hands on lessons.