In this quick video, I just want to discuss a couple of options to getting hands-on practice.
Now, whatever technology you're learning, there's no substitute for getting hands-on practice actually
using the technology.
it really is the best way to learn.
Now, in this course, I recommend you open your own AWS free tier account.
But there's another additional tool that might be useful called a Sandbox.
So let's start off with free tier.
With the free tier, you're going to create your very own AWS free tier account, and I'm going to show
you how to do that.
Now you get full control over this account. It's your account and that means you can do anything
you want with the account.
Now, this does mean that you're responsible for any bills.
You'll need to add a credit card when you sign up for your free tier account and you'll have to pay
any bills that you run up.
Now, we will operate in the free tier in this course, and if we ever go outside of the free tier, I'm
going to warn you. But you always have to follow my instructions and make sure you shut down resources
to avoid bills.
And we're going to set a billing alarm, so you get a notification if you reach a certain threshold.
I highly recommend that you do open your own free tier account so you can follow along with my instructions
as we go through the course in the hands-on lessons.
An additional resource is known as a Sandbox or a Challenge Lab.
Now in this model, the AWS account is actually hosted by a provider,
it's not your account.
Now that does mean that you will have limited control. For more advanced courses
it means you won't be able to do things like cross account access because you'll only have one account
and you'll have limited control over it.
On the plus side, it means you get no cloud bills.
You don't take any risk or responsibility. You pay for the service upfront and there's no risk of running
up any additional bills.
With Challenge Labs
you get scenario-based challenges, so it's a great way to test your skills and learn new skills as
well
based on a scenario that's been pre-configured for you. It's been designed for you and the lab has
been set up to accommodate that particular challenge.
I recommend Challenge Labs as an additional training tool.
If you do want to gain access to Challenge Labs, then we actually have some on our website.
Now this is completely optional.
It's not required for this course, but it's an extra learning tool.
It does require registration and you have to pay an additional fee.
There's a video on this page to show what they look like in action, and in this particular example,
there were over 700 labs across many different cloud platforms and technologies.
Alternatively, if you're just learning AWS, you can access the AWS Challenge Labs. And you can see an example
here of the console. For those who are taking the SysOps exam,
this is what you'll see in your AWS exam lab.
This is the same provider that AWS used for their new exam labs. So you'll get the AWS management console
on the left and some instructions on the right. Or in the case of the exam or the more advanced labs,
you just get a scenario and a few hints as to what you need to do.
And it also verifies and validates the work that you've done.
So these are completely optional, but they're definitely a very useful tool for getting extra practice
and validating your own skills.