AWS CloudFormation is a tool that we can use to build infrastructure according to code.
So, you'll often hear the term infrastructure as code.
Now what that really means is you define your infrastructure.
And by that, we mean anything from a VPC, through to an EC2 instance, through to a serverless application.
All of that is defined in code in a template file. And then you supply the template file to Cloud
Formation and it will then go and build your infrastructure, build out your entire application for
you in an automated fashion.
So let's have a look at it visually.
With CloudFormation, we have a template file.
The template file contains our code.
Our code is written in one of two languages either JSON or YAML.
So we define our entire application stack in code,
we supply that template file to CloudFormation and CloudFormation then goes and builds out our entire
infrastructure according to whatever code we've written in that template file.
In this case, it's built an entire VPC, public subnets,
it's added an auto scaling group with a number of instances, and then it's also provisioned to load balancer.
The great thing about CloudFormation is now that we have our template file, we can go and repeatedly
deploy the same stack in different locations, maybe in different regions, or even again in the same
region by creating an entire new stack in parallel.
So, it gives us that repeatability and automation.
So let's look at the key benefits.
Your infrastructure is provisioned consistently, and that means there are fewer mistakes in terms of
human error.
Because once you've defined your template and you've made sure it's working correctly, you've tested
it thoroughly,
from that point on, you can keep using that template file without worrying about there being any mistakes
in the code.
It takes a lot less time and effort than configuring resources manually.
This is especially true if you're repeatedly deploying a very similar set of infrastructure.
So if you're deploying VPCs with very similar configurations in the same region or across multiple
regions or multiple accounts, it makes a lot of sense to define a CloudFormation template
and then from that point on, there's a bit of upfront effort, but from that point on, you can then
really save a lot of time, reduce errors, and deploy consistently.
CloudFormation includes the ability to have version control and peer review of your templates. And
it's totally free to use.
CloudFormation doesn't cost anything, but you do pay for the resources that are provisioned by Cloud
Formation.
So in the previous example, you would still pay for your auto scaling group,
you would pay for your EC2 instances and your load balancer, but you wouldn't pay for actually deploying
them through CloudFormation.
CloudFormation can be used to manage updates and dependencies, and it can be used to rollback and
delete the entire stack as well for you,
also automated. Let's look at some of the key components of CloudFormation.
Firstly, you've got the template file. That's written in JSON or YAML and it contains the instructions
for building out the AWS environment.
Now when you do that, you create something called a stack.
The stack is the actual environment that's defined by the template and created and deployed by Cloud
Formation.
We then have something called a stack set.
When you create a stack set, you deploy stacks across multiple accounts or multiple AWS regions. So,
it's extending the core functionality.
A change set is a really useful feature for validating and viewing what the changes are going to be
to your stack when you've updated your template file. So you can update your template file,
load it in as a change set, and then CloudFormation will show you what's going to change.
Once you're happy with the changes, you then actually push them into production.
CloudFormation is best understood when you really see it in action.
So, in the next couple of lessons, we're going to be deploying some stacks in CloudFormation.