Okay. So let's look at Stacks, Stack Sets, and Nested Stacks in a bit more detail.
So we have our CloudFormation stacks.
Now these are the resources that are deployed based on our CloudFormation templates.
You create, update, and delete stacks using templates.
Stacks are deployed through the management console,
the Command Line Interface or the APIs.
Now, sometimes you get creation errors for your stack.
Automatic rollback on error is enabled by default.
So if it finds an issue it will automatically roll back and attempt to
terminate or delete any resources that have been created up to that point.
You will get charged for any resources that have been used even if there is an error.
Next we have Stacks Sets.
This allows you to create, update, or delete stacks across multiple accounts
and regions with a single operation.
An administrator account is the AWS account
in which you then create the stack set.
A stack set is managed by signing in to the AWS administrator account
in which it was created.
The target account is the account into which you create,
update or delete one or more stacks in your stack set.
Lastly, we have something called nested stacks.
Nested stacks allow reuse of cloud formation code for common use cases.
So for example, you might have a standard configuration for your load balancers,
your web servers, application servers or even VPCs.
And you can reuse that across different stacks.
So you create a standard template for each common use case
and then you reference it from within your CloudFormation template.
So here we can see that we have a root stack in this diagram,
and then there are various nested stacks.
And the are even nested stacks within nested stacks, so they're each calling
upon another template, which has a specific resource or set of resources defined,
which are standardized.