Hi guys in this lesson,
we're going to create an application using AWS Elastic Beanstalk
and then we're going to see how we can update that application.
I'm logged into AWS and I'm on the Elastic Beanstalk page.
And what I'm going to do is use the create application button here.
Now what we need to do first is provide an application name.
So I'm going to call my application My Beanstalk Test.
And if I scroll down a little way, we then have the choose platform.
Now I'm going to choose Node.js.
I'm going to leave the defaults here.
But then I'm going to choose to actually upload my own code.
So let's scroll down
and I'm going to choose a file.
And what I'm gonna do is in my course download, go to the Elastic Beanstalk directory
and choose this Node.js.zip.
Click on upload.
So now we can simply create our application.
Now, if you wanted to apply some more advanced configurations,
you can choose to configure more options.
In here we can define various different things. So firstly we've got some presets.
Presets for single instance with free tier eligibility,
we can create highly available infrastructure,
and we can use high availability with spot and on-demand instances,
or our own custom configuration.
We can enable things like the X-ray daemon for tracing our application.
We can configure information about our instances,
the capacity, so what instance types we want to use and the image ID, etc.
And of course we can add load balancers.
So in a highly available configuration we would
have multiple instances and a load balancer.
So there's quite a bit you can do there. I'm not going to change any of those settings.
Let's just go and create our application.
So that's being created and we can see the progress happening on our screen here.
And it can take several minutes with Elastic Beanstalk for it to complete.
So it's been a few minutes and my application appears to be deployed now.
And what I can do to check is we've got this URL here. So I can click on this URL.
And it should take me to this landing page, which is the Node.js landing page.
So this is a default document that gets shown.
So that looks good. That looks like my application has correctly installed.
Now, as you can see on the left hand side here,
we have a couple of different places that we can configure options.
Firstly, we have the application which is here.
And you can see the application versions.
We only have one at this stage.
Then we actually have the environments which are part of the application.
So here you can see the environment
and the various different configuration options for environment.
Now, what we're going to do is we're going to upload a new version of our application
and we're going to make a modification to the code that we used before to do that.
I'm in the file system of my computer here and looking at the Node.js.zip file.
What you need to do is just unzip that file
and then go into the Node.js directory.
And in here we'll find a few files.
Now what I want to do is I'm going to edit the index.html.
and I'm going to use visual studio code.
So here is my file.
Now what I'm going to do is scroll down a little way
to the area where I see this background color and it's green.
Now, we're going to copy over this
and we're going to put in blue.
And as we do so we have the option come up here.
So that's how I want it to look.
I'm going to save my document.
and now here's the really important thing. We need to zip this up again.
But I don't want you to zip this folder.
You must take the files and zip the files.
Now I'm on a Mac and the way I do that is I highlight them all and then compress.
You might be using Winzip or some other utility on your computer.
But just make sure you select the files.
So I've got this archive, I'm just going to bring it up to this directory.
And I'm going to rename it to Node.js-bue.
Back in the Elastic Beanstalk console I'm going to choose upload and deploy,
choose a file,
choose My Node.js Blue, click on upload.
It's going to give it a version label and we can see here it says source-1.
So let's click on deploy.
And that should just take a few minutes.
So remember this is how our web application looks at the moment.
And what we're trying to do is change this here to green.
So that's taking place, just give it a couple of minutes
and then it should be updated.
Now in the meantime, if you've got EC2 open,
you should be able to find your instance running here.
So in EC2, we can see our beanstalk instances.
It has a name so mine is named after the environment that we created.
So you can interact with your EC2 instances and you can manage them as well.
As long as you add a key pair during the creation,
which is something we actually didn't do,
But if you do do that then you're able to
actually use that key pair to access your instance.
So let's go back and just watch the status and once it's complete,
we'll test our application again.
So I've just noticed that it now says instance deployment completed successfully.
Hasn't quite got the health information back yet.
But if we come back to our web application here,
refresh and now it's turned blue.
So that's worked as expected.
Now back in Beanstalk we should now
see that we have these different application versions.
And you can see the different code.
So if you wanted to, you could now revert back,
you can always change back to a different version.
So for example I can choose this option, go to deploy,
and it's going to actually redeploy the original code.
So these exist independently of the actual application that's running.
And they're there so that you have a history of the source code
that you can always go back to a previous version if something goes wrong.
So that should now be updating again. Let's go back to our environment.
And that appears to have completed.
So let's go back, refresh, and now we're back to where we were.
And that's it for this lesson. We've finished with this environment.
So what I'm going to do is simply go to actions and terminate environment.
Now you do need to then copy the name of the environment and paste that in
and then terminate.
Now this won't actually delete the application, it deletes the environment.
That is the EC2 instance as well.
So the EC2 instance will be terminated
but the application configuration is there so we can then
create new environment. So we will do that later on in this section.