In this lesson, I'm going to cover the deployment options for AWS Elastic Beanstalk.
And this is something that comes up on quite a lot
of exam questions so you need to know the details here.
The first deployment option we have is called all at once.
What this does is it will deploy a new version to all instances simultaneously.
Now of course, that means it's going to take all of your instances out of action.
There's downtime for all instances at the same time.
We then have rolling.
Here, you get to update a batch of instances
and then move on to the next batch once the first batch is healthy.
So it avoids having everything offline.
We also have rolling with additional batch.
It's like rolling but it launches new instances in a batch first.
So it ensures that you've got the full capacity for your application available
at all times.
Then we have immutable.
This will launch new instances in a new Auto Scaling group
and deploy the version update to these instances before
swapping the traffic to these instances once healthy.
And then we have blue/green,
which isn't exactly an Elastic Beanstalk deployment option itself.
It's not something you can configure in Elastic Beanstalk
but you can do this to create a new staging environment and then deploy the updates
and direct your traffic there.
So you have to direct the traffic maybe with AWS Route 53.
So let's look at some diagrams.
So for all at once here we have two EC2 instances.
And what's going to happen is we're moving from version one to version two.
Both instances get taken out of action.
The update is applied and then our instances are healthy again.
So this deploys a new version to all instances at the same time
and all instances will be taken out of service while the deployment takes place.
This is the fastest option.
And it's good for quick iterations in a development environment.
You might not want to do this in prod.
So absolutely be careful using this one.
It's going to be a complete outage of all of your application instances
so make sure you're not doing it in prod or for any kind of mission critical system.
If the update fails,
you need to roll back the changes by redeploying the original version
to all of your instances.
If the update fails, you need to roll back the changes by
redeploying the original version to all of your instances.
And there's no additional cost to using an all at once update.
Next we have the rolling update.
So again, we're moving from version one of our code to version two.
What happens here is we have a batch size and in this case the
batch size is two so two instances are going to get taken out of action
and the update gets deployed.
And then the next two instances get taken out of action
and now they're updated as well.
So bear in mind with this option,
you've got to configure your batch size in this case our batch size is two.
But we've only got four instances so that's 50%.
That means 50% of our capacity
for our application has been removed from service for a while.
So with rolling update, you're updating a few instances at a time, that's a batch
and then you move on to the next batch once the first batch is healthy.
So if we had for instance, you know, 15, 20 instances we're going to do two at
a time until we've completed all of the instances.
Downtime will only ever affect one batch at a time.
And the application is running both versions simultaneously.
So you've had some that are updated to version two
and you've still got some instances that are running version one at the same time.
And each batch will get taken out of service while the deployment takes place.
Your environment capacity will be reduced by the number of
instances in a batch while the deployment takes place.
Therefore this is not ideal for performance sensitive systems
where you need full capacity for your application.
If the update fails,
you need to perform an additional rolling update to roll back the changes.
And again there's no additional cost to using a rolling update.
There's also a long deployment time because you're going through those batches,
of course it depends on your batch size and how many instances you've got.
But it's going to take longer than for example and all at once update.
Next we have rolling with additional batch.
So in this case what we've done is launched additional instances
before we take out the existing instances out of action.
So with this option we're ensuring that we've always got full capacity.
So if our normal capacity is four instances,
we've got these two to ensure that four are always going to be available so
when two are taken out of action there's always going to be four available.
This option is like rolling but launches new instances in a batch,
ensuring there's full availability.
The application is always running at full capacity
and you can configure the batch size.
The application is again running both versions simultaneously.
There is a bit of an additional cost because you've got the extra instances.
And the additional batch is removed at the end of the deployment,
putting you back to your normal capacity size.
Again this is a longer deployment and it is
good for production environments because we're not reducing capacity
and we're not taking everything out of action.
Next we've got the immutable update.
With an immutable update, we're deploying a completely new Auto Scaling group
with the same number of instances.
We're updating those instances and then once they're
healthy we can take the old Auto Scaling group out of action
after we've actually sort of redirected our traffic to the new ASG.
So with immutable, we're launching new instances in a new ASG,
deploying the version updates of those instances,
and then swapping the traffic to those instances once healthy.
There's zero downtime.
The new code is deployed to new instances using an ASG.
It does have a high cost as you're doubling the number of instances running
during the update period.
And it also has the long deployment time, it's going to take longer to deploy.
So you've got to bear in mind that.
There is a quick rollback in case of failures because you just
redirect the traffic back to the original instances in the old ASG.
This is great for production environments.
You're not reducing capacity, you have an easy sort of rollback solution.
I mean, the only issue is there's a little bit of an additional cost
and the longer deployment time.
But that's usually worth it for a production deployment.
The next option is a blue/green update.
So here we have an environment with V1 of our code, another one with V2.
We've got Route 53.
And we're using weighted routing policies to send 80% of our
traffic to one environment and 20 to the other environments.
So V2 is our staging environment at this point in time
and we're testing our code there.
This is not a feature of Elastic Beanstalk. We're using route 53 here.
You create a new staging environment, you deploy your updates there.
The new environment, the green one gets validated independently
and you can roll back very easily if there are any issues.
You're using Route 53 weighted routing policies here to
redirect a percentage of traffic to the staging environment.
You can configure what that percentage is.
Using Elastic Beanstalk, you can then swap the URLs
When done with the environment test.
So that means the URL is getting swapped across and that we can update
our weighted routing policies as we need to.
There's also zero downtime with a blue/green update.
So that's it for this lesson.
Do make sure that you fully understand these different options
and the various strengths and weaknesses of each option
because that's definitely subjects that you will be tested on in the exam.