In this lesson we'll review the backup and recovery options for RDS databases.
So we have our RDS database instance.
We can configure a backup window and we can choose that ourselves or we can leave it as no preference
and it gets decided for us.
So if we choose it, then we can set a start time and also a duration.
When we take a backup using an automated backup, it is actually done as a snapshot.
And that snapshot can be retained for zero to 35 days.
Zero just means that you've basically turned off automatic backups.
35 days is the maximum.
You can then restore that snapshot and it creates a new database instance.
Restore can be to any point in time during the retention period.
You've then got manual backups.
So this also is using snapshots.
It backs up the entire database instance, not just individual databases.
Note that for single availability zone database instances there is a brief suspension of I/O,
so they can cause a slight interruption to your application, which might be in production.
So bear that in mind.
And this doesn't happen for multi-AZ because the back up can be taken from the standby instance.
For Multi-AZ SQL Server, the I/O activity is briefly suspended on the primary.
For multi-AZ MariaDB, MySQL, Oracle and PostgreSQL the snapshot is always taken from the standby,
so you don't have to worry about that slight interruption.
Snapshots do not expire, so there's no retention period.
So unlike the automatic backups where you must specify how long, up to 35 days, you can actually just
keep these ones forever.
So what about maintenance windows?
The operating system and database patching does sometimes require taking the database offline.
So this is where you can specify your maintenance window.
Again, you can leave it as no preference or select your own window and have a start time and day
and also a duration.
So the tasks that require the database to be taken offline will happen during the maintenance window.
And by default, there's a weekly window that's actually specified or you just go and choose your own.
So that's all I wanted to cover in this lesson.
I'll see you in the next lesson.