Welcome back.
We're now going to continue from where we left off before.
And we're going to create a read replica from our Digicloud database and also enable multi-AZ as
well.
Back in the console, I can see my database is here Digicloud.
I've got it selected and under actions, I'm going to create a read replica.
Now, you can then change the DB instance class if you want to.
You can enable multi-AZ, so you have a multi-AZ copy of your read replica database and you can modify
the storage.
We're going to leave those defaults. Now,
you can also change the region so you could have a read replica in a different region if you want to.
You can also specify the availability zone and whether you want this to be publicly accessible.
Now again, I'm going to leave all the defaults.
We can't actually encrypt because remember with a read replica, it must have the same encryption status
as the master database that it has been copied from.
So if the primary is encrypted, then you can have an encrypted read replica or you will have encrypted read
replica.
There's no two ways about it.
And if the primary is not encrypted, then it cannot be an encrypted read replica.
I'm going to give a slightly different identifier for my database.
It's going to be called Digicloud-Replica. And the port is going to be the same.
We're going to keep all the remaining defaults as they are and choose to create the read replica.
We can now see the Digicloud-replica database in the console here.
So it's a separate database and it's in the creating state. And the Digicloud database is in the modifying
state.
So what's happening is the Digicloud Replica is having the database information replicated across
to it, so we're creating a replica of that primary instance.
Now, if we click on this identifier, we can then see some information about the database.
Now, in this point in time, because it's not complete yet, it's not available,
we don't have the endpoints and port.
So, in a few minutes, we'll refresh and hopefully we'll get a read replica endpoint. Back up a level,
we can see that the Digicloud Replica is still in the creating state,
but my main database is available. Now,
what I'm going to do while this is completing is select my main database, the primary, choose modify,
and what we're going to do is just scroll down.
We're not changing any of these settings here.
What we want to get to is availability and durability.
And we're going to change to a multi-AZ deployment.
And then just scroll all the way to the bottom and click on continue.
Now, when we want to apply this change, it does warn us that there's a potential performance impact.
So, you can actually allow this to happen in a maintenance window or you can apply immediately.
We want to apply it immediately. So, make sure you change to that option and then click on modify DB
instance.
Both of our databases are now in the modifying state.
The replica database should be finished very shortly.
The main database is now creating a multi-AZ stand by in a separate availability zone.
Now, unlike the replica, it's not a separate DB identifier in here, so you can't see it as a separate
database that you can interact with and point your applications to.
But it is being created, and you might have to give this a few minutes be a bit patient, and hopefully
it will be ready very soon.
My replica has now become available. So let's click on the replica and under connectivity and security,
we can see a different endpoint here, so we have a separate endpoint.
So it's really important to remember that when you have a read replica, your application logic needs
to know to point to the read replica for any queries and to point to the primary database for any database
writes.
Now, if we come back up and have a look at the primary database and scroll down, you can actually
see under replication here that we have the replica and the replica source is the primary database.
It's in the same availability zone in this case, and it's in a replication state at this point in time.
So, our read replica is almost ready, just replicating at this point. We just need to wait a couple
more minutes now for our main primary database to become available again so that we can have a look
at how we can fail over to our multi-AZ standby.
So that's it.
My database is now available, which means I have a multi-AZ standby ready.
Now it did take maybe 15 or so minutes to create that standby in another availability zone. But it's
really important to remember that this is a real differentiator of cloud. Before cloud,
this kind of deployment where you have a database and then a multi-AZ standby or read replica even
in another region that could have cost tens to
hundreds of thousands of dollars.
And it would take from weeks to months to actually put together a solution like that with all the planning,
the deployment and the testing.
I know because I've done that many, many times.
Now, let's go into our DB identify for the primary database and have a look at what's changed.
Under connectivity and security, we can see
we have the same endpoint.
The endpoint has not changed because it's multi-AZ.
This is still where we're going to point our applications. Now, under networking, we can see that
our primary is in US-East-1D.
If we then click on configuration, scroll down a little way, you'll see multi-AZ and we can see the
secondary zone is US-East-1F.
So that's where our stand by instance is running.
Now, if we come back to the top now, by the way, if you don't see that yet, you need to wait and
refresh until you see the secondary zone.
Otherwise, you won't be able to do the next part of the exercise correctly.
So, what we're going to do now is go to actions, and from the actions menu you see we can create a read
replica, take a snapshot, restore to a specific point in time.
But what we want to do is reboot.
We're going to reboot with failover, and that means we're going to switch the primary from the current
primary to the standby.
The standby will become the new primary in a different availability zone.
So, with reboot with failover selected,
click on confirm.
And again, you'll need to wait a few minutes while that takes place.
So my database has now successfully failed over to the standby.
And so what you can see now is the primary database has change to the US-East-1F availability zone.
If we click on the DB identifier, under networking we can see again the availability zone the primary
is running in.
If we go to configuration, we can now see the secondary is in US-East-1D, so that's where we
originally had our primary. So, that all looks good.
That's exactly what we were expecting.
Now, don't worry if yours hasn't changed availability zones here in the console because sometimes
it does take a few minutes for the console to update.
Now, that's it for this lesson. And we have actually finished with these databases, but I'm going to
leave mine running because I want to show you a couple more things in another lesson.
If you want to, you can go now and delete your database.
You'll simply select your database, click on actions, delete.
You can deselect the option to create a final snapshot.
And just select this option to say that you acknowledge that the database, its automated backups, and
the system generated snapshots will be deleted.
Now, don't worry your snapshot that you took earlier the manual one, that will still be here. And we're
going to use that and another lesson.