Amazon Aurora is a database in the RDS family.
Now, it was developed by AWS themselves, and it has some really great features, especially in durability
and scalability.
Aurora is AWS's fastest growing product, so that really tells you about how powerful it is.
Now, many customers find great use cases for moving off of third-party databases that often have very
expensive licensing and support models.
So, moving on to Aurora can often give them the features they need and the performance they need whilst
lowering costs.
So let's have a look at the key features of Aurora.
As I mentioned, it's a database in the RDS family.
Now, it has two different engines, MySQL and Postgres.
Of course, both of these are relational database engines.
Now it has some really great speed improvements. AWS say five times faster than MySQL and three times
faster than Postgres.
Aurora has a distributed, fault tolerant, and self-healing storage layer.
I'll show you what the architecture looks like shortly.
And you can actually scale right up to 128 TB per database instance.
So that's really big.
So let's have a look at the architecture. Here
we have a region with multiple availability zones.
We have a primary database and then we have one or more replicas. And these replicas can be in different
availability zones,
but they're always within a region.
So these are known as Aurora replicas. And an Aurora replica will always be in the same region.
Now, I mentioned the database layer.
You can see here that we have six copies of our data.
Each of those database icons is representing an individual copy of the database.
The primary and the replicas can all read from the database, but only the primary gets to write to
the database.
And when it does write, it will write across these different copies so that they're always up to date.
So what about the fault tolerance of Aurora?
We get fault tolerance across three availability zones with a single logical volume.
The Aurora replicas scale out read requests, and you can promote an Aurora replica to be the new primary,
or you can create a new primary at any time.
You can also use auto scaling to add replicas, so you have an auto scaling capability for that
read traffic on your database.
So in other words, if you're replicas are experiencing very high read traffic, then you can actually
have an additional replica created for you automatically.
This table includes some of the key features of Aurora. For high performance and scalability.
You get self-healing storage that can scale up to 128 TB per database instance.
You get point in time recovery and continuous backup to Amazon S3 as well.
For database compatibility, we've got MySQL and Postgres databases.
Aurora replicas give you that in-region read scaling that we looked at in the slide previously. And
they can also be a failover target.
Now, you can have up to 15 Aurora replicas and you can use auto scaling for those.
We then have a MySQL read replica.
Now the MySQL read replica is only applicable to MySQL databases. And it gives you a cross region
capability where you can have read scaling in another region.
They can also be a failover target, which means you have that capability to failover to another region.
You can have up to five MySQL read replicas, and they can each have up to 15 Aurora replicas coming
off of them.
There's another feature called global database.
This is a cross region cluster
with read scaling. And you can also remove the secondary and promote it.
So in other words, you can failover to the database that's in another region.
Global database, though, always has the writeable copy in one region, so you're only scaling
read. Multi master allows you to scale out the writes within a region.
So, each Aurora instance will be able to write to
the database. It may not appear on the exam yet because it's fairly new, but watch out for it.
Aurora serverless gives you an on-demand auto scaling configuration for Aurora.
Now, it doesn't support read replicas or public IPs, and you can only access it through VPC or Direct
Connect not for a VPN.
Aurora serverless means that your database is not running all the time, so you're waiting for traffic
and then it gets instantiated.
So, let's just clarify the differences between the two different types of replicas.
So, there's the Aurora replica and the MySQL replica. With Aurora replica,
you get up to 15 replicas from your primary and with MySQL, you can have up to five.
The replication type is asynchronous for both types of replicas, but the actual latency is lower in
the milliseconds for Aurora versus seconds with the MySQL replica.
Performance impact is low on Aurora, but it's higher on replicas using MySQL.
So just bear that in mind. It's actually using replication in the database engine
so it does put a performance impact on your database. With Aurora replicas they're in-region,
whereas with MySQL, they can be cross-region. Both types of replicas can be a failover target,
but you'll get less data loss.
You get no data loss with an Aurora replica, whereas you can potentially have up to minutes of data
loss with a MySQL replica.
The failover is automatic with the Aurora replica, and it's not with MySQL.
And then the MySQL replica does have a couple of additional features at the bottom there as well,
which aren't supported by Aurora replicas. So quite a lot to digest about Aurora.
But as I say, is a really important product in AWS. And in the next lesson, we're going to have a look
in more detail at the various different deployment options.