Welcome back.
We talked a bit in the last lesson about scalability with ElastiCache and now I'm going to go into
a bit more detail.
So it depends on which data store you're using.
If you're using Memcached then you can add nodes to a cluster.
That's one way of scaling and you can scale vertically by changing the node type.
So ElastiCache runs on EC2 instances.
So you're essentially changing the underlying EC2 instance on which it runs.
Now, when you do do that, you must create a new cluster manually.
So this is not an automatic thing and you can't change your node type within the existing cluster.
So with Redis it's a bit different and we've got the two nodes of course.
So firstly you've got the cluster mode disabled.
In this case, you add a replica or you change the node type.
And it will create a new cluster and migrate data for you.
We've then got cluster mode enabled.
In this case, you have two options.
The first is known as online resharding.
You can add or remove shards and you can perform vertical scaling to change the node type.
Then you've got offline resharding, again, adding or removing shards and changing the node type
or also upgrading the engine.
And it's a bit more flexible offline than online.
Now, this is going to make a lot more sense when you see it visually.
So let's have a look at some diagrams.
So this is what Memcached essentially looks like.
There's no shards here, you have a cluster.
The cluster can be across multiple availability zones and you've got these different nodes.
Now, each node is a partition of data.
It's not a replica of data.
So if you lose a node, you essentially lose the data that was on that node.
So that's something that's very important to understand.
You're not replicating data here and there's no backup of that data either, which is why you have
to be very careful to be able to recreate that data if you need to.
And you have to work out how expensive is it to recreate that data?
Where does it come from getting loaded?
How much is that going to cost in terms of things like the the bandwidth, the time?
What does it take to actually recreate that data if it's needed?
And what's the impact on the application as well?
We've then got ElastiCache Redis and this is cluster mode enabled.
So as you can see, you have shards.
In this case we have three shards.
They can be within an AZ or they can be across an availability zone.
In each of the shards, you have a primary and then you have one or more replicas.
In fact, you can have zero replica, so zero to five replicas in each of those shards.
Then we have cluster mode disabled.
So now you can see there's just one shard.
You've still got your primary node and then you've got your replicas, but you can't have multiple shards.
However, your shard can be across availability zones.
Now, that's it for ElastiCache.
That should set you up for any exam questions you see.
Hope you enjoyed it and I'll see you in the next lesson.