In this lesson, I'm going to talk about amazon memory dB for regis.
So what is memory DB for read this.
This is a red is compatible durable in memory database service
and it gives you ultra fast performance.
So very low latency and very high performance
and everything is in memory with memory DB.
As the name suggests in this case the entire data set is stored in memory.
It's an entire DB solution. So it's different too.
For example, elastic cache,
which is a cashing engine that sits in front of your database.
So typically with elastic cache, whether you're using Reddit or Mem cache D,
it will actually
cash the queries that are made to your database
and then the rest of the data set is actually within a database behind it,
for example.
Rds. So that's different to the way memory DB works.
Now you can have your entire data set in Alaska cash. It's just not always the case.
This is purpose built for modern applications with microservices,
architectures,
you can build applications using the
same flexible and friendly reddest data structures
ap eyes and command.
So fully compatible with Reedus, you get microsecond,
read and single digit millisecond write latency and very high free put.
So this is a higher performance option compared to
Alaska cache data is stored durably across multiple.
Aziz
using a distributed transaction log.
It also supports right scaling with chard NG and read scaling by adding replicas.
So lots of redundancy options there.
So let's just compare Reedus with elastic cache of course with amazon elasticache.
You can choose from using the red this engine or mem cache.
So either way, let's compare at a high level the differences between the two.
So the last akash, you're cashing DB queries.
So typically as I mentioned before,
you're going to have a database behind elastic cache.
You cash the queries and then
depending on the strategy,
you're using that data then gets loaded in when it's changed when rights are made
to the primary database or just when a call is made using memory DB,
you get a full database solution combining the database and the cash.
So it's essentially one database
with memory DB you get higher performance with lower latency compared
to using elastic cache and memory DB offers strong consistency for primary
and eventual consistency for replica nodes with
elasticache there can be inconsistency and latency depending
on the engine that you use and the cashing strategy that you use as well,
for example, right through versus lazy loading,
which is something we talk about in the elasticache lessons.
So that's it. For a quick comparison of the two and memory dB for red.
This is something which may come up in the examples of minor question or two.
So you should have enough information here to make sure you're prepared