The Kinesis Client Library is an important component of using Kinesis
and being able to consume and process messages from Kinesis.
So the KCL helps you consume and process data from a Kinesis Data Stream.
And it's different from the data streams API that is available in the SDKs.
The Kinesis Data Streams API helps you manage many aspects of KDS
including creating streams, resharding, and putting and getting records.
The KCL provides a layer of abstraction
specifically for processing data in a consumer role.
So let's say we have a Kinesis Data Stream and here we have our various shards.
We then have EC2 instances running the KCL worker.
KCL enumerates the shards and instantiates
a record processor for each shard that it manages.
We can see that these KCL workers may have multiple record processes.
Each shard is processed by exactly one KCL
worker and has exactly one corresponding record processor.
So you don't ever need to have multiple instances to process one shard.
But one worker can process any number of shards.
So it's okay if the number of shards exceeds the number of instances.
So to visualize that we have our Kinesis Data Stream with multiple shards,
we have a couple of KCL workers each with multiple record processes.
As I said, each shard is processed by exactly one KCL worker.
So each of those record processes maps to one shard.
And that's it for KCL. I'll see you in the next lesson