In this lesson, you're going to learn about the Amazon OpenSearch service, also known as Elasticsearch.
So the opensearch service is the successor to Amazon Elasticsearch Service.
Now, don't worry if you see one name or the other in exam questions because the concepts I'm going
to teach you are the same for both.
So what is it?
Well, it's a fully managed service that you can use for searching, visualizing and analyzing text
and unstructured data.
It's petabyte scale and it's secure so you can deploy it into an Amazon VPC.
Integrate with IAM and you can encrypt at rest and in transit.
It's also highly available and scalable.
Now you deploy nodes and replicas into and across availability zones, and we'll go into that in a bit
more depth.
later on.
So it's a distributed search and analytics suite.
It's based on the popular open source elastic search service, and it supports queries using SQL syntax
and integrates with open source tools.
Now you scale by adding or removing instances.
It's not a surplus service.
You're using the underlying EC2 service for running your open search.
We have availability in up to free availability zones, and you can back it up using snapshots.
You can also enable encryption at rest and in transit.
Now, how do we deploy open search?
Well, you create a cluster, you can do so through the management console, the API or the CLI.
Now, a cluster is also known as an opensearch service domain.
You specify the number of instances and the instance types, and you can have storage options, including
ultra warm or cold storage, depending on your needs.
So the next thing is, once we've deployed our cluster, we need some data so that we can use that for
populating our open search cluster and then searching and analyzing it.
So data can come from various different sources, including Kinesis Data, Firehose, Log Stash and
the ElasticSearch, an open search APIs.
So data gets ingested from these different sources.
Now, we might then use an open source tool like Cabana to search, visualize and analyze that data
by pointing Cabana Dashboard at the open search service.
As I mentioned before, we can deploy our open search cluster into a VPC, so that will allow secure
intra VPC communications.
If you've got your other components of your solution inside a VPC, then it means you never have to
traverse outside the VPC.
Now, a VPN or proxy will be required to connect from the internet, whereas public domains are directly
accessible.
So if you deploy in a public domain, then you can directly access your cluster from
the internet.
Otherwise, if you deploy in a VPC, you'll need a VPN or proxy service.
When you deploy your open search cluster into a VPC, you cannot use IP based access policies.
Now there's also some other limitations of VPC deployments.
You can't switch from a VPC deployment to a public endpoints.
And the reverse is also true.
You also can't launch your domain within a VPC that uses dedicated tenancy.
After you place a domain within a VPC, you can't then move it to a different VPC.
But if you need to, you can change the subnets and security group settings within the VPC.
Now there's another concept you need to understand for exam questions, and that's the elk stack. elk
stands for ElasticSearch, LogStash and Kibana.
So that's where you're actually combining these different services together.
So let's say we have an open search service domain.
We have logstash and that is ingesting data into open search.
Then Kibana is actually used as the dashboard to then perform that search and analytics on the data
that's in our open search cluster.
This is a very popular combination of different projects, and you can use this to aggregate logs from
systems and applications and analyze them and create visualizations as well.
Use cases include visualizing application and infrastructure, monitoring, data troubleshooting and
security analytics.
Let's have a look at access control with open search, so we've got a few different options.
We've got resource based policies and these are called domain access policies.
Identity based policies which get attached to users or roles are the same as with any other kind of
identity based access that we've looked at in the course.
And then we have IP based policy to remember you can't use these if you're using a cluster of apps.
These restrict access to one or more IP addresses or side blocks.
And then lastly, we have fine grained access control.
Now this will provide role based access control gives you security at the index document and field level
open search dashboards, multi-tenancy and HTTP based authentication for opensearch and opensearch
dashboards.
We then have the authentication options.
These include using federation with SAML, so the security assertion markup language to on-premises
directories.
So maybe if you have an Active Directory on-premises, you can federate using SAML.
You can use Amazon Cognito with social identity providers as well.
Lastly, I'm going to cover some opensearch best practices now.
This is really important to understand because these do come up quite a lot and in some questions.
So one best practice is that you should deploy your opensearch data instances across three availability
zones for the best availability.
You should provision your instances in multiples of three for equal distribution across AZs.
And if three AZ are not available, as is the case in some regions, then use to AZs with equal
numbers of instances.
You should use three, dedicated masternodes, configure at least one replica for each index and apply
restrictive resource based access policies to the domain so you can use that all fine grained access
control.
You should create the domain within an Amazon VPC and for sensitive data, enable nodes to
node Encryption and encryption at rest.
Now that's it for opensearch.
Now remember, open search and ElasticSearch are essentially the same thing.
So if you see even those names in the exam, then the concepts in this lesson will apply the same.
Now it does come up in quite a few exam questions these days, but they shouldn't be too difficult,
and you certainly don't need strong hands on knowledge of ElasticSearch or open search, as it's now
called.
Instead, just understand the concepts in this lesson, and that should do you quite well for the exam.