Welcome to the exam cram for databases and analytics.
So RDS uses easy to instances and you need to choose an instance, family and type
relational databases are known as structured, query language or SQL databases.
RDS is an online transaction processing O L T P type of database. It's easy to set up.
Highly available. Fault tolerant and scalable.
Common use cases include online stores and banking systems.
You can encrypt your RDS instances and the snapshots at
rest by enabling the encryption option for your DB instance
and that must be during creation
encryption uses the KMs service.
RDS scales up by increasing the instant size so compute and storage is allocated.
Read replicas are an option for read heavy workloads
and that scales out reads and queries.
Disaster recovery is available with the multi az option
encryption at rest can be enabled that includes the dB storage, the backups,
the read replicas and snapshots.
You can only enable encryption for your dB when
you create it and not after the instance is created
instances that are encrypted can't be modified to disable encryption.
RDS for oracle and sequel server are also supported using T D E but that might have
a performance impact on your database.
Kms is used for managing the encryption keys.
You can't have
an encrypted read replica of an unencrypted DB instance
or an unencrypted read replica of an encrypted dB instance.
Read replicas of encrypted primary instances are encrypted
the same. Kms key is used if in the same region as the primary
and if the read replicas in a different region. A different KMs key is used.
You cannot restore an unencrypted backup or snapshot to an encrypted dB instance
elastic cache is a fully managed implementation of either read this or mem cache D.
It's a key value store.
It's an in memory database gives you high performance and low latency.
You can put it in front of other databases such as RDS or dynamodb
Elastic Cache known to run on Ec two. So you got to choose an instant family and type
data is not persistent with mem cache de but it can be with Reedus
encryption can only be enabled with Reedus.
Mem cache D is the only option for multithreaded applications.
Cashing options include lazy loading, which loads data only when necessary.
If a cache miss occurs
and that results
in higher latency for reads
or you can use right through.
In that case the cash is updated whenever a new write or update is made
to the underlying database,
that results in higher latency for rights
with kinesis data streams,
producers send data to kinesis and data is stored in shards for 24 hours
Or up to seven days,
consumers then take the data and process it and
data can then be saved into another service.
You get real time with latency of 200 milliseconds.
The kinesis client library helps you consume and
process data from a kinesis data stream.
Each shard is processed by exactly one K C.
L worker and has exactly one corresponding record processor,
one worker can process any number of shards
so it's fine If the number of shards exceeds
the number of instances
producers send data to kinesis
data. Firehose
there are no chance. It's completely automated and scalability is elastic.
Firehose data is sent to another service
for storing and data can be optionally processed
or transformed using lambda.
It gives you near real time delivery with about 60 seconds of latency
kinesis data analytics provides real time
sequel processing for your streaming data.
K D A provides analytics for data coming
in from kinesis data streams or data firehose.
K. D A destinations can be data streams.
Data firehose or AWS lambda
amazon. Open Search is a distributed search and analytics suite.
It's based on the popular open source elasticsearch.
Open search supports queries using sequel syntax.
It integrates with open source tools and scales by adding or removing instances.
It's available in up to free availability zones
and you can back it up using snapshots.
It offers encryption at rest and in transit
clusters are created using the management console,
the A.
P I or the Cli.
And they are also known as open search service domains.
Now let's look at some best practices for open search.
You should use free dedicated master notes.
Can figure at least one replica for each index
and apply restrictive resource based access policies to
the domain or use fine grained access control.
You should create the domain within an amazon VPc
and lastly for sensitive data,
enable no two known encryption and encryption at rest,
and that's it for this exam crime.