Welcome to this section in this section there's
coverage of quite a lot of different services.
We're going to look at the application integration services,
we're going to look at some services
you can use for creating event driven architectures
as well as a P. I. S.
So with the application integration services we have services
such as the amazon simple queue service sqs.
Now that's a really important one to understand for
the exam does come up in lots of questions,
so we've got quite a long theory lesson on SQS
and also it's covered in lots of hands on lessons.
S and S. The simple notification service comes up as well.
Not in as much detail though.
Well look at amazon event bridge which you can use for creating a venture of
an architecture so you can say that when a certain event happens in one service
then you need to do something else. So execute something.
I also cover step functions which
is used for orchestrating various different processes
as part of a visual workflow. Quite an interesting service.
Another service that's important to understand and I have to
go into quite a bit of detail on this one
is the amazon Api gateway. So api gateway is used for creating
different types of API like HTTP APIs
and REST APIs
And it does require quite a bit of understanding for the exams,
so we'll go into lots of detail there.
Now all of this is going to be put into practice, we will be creating APIs
And microservices and using application integration services
to connect different application components together.
So lots of really interesting hands on lessons. Hope you enjoy them.