In this lesson, I'm going to cover the Simple Notification Service in a bit more detail.
So SNS is all about sending notifications.
It's a publisher/subscriber system. So, we have a publisher and that publisher will produce some kind
of information that it sends to an SNS topic.
SNS will then forward via different transport protocols to the subscribers.
So, a transport protocol is something like HTTP or an email or an SMS text message.
There's a few different options to use. And then the subscriber is the actual service or endpoint where
the information is received.
So, for example, if 100 users subscribe to a topic via email, all of those 100 users will receive
any message that gets published to the SNS topic.
Now, as subscribers, you can also have things like Lambda functions, SQS queues, or web applications.
Amazon SNS is highly available, durable, secure, and a fully managed publisher/subscriber messaging
service.
It provides what we call a topic for high throughput, push-based, many-to-many messaging.
Now, the push-based is really important to understand as it's opposed to SQS.
So, whenever you see SQS or SNS side by side, remember, with SQS, it's a pull-based mechanism where the
consumer pulls the message from the queue.
It polls the queue,
if there's a message there, it will process that message. Whereas with SNS, it's push-based. The notification
goes to the topic and then it's immediately forwarded to all of the subscribers.
With SNS, you can fan out messages to a large number of subscriber endpoints.
And those include SQS queues, Lambda functions, HTTP or HTTPS webhooks, mobile push, and SMS. And also,
of course, email.
Multiple recipients get grouped using a topic, so the topic is the key component you need to understand,
and it's an access point for allowing those recipients to subscribe to receive notifications.
One topic can support deliveries to multiple endpoint types as well.
SNS uses simple APIs, and there's really easy integration with many applications. And we've seen
that so far in the course. And we'll keep on using SNS for a few more of the hands-on lessons as
well.
You get flexible delivery over multiple transport protocols.
There's an architectural pattern that comes up in exam questions quite a lot. And that is where we have
Amazon SNS with SQS
fan out. What this means is that you subscribe one or more SQS queues to
an SNS topic. SQS manages the subscription and any necessary permissions.
And when you publish a message to the topic, SNS will send that message to every subscribed queue.
So, it looks something like this.
We have an SNS topic and we have multiple subscribed queues. And we're fanning out the notifications
that come in to those different queues.