Hi guys. In this hands-on lesson, we have a fun little exercise which is
to create a very simple serverless application.
So our application is going to include SNS.
And we're going to simulate an application sending a notification to the SNS topic.
Of course the application could be another Lambda function,
could be something non serverless like EC2.
But we're going to add that manually.
Then SNS is going to send that information as a message into an Amazon SQS queue.
Then Lambda is going to poll that queue using an event source mapping.
And Lambda will find the message in the queue
and then it's going to send some information through to CloudWatch
logs where we can then go and look at it.
So that's how it works. Very simple.
So let's head over to the console and build this out.
I'm starting off in the Simple Notification Service. Let's go to topics,
create topic.
We're going to choose a standard type and it's simply going to be called SNS to SQS
test.
And that's really all I need to do. Just create that topic.
So now we have our topic.
We then need to create a Lambda function. So let's choose create function.
I'm going to call this one SQS SNS test function. It will be Node.js.
And let's just allow it to create the default execution role.
So we create that function.
Now we will need to provide permissions so that Lambda is able to access SQS.
So that's one of the first things we need to do once the function is created.
So our function is created.
I'm going to go to configuration, permissions, click on the role name
that brings me into IAM.
And under permissions, I'm going to add permissions, attach a policy
and I'm going to search for the AWS Lambda SQS queue execution role
and select that policy.
Now that policy will provide Lambda the permissions to receive messages,
delete messages, and get queue attributes
as well as also providing access to CloudWatch logs.
We already have those permissions so we don't need
those but we do need the SQs permissions.
So that's good. Let's attach this policy.
And now Lambda has the write permissions.
Now we need to update the code. So let's go back to Lambda.
Let's go to code
and we have a file which provides the code we need for this exercise.
So in the course download, we've got the code directory Amazon SQS
and you'll find Lambda code SNS SQs.
So just copy all of this code to your clipboard.
And back in our function, let's delete everything out, paste this in,
and click on deploy.
So that's done. Okay, so we have the write permissions.
So what I'm going to do now is go to SQS
and you'll see we have Lambda triggers and SNS subscriptions.
So let's start with the SNS subscription.
Lets subscribe to an Amazon SQS topic.
We can find our topic here. Mine is called SNS SQS test.
Click on save.
That's done.
Then go to Lambda triggers.
Configure Lambda function trigger.
And let's find our function.
Mine is called SQS SNS test function.
And click on save.
So that's all worked. That shouldn't take long to actually complete.
And if you come back to your Lambda function, you should now see SQS as a trigger.
So what we're gonna do now is simply test this out. So let's come back to
the SNS console.
I've selected my topic.
And I'm going to click on publish message.
I'm going to call this message from SNS.
And I can enter a message body.
So mine is going to be this message was sent from SNS.
And let's publish that message.
So the message has been published to the topic.
And that means it should now be pushed through to the queue
and then the SQS queue will be polled by Lambda
and Lambda should then run its code.
And the code should then take the information from the SNS message
and it's going to record that in CloudWatch logs.
So that's where we have this console.log body. So it's gonna log that information
to CloudWatch logs.
So if I go to monitor,
view logs in cloudwatch logs,
choose my stream,
and here we can see that we have some messages.
So we can see one from earlier on the
test long short polling that was already in the queue.
And we can see that the topic ARN is specified here.
The subject message from SNS was recorded and the message body
this message was sent from SNS.
So that's been successful.
Now I have actually finished with this application.
So what I'm gonna do is just go back in. I can delete my queue now
and I can also delete my Lambda function and my SNS topic if I want to.
I don't need to delete them.
They're not going to cost anything. But I've cleaned up my queue.
So that's it for this lesson. I hope you enjoyed it. I will see you in the next one.