Amazon EventBridge is a serverless event bus. And it's useful for building distributed event-driven
applications.
It can react to state changes in resources including AWS resources and also non-AWS resources
as well.
Now, it used to be known as Amazon CloudWatch Events.
You can still find CloudWatch Events in the CloudWatch console, but you also find EventBridge as
a separate service within AWS.
So let's see what we can do with EventBridge. Now,
with EventBridge, we have our event sources.
They can be AWS services, custom applications or some kind of third-party SAS-based application.
State changes to those resources get sent as events to what we call an EventBridge event bus.
The information is then processed by rules. And those rules can then send information through to various
destinations like Lambda functions, Kinesis data streams, or AWS Config. And those are known as targets.
Let's have a look at an example.
Let's say we have EC2 as an event source and an event happens. And that event is a termination event
of an EC2 instance That gets forwarded to the EventBridge event bus,
a rule gets processed, and that rule then gets sent through to a destination.
In this case, an SNS topic. And so, an SNS notification gets sent through to an email address.
With this example, we might have a configuration that looks much like this.
We've defined a pattern by service.
We're using AWS as a service provider, EC2, and as a state change.
The specific state is terminated.
And in this case, we've specified a specific instance ID.
Now, the result will look something like this. So, we'll see some information recorded that can then
be utilized.
In another example, we have AWS CloudTrail as a source.
Now, CloudTrail is a service that monitors API actions for auditing.
In this case, information gets forwarded through about an API event, and it's an S3 PUT bucket policy
event. So, somebody has added a policy to an S3 bucket.
So, what's going to happen is a rule gets processed and that rule is then going to send information to
a target.
And again, this could be an email address.
Now, we're going to see both of these examples in this course.
Example one is going to be in the very next lesson.