In this lesson you're going to learn about the structure of an API
including the methods, integrations and mapping templates as well as more.
So let's get started with what are called methods and resources.
Now a resource represents a path in your API.
So in the example, API on the right hand side here are pet store API.
You'll see some resources.
And that's where we have a path specified.
So a slash then slash pets then slash and then a variable for the pet ID.
Methods are created within resources.
So these are the methods.
You'll recognize these as HTTP methods. So Get, Options, Put,
and there are more as well.
A method represents a client-facing interface by which the client
caused the API to access backend resources.
So for example the client would issue an HTTP Get request and then the API
would allow that if the Get method was enabled for the path that has been called
and then forward that request on to the backend.
A method is created for a specific HTTP verb or you can use Any to allow all methods.
We then have methods and integration. So let's look at a published API.
Users connect to the published API, we then have our method request.
This is where we specify the methods that we want to allow.
So it could be one or more of these.
And here you can see the ARN for the Get method.
Next we have something called the integration request.
So this determines how we're actually integrating with the backend service.
Either HTTP, HTTP proxy, Lambda, Lambda proxy, or mock.
So this maps the request parameters of the method request
to the format that is required by the backend.
And then we have our backend endpoint
which could be something like a Lambda function,
HTTP endpoint, EC2 or some other AWS service.
After the request has been processed by the backend,
the integration response is called on the path back to the client.
Here you can either convert or pass through the response.
Then we have the method response which has HTTP status codes
and response bodies.
So here we are mapping the status codes,
headers and payload that's received from the backend
into a format that we can present back to the client.
So that's essentially the structure of an API.
So let's look at method requests and responses.
A method resource is integrated with an integration resource.
So firstly we have the method request.
This is the public interface of a REST API method
in API gateway that defines the parameters and body
that an app developer must send in requests
to access the backend through the API
Then you've got the response.
The public interface of a REST API that defines the status codes,
headers, and body models that an app developer should expect in responses
from the API.
So this is all about ensuring that in our requests
and our responses we all speaking the right language.
API methods are integrated with backend endpoints using API integrations.
Backend endpoints are known as integration endpoints.
So we have firstly the integration request.
This is the internal interface of a Websocket API route
or rest API method in API Gateway.
It maps the body of a route request or the parameters and body of
a method request to the formats that are required by your backend.
And then in the integration response this is the internal interface
of a Websocket API route or a rest API method
in API Gateway and it maps the status codes,
headers, and payload that are received in the backend to the response
that's required by the actual client application.
So let's look at the integration types.
You can choose various integration types according
to the type of integration endpoint you're working
with and how you want to process and pass data to and from the integration endpoint.
For a Lambda function you've got the options
of a Lambda proxy integration or a Lambda custom integration.
For an HTTP endpoint you can have the
HTTP proxy integration or the HTTP custom integration.
For an AWS service action, you only have the option of the non-proxy type.
API Gateway also supports the mock integration where API gateway serves
as an integration endpoint to respond to a method request.
So let's have a look at the various integration types in a bit more detail.
Firstly, here we have the AWS option.
This integration let's an API expose AWS service actions.
You need to configure the integration request and response
and set up data mapping from the method request to the
integration request and the integration response to the method response.
Next we have AWS proxy.
This integration relies on direct interactions between
the client and the integrated Lambda function.
So this is actually a Lambda proxy type. AWS proxy.
With this type of integration that's also known as Lambda proxy integration
you don't need to set the integration request or the integration response.
API Gateway passes the incoming request from the client
as the input to the backend Lambda function.
The integrated Lambda function takes the input of this
format and passes the input from all available sources
including information such as in the request headers,
the URL path variables, query string parameters, and the applicable body.
The function returns to result following this output format.
So here is a diagram showing what this looks like.
Here we actually have the Lambda proxy specified as the integration request.
Next we have HTTP.
This type of integration let's an API expose HTTP endpoints in the backend.
With the HTTP integration also known as the HTTP custom integration,
you need to configure both the integration request and the integration response.
And you have to set up the data mappings
from the method request to the integration request and from the integration response
to the method response.
And this is what this might look like. We've got HTTP or HTTP_proxy.
Lastly we have mock.
This let's API gateway return a response without
sending the request further to the backend.
It's used for testing integration set up
without incurring charges for using the backend
and to enable collaborative development of an API.
Teams can also isolate their development efforts by setting up simulations
of API components owned by other teams using mock integrations.
So more of a testing use case rather than any kind of production implementation.
Next, let's look in more detail at what are called mapping templates.
An API's method request can take a payload
in a different format from the corresponding integration request payload
as required in the backend.
Also the backend may return an integration response
in a different format from the method
response payload that's expected by the frontend.
Mapping templates come in really handy here.
They map the payload from the method request
to the corresponding integration request and the integration response
to the corresponding method response.
Mapping templates are scripts based in what's
called the velocity template language or VTL
and they're applied to the payload using JSON path expressions.
So looking at an example here of the structure of an API,
let's say we need to convert some JSON XML.
And we can use code to do that and we specify
what we're going to do using a mapping template.
And that's it for this lesson. I will see you in the next one.