Hi guys. In this lesson we're going to create an API using Amazon API gateway
and it's going to use a Lambda proxy integration.
So the first thing we're going to do is create our Lambda function.
So you can see some code on your screen here.
Now, you'll find this in the code directory of the course download
Amazon API Gateway Rest API Lambda Proxy.
So I'm going to copy all of this code to my clipboard.
And back on the Lambda console, I'm going to create a new function.
I'll call this Rest API With Lambda proxy.
Run time is going to be Node.js. Let's create our function.
And the function is being created. So let's delete out the code here,
paste in our code and click on deploy.
Now let's go over to API Gateway.
On the API gateway console I'm going to click on get started.
Now, you'll see that there's the different types of API we can create.
We've got HTTP API, Websocket API,  REST API,
and another one which is a private REST API.
We're going to choose this REST API here.
The one that has Lambda, HTTP, and AWS services options,
but this is not a private one.
It's actually going to be a regional API.
So let's click on build, click on OK for the message here.
Now we could always flick to a Websocket. We're going to keep with REST.
It does come up with an example API.
Alternatively, you can import from Swagger or OpenAPI three.
But we're going to choose new API.
And I'm going to call mine Lambda Simple Proxy.
And it's going to have a regional endpoint type.
Of course, if you wanted to you could change it here to edge-optimized or private.
So let's leave it on regional and create our API.
Now that we've created the API, we have several options
for how we can configure our API.
Now the first thing is we want to create a resource.
So for the resource I'm going to put in Hello World.
We don't need to change anything else. Let's just create that resource.
Next we need to create a method, so we choose actions,
create method and it will be created under the Hello World resource.
So we have /Hello world and then which of the actions do we want to allow?
Which methods?
So you know, you can see here you've got Any which is any action, you've got Get,
Post, Put and so on.
Now we're going to choose Any.
Click on the little tick mark.
And as you can see we now have our various integration. So Lambda, HTTP, Mock,
AWS services, and VPC link. We're going to leave it on Lambda.
The region is correct as us-east-1.
And if I just type space, I will now see my Lambda functions.
So I'm going to choose the REST API with Lambda proxy.
And we do want this to be a proxy integration.
So that means the information that's received will get proxies
straight through the Lambda without any kind of modification.
So let's choose save.
And click on OK to accept the API Gateway is going to
be given permissions to invoke the Lambda function.
So our API is now ready for deployment.
What I'm going to do is choose actions
and deploy API.
So now we get to deploy our API to a stage.
So for example, I can create a new stage and let's call this one Prod.
Optionally, you can give it a stage description and a deployment description.
Let's click on deploy.
And that has been deployed.
So now we get an invoke URL.
Now what I want to do is copy this one to my clipboard.
You'll find this file in the course download as well.
So this is the URL that we're going
to construct in order to invoke our Hello World application.
So as you can see where it says API in capitals,
this is actually where I want the URL to go.
So I already actually copied right from HTTPS. So let's paste that in.
Now, I've also got /prod which is the stage.
So I don't need the stage written again.
So what you should have is the full URL which finishes in .com/prod/
and then Hello world.
Then there's a question mark, name equals, so I'm going to put my name in here.
City equals. Well, my nearest city is Miami. So let's put Miami in here.
And then I'm going to copy this to my clipboard.
And in a new browser window,
I'm going to paste that in and hit enter.
So I get all this response.
It's a bit messy but there's lots of information in here.
But at the beginning you can see message Good day Neal of Miami.
So that is essentially what the API is returning based on Lambda.
So Lambda is actually processing the information that we pass to it, which is
just my name and my city.
And the Lambda functions process that and then return this result to us.
So that's how we can invoke the API using the URL.
Now the other way is to use curl. So I do use a Mac machine
and Mac and Linux normally come with curl installed.
If you're using Windows then you might need to download the curl utility.
But what I need to do here again is enter some information.
So as you can see we've got the API stage Hello world.
So I'm going to copy from HTTPS
through to where my stage name is slash
and I'm going to copy that here,
paste that here rather.
So now we have HTTPS going through to .com/prod/. Should just be one slash
Hello World.
And again we're going to put in,
I'm gonna put it Neal.
I'm going to put in Miami
and then it says the day, so let's put in the day. So today is Wednesday
and the time of day is afternoon.
So that's my command.
So I'll copy this command to my clipboard and go to a command prompt.
So make sure you do have the curl utility.
I have the curl utility installed so I can run this command.
So again the response has lots of information and just here we can see message.
Good afternoon Neal of Miami. Happy Wednesday.
So that's it. That's how we can create an API with a Lambda proxy integration.
So that's it for this lesson.
I'm not going to delete my API at this stage because
we are going to work with it in another lesson.