In this lesson, I'm going to cover usage plans and API keys.
And I'll start off with a diagram to show you how we can use these two elements.
So let's say we have an API.
And we've got two different classes of user.
We've got our basic users and we've got our premium users who pay more money.
So what we want to do here is we're going to create two different usage plans.
One's called premium and one's called basic.
And we're going to configure different settings for the different usage plans.
So for example, the premium usage plan is going to have higher rates
and bursts enabled, so we're giving more throughput for the premium plan
and increasing the quotas for requests a minute.
So what happens then is we need to identify who our users are when they connect.
For that we use an API key.
So the users connect the specific public endpoint with an API key that's configured
in a usage plan.
So they're both connected to the same endpoint
but they have different API keys included in their request.
Then we can identify who they are and forward them on to different stages.
So here we have a production V1 stage and a V2 stage.
And then we might have different endpoints on the backend as well.
You can also configure per method throttling limits.
So you might have it at the method level as well as at the API level.
Usage plans specify who can access one or more deployed API stages and methods
and how much and how fast they can access them.
You can use a usage plan to configure throttling and quota limits
which are then enforced on individual client API keys.
The plan uses the API keys to identify the API clients
so we know who they are and we can associate them
with the correct plan that we want to connect them to.
And it meters access to the associated API stages for each key.
It also lets you configure throttling limits
and quota limits that are enforced on those individual client API keys.
Lastly, you can use API keys together with
usage plans or Lambda authorizers to control access to your APIs.