Welcome to this lesson. So let's look into Access Control With API Gateway.
So there are several mechanisms for controlling and managing access to an API.
We've got resource-based policies which we can attach to our API.
We've got identity-based policies which of course apply to users, groups, and roles.
We've got IAM tags and we've got endpoint policies for interface VPC endpoints.
We've also got Lambda authorizers, so we can use Lambda
for authorizing access to our published APIs.
And we have Amazon Cognito user pools.
First, let's look at resource-based policy.
API Gateway resource-based policies are JSON policy documents that you attach
to your API.
They control whether a specified principal is able to invoke the API.
So we have our published API.
We might have other accounts or resources in a VPC or CIDR block or IP ranges.
And we can control access to any of those based on the permissions policy.
Then when policy evaluation is taking place, we can either grant or deny access.
And that's based on those different sources.
So the account that the request is coming from,
the VPC or VPC endpoint that it's coming from, or the CIDR block or IP range
that the request is coming from.
If the request passes validation,
then the user or the service is granted access to the endpoint
and the API is securely invoked.
So let's have a look at an example resource-based policy.
First we would have the permission.
That could be either allow or deny.
Then the supported operations.
So those are the execution operations we want to either grant or deny access to.
And then lastly the ARN of the deployed API.
Next up we have Lambda authorizers.
This is a feature that uses a Lambda function to control access to the API.
API Gateway calls the Lambda authorizer which takes the caller's identity
as input and then returns an IAM policy as output.
There's two types of authorizers.
We've got a token-based Lambda authorizer,
this receives the caller's identity in a bearer token
such as a JSON Web Token, JWT or an OAuth token.
Also we have a request parameter based Lambda authorizer
which receives the caller's identity in a combination of headers,
query string parameters, stage variables and context variables.
For Websocket APIs,
only request parameter-based authorizers are actually supported.
So let's see visually how this works.
In step one of my diagram, the client calls
the API method passing bearer token or request parameters.
Then API Gateway calls the Lambda authorizer.
Then the Lambda function authenticates the user.
It can call OAuth provider to get token.
It can call a SAML provider to get an assertion
and it can generate an IAM policy based on request parameters.
If successful Lambda then grants and returns an IAM policy
and a principal identify.
API Gateway then evaluates the policy.
If access is allowed, it will execute the method.
If access is denied, it will return a status code 403.
We then have user pool authorizers with Cognito.
A user pool is a user directory in Amazon Cognito.
With a user pool, users can sign into a web or mobile app through Cognito.
Users can also sign in through social identity providers like Google, Facebook,
Amazon or Apple and through SAML identity providers.
You can also use a user pool to control who can access your API
in Amazon API gateway.
And to do that, you create an authorizer of the Cognito user pools type
and then configure an API method to use that authorizer.
So let's have a look at our diagram.
We have a Cognito user pool here which can
use a local account or a Federated Identity.
The users who want to connect to the API authenticate
using the user pool and get tokens.
In this case it's a JSON Web Token, a JWT that's returned.
Then they're able to access the API.
So that's the basic setup of using a JWT token with a Cognito user pool authorizer.