Welcome to the exam cram for application integration and A P. I. S.
So let's get into it
amazon SQs is pull based and it's not push based like S. And S. S.
Messages are up to 256 kilobytes in size,
larger messages can be sent using the SQs extended client library. For java
Messages can be kept in the queue from one minute up to 14 days.
The default retention period is four days.
SqS guarantees that your messages will be processed at least once.
A standard Q. Offers best effort ordering and at least once delivery
folk use on the other hand offer first in first out ordering
and exactly once processing
the main task of a dead letter queue is handling message failure.
A dead letter queue lets you set aside
and isolate messages that can't be processed correctly.
It's not a Q. Type, it's a standard or a fee fo Q. That's been specified
as being a dead letter queue,
messages are moved to the dead letter queue when the received
count for a message exceeds the max received count for a Q
delay queues, added delay to processing of the messages.
The visibility time out is the amount of time a message
is invisible in the queue after a reader picks it up.
If the job's not processed within the visibility.
Time out the message will become visible again
and another reader can then process it
SQs. Long polling
is a way to retrieve messages from sqs queues and it waits for messages to arrive.
So as you're performing the aPI action, it stays open until the message arrives.
Short polling, on the other hand, returns immediately. Even if the queue is empty.
Long polling can lower costs because
fewer api actions.
Long polling can be enabled at the Q level or at the aPI level.
Using the wait time seconds parameter
long polling is in effect when the received message wait time
is a value greater than zero seconds up to a maximum of 20.
You could use s free with the SQs extended
client library for java to manage SQS messages.
Remember the ones that are bigger than 2 56 kilobytes.
So that's useful for storing and consuming messages that can be up to 2GB
in size.
SNS is a highly available durable,
secure and fully managed pub sub messaging service.
So publisher subscriber
sns provides topics for high free put, push based many to many messaging,
multiple recipients can be grouped using a topic.
You can subscribe one or more sqs queues
to an sns. Topic.
Step functions is used to build distributed applications
as a series of steps in a visual workflow
and you can quickly build and run state
machines to execute the steps of your application.
Event bridge was formerly known as amazon cloudwatch events.
It's a serverless event bus.
It's used to build event driven applications.
Event sources can be aWS services or third party applications
rules are run based on events and routed to targets.
Moving on to api Gateway.
It supports rest A P I. S.
They support Oh I D C and O of two,
authorization and come with built in support for cause and automatic deployments.
Also H T T P A P I s
designed for low latency cost effective integrations with AWS services
such as lambda
and also http endpoints.
We then have Websocket API s.
These are deployed as a state full front end for an AWS service
such as lambda or dynamo DB or for an http endpoint
Rest Apis. And http API support authorizes for AWS lander,
I am and Cognito
and Websocket API support I am authorization and lambda authorizes
an edge optimized API endpoint is best
for geographically distributed clients.
API requests are routed to the nearest cloudfront point of presence.
A regional API endpoint is intended for clients in the same region
that will reduce connection overhead for connections that come from that region.
Private rest API's can only be accessed from within the VPc
using an interface. VPc. Endpoint.
A resource represents a path in your A P I
and methods are created within resources.
A method Resources integrated with an integration. Resource
deployments are a snapshot of the API's. Resources and methods,
deployments must be created and associated with a stage
for anyone to access. The A P I
A stage is a logical reference to a life cycle, state of your rest or websocket api
such as Deb or prod or B- two or B- two.
You can add cash into API calls by provisioning and
API Gateway cash and you need to specify its size
in gigabytes
caches are defined per stage. API Gateway sets a limit on a steady state rate
and a burst of request submissions against all a p i. S in your account.
It can also apply service side throttling limits and per client throttling limits.
They're implemented using aPI keys associated with a usage policy.
That's it for this exam, cram see you in the next lesson.