Hi guys, this is the first of several hands-on lessons for Amazon S3.
And in this lesson we're simply going to go and have a look at how we can create
an Amazon S3 bucket using the management console.
I'm in the management console for Amazon S3 and here you'll
be able to see your buckets if you already have some.
Now we don't actually have any in this particular account.
So what I'm going to do is click on create buckets.
Now, the first thing we need to do is give it a bucket name.
Now you'll notice that with S3, this is a global service so you can't choose a region
and that's because the namespace for Amazon S3 uses DNS and is therefore global.
So just like you can only have one Amazon.com,
you can only have one bucket name globally.
It uses DNS.
So we have to create a bucket name that's completely unique around the world.
There's no other S3 buckets with that specific name.
So for example, I'm going to call mine DCT Cloud S3 HOL,
and hopefully that is unique around the world.
Now if you want to use a similar name,
you can always just add on some random characters at the end.
Now, even though it is a global namespace,
you do actually select where your data is going to be stored.
So you can select the region and your data will be stored within that region only.
Now your data is never replicated outside of that region
unless you specifically enable that to happen.
So here, I'm going to choose us-east-1.
If you want to you can choose another bucket and it will actually copy the settings
from that bucket across.
In this case we're not going to do that.
Next there's objects ownership.
This is specifying whether ACLs, Access Control Lists
are enabled or not for this bucket.
It's a relatively new setting.
So this didn't used to be here, but it's been here for several months now.
What I want to do is actually enable ACLs. They are useful for some specific use cases
and we will be doing a hands-on where we use ACLs a bit later on.
So I'm going to leave those enabled with bucket owner preferred, the default option.
And then let's go down a little bit further.
Now, AWS is trying to enforce default security.
So one of the things they do is they block all public access by default.
So if for example you wanted the contents of your bucket to be available
for anyone in the world who is not authenticated,
then you would need to disable this setting.
And that way you would enable the ability
to have your contents of your buckets publicly accessible.
And then you can actually use the ACLs or other settings to
make sure that they are available.
And that's something we'll look at later on.
For now, I'm going to leave the default setting.
Bucket versioning is a feature where it will keep
multiple variants of the files that you upload to S3.
So for example, if you uploaded a word document
and then you made some modifications to that document,
saved it with the same file name and then uploaded that to S3,
you would now actually have two versions.
So you could go back to the older version if you needed to.
You can enable tags and you can also specify encryption for your bucket.
We're going to look at that as well later on.
Now I'm happy with these settings. So I'm just going to create my bucket.
So my bucket has been successfully created.
You can see the name, you can see the region,
and some other information.
So what I'm going to do now is just select my bucket and let's go in
and have a look at some of the settings.
The first screen we come to is objects.
This is where you can actually upload and view the objects in your bucket.
So objects can be any type of file can be video files can be photos,
can be word documents and much, much more.
So we can easily upload our objects here.
If I click on upload
and then choose a file,
so let's choose this beach.jpg.
Click on upload.
So the file is now ready for upload.
Now we can specify the ACL permissions on this if we want to.
We'll look at that in another lesson.
And also if we click on properties here,
this is where you can specify the storage class
that your object is going to belong to.
The default is standard and that's available through three availability zones.
And of course if you want to lower the cost you can use things like One Zone-IA
Or Standard I A.
I'll just leave this on standard.
You can then specify the encryption settings for this particular object.
We can also enable checksums, tags, and metadata.
Now I'm just going to click on upload.
And that has succeeded.
And so now we have our jpeg file in the objects pane here.
Next we've got properties.
Here you can see things like the ARN for your bucket
if you need to copy that to your clipboard so you can use it somewhere.
You can change the versioning status,
add tags for the bucket rather than the objects which we just saw a moment ago.
You can specify the default encryption,
intelligent-tiering archive configs, server access logging, CloudTrail data events,
event notifications, and Amazon EventBridge.
So you can actually send information about what's
happening in your bucket to these services.
We'll look at event notifications a bit later on in this section.
You can also enable transfer acceleration and that improves
the upload speeds for your objects, but it does come at a cost.
We've got object lock, requester pays
and also static website hosting. Again, we'll look at that later on in this section.
Back at the top here, we then have the permissions pane. And in here
you can change that block public access settings, add your bucket policies.
We'll definitely look at those shortly as well.
You can modify the object ownership settings, ACLs,
and enable cross origin resource sharing.
There's also metrics about the data in your bucket.
There's a few things that we can do on the management page
including specifying our lifecycle rules if we want to specify rules for when
our data is moved between different storage classes.
There are replication rules for replicating our data
between buckets in the same or different regions,
and inventory configurations as well.
And lastly, there are access points.
So you can actually create your own named network endpoints for accessing S3.
So that's a quick overview of creating buckets and looking
at these settings that we can apply to our buckets.
And in subsequent lessons we're going to do some more hands-on working with S3.