The amazon Simple storage service,
amazon S three is an object based storage system and it features
in many different AWS exams is one of the fundamental AWS technologies
now.
It does feature quite a lot on the DVA exam,
so there's quite a few particular topics
that are very important to understand for the
exam and that's all gonna be covered in lots of detail in this section.
So quite a lot of coverage of amazon S three. Then we look at cloudfront as well.
So Cloudfront is a content delivery network at CDN.
That means it caches media assets like video,
files and images and all sorts of different types of files around
the world to get them closer to end users for better performance.
So we're going to be looking at Cloudfront in a
little bit of detail to understand how it works,
what the benefits are and what settings you need to understand for the exam.
So that's it for now, enjoy the section, I'll see you in the next lesson.