There are a few ways that we can control access to our buckets and the objects that we store within
our S3 buckets.
So, in this lesson, I'm going to walk you through
IAM policies, bucket policies, and access control lists.
And then in the next couple of lessons we'll do hands-on to see these in action as well.
So firstly, we have policies created in the Identity and Access Management service.
Now, these are identity-based policies, which means that they get associated with principals like users
and roles.
So, with an IAM policy, we're directly applying the permissions that we want to assign to a principal
to that principal. Or we might be applying them to a group by attaching a policy to a group and then
adding a user into the group. We can specify what actions are allowed on what AWS resources, so we
can say that you're allowed to perform specific actions on a specific bucket, for example.
So, with I am policies, these are attached to users or groups or roles.
And remember, with a group, you attach the policy to the group and then you add the user to the group
and they will get the permissions assigned to that permissions policy.
IAM
policies are written in JSON using the AWS access policy language, and the principal element is not
required in the policy.
So, when you see one of these JSON snippets of code, if it doesn't have a principal element in it,
then that means that it could be an IAM policy that's used for S3 rather than a bucket policy.
So next, we have S3 bucket policies. And these are resource-based policies.
So, with the bucket policy, you're attaching it directly to an S3 bucket.
They can only be attached to Amazon S3 buckets and they also use the same access policy language.
So, it's still JSON, looks very much like the policies created at the identity level, but it's not a
resource instead.
So, we might have an S3 bucket,
we apply our bucket policy to it, and a bucket policy might look something like this.
So, note that there is a principal element here which specifies the specific user we want to assign these
permissions to.
There's also a resource and it specifies the bucket name.
And of course, there's an action which in this case is to, the effect is allow and the action is any
S3 action.
So, a wildcard for S3 actions.
So, in this case, Paul will be able to put an object into that S3 bucket because he's allowed through
the resource-based policy.
Lastly, we have access control lists.
These are really a legacy access control mechanism that pre-dates Identity and Access Management.
AWS generally recommends that you try and use bucket policies or IAM policies
rather than using ACLs. They can be attached to a bucket or directly to an object.
So, a bucket policy is always at the bucket level whereas an ACL can be specified at the object level
as well.
There are limited options for grantees and permissions, we'll see this in the hands-on.
It's not as powerful as using the access policy language.
So, when might you use these different access control mechanisms? You might use
IAM policies for the following use cases. Where you need to control access to AWS services other than
S3 because you can then specify whatever permissions you want to
whatever AWS service as well as the S3 bucket. You have numerous S3 buckets, each with different
permissions requirements.
So that means you're essentially controlling access to lots of different buckets using a single IAM
policy, which is, you know, centralized in the management and hopefully simplifying it.
You might just prefer to keep access control policies in the IAM environment rather than using resource-
based policies, which can be a bit harder to track.
So, you might want to use bucket policies if you want a simple way to grant cross account access to
S3 without using IAM roles. You can do that quite easily in a bucket policy.
Your IAM policies might be reaching the size limits.
There is a limit on the size of an IAM policy. So that might force you to use a bucket policy.
Or you might just prefer to keep your access control policies in the S3 environment. And that could
be down to separation of control within your organization.
It's important to understand the authorization process. So, let's walk through the logic.
The decision will always start at a deny. And then evaluates the policies and looks for explicit denies.
If there is an explicit deny, then that's the end.
The final decision is deny. Next,
if there isn't an explicit deny, we look for any allows.
If there is an allow, then the decision is to allow.
That's an explicit allow. If there isn't one, then the decision is deny.
So, that's basically the process for how authorization works.
Now, in the next lesson, we're going to look at access control lists in a hands-on,
and then we're going to look at IAM policies and bucket policies.