Hi guys, In this lesson, we're going to work with Access Control Lists.
I'm back in the S3 management console.
And we already created this bucket before.
Now in my bucket, I have this file, it's a jpeg image.
Now if I select the image, we'll see that I have an object URL.
Now let's see what happens if I try to go to that object URL.
So I'm just going to paste it into a web page here.
And what you'll see is we get this access denied error message.
So we can't actually access that object.
Now, one of the ways that we can access the object is if we update the ACL.
Now, ACLs are configured in a couple of places.
So firstly, if we go to permissions for the bucket, so now I'm at the bucket level,
and we scroll down, now, note, we do have block public access on.
But if you scroll down a little bit further, you'll see here,
we've got Access Control Lists.
Now, let's click on edit.
And you can see the settings you can apply.
Now there's only a few grantees, so you have an option of applying
Access Control List permissions to the bucket owner,
to everyone, so public access,
to authenticated users group, so that's anyone with an AWS account who's logged in,
and the S3 log delivery group and also other accounts.
So you can add a grantee and specify the canonical idea of another account.
And that means anyone coming from that
account will have whatever permissions you apply.
So these are the settings. Now it's not a huge amount.
I know sometimes in the documentation refers to how ACLs are very granular.
But of course this is nothing like as granular
as using bucket policies or user policies.
So when you apply a bucket policy you have all the power
of using JSON code and all the various different options we can configure
such as configuring whether we're allowing people access based on the IP address,
they're coming from, that kind of thing.
So you get a lot more granularity with bucket policies than you do with ACLs.
So with an ACL, we might want to for example, allow public access.
So here we can say well, for objects I'm going to enable list access.
If you want people to be able to see the bucket ACL, you can enable read here.
Now note the other options are actually grayed out.
Now, the console is warning us that by configuring these settings,
anyone in the world will be able to access these objects.
I'm okay with that. So I'm going to click I understand.
So let's see what happens when I try and save my changes.
I opened this up so I need to remove that. And let's try and save those changes.
Now I'm not able to.
And the reason for this
is because we still have that block public access setting on.
So it's not going to allow me to make these changes. So let's cancel out there.
Click on edit under block public access.
Deselect this option, click on save.
We need to confirm.
And those settings were applied.
And now we can go back to the ACL.
Click on list for everyone,
accept it, and click on save changes and now it works.
So we've done that. Does that mean that we can now come back and access our object?
Let's refresh.
And no it doesn't. We still have an access denied.
So we've enabled that setting at the bucket level,
but what we haven't done is we haven't enabled
it actually at the object level as well.
So if I click back on this object and go to permissions,
you'll see that here there are no permissions for public access.
So if I want to enable public access, I need to enable read here.
Again, I need to confirm it.
Come down, click on save changes.
Now let's go back to our objects,
click on refresh.
And this time we get a nice image.
So that's how we can work with ACL. So key things to remember are ACLs
they're not particularly granular as you can
see there's just a few different grantees.
It's different at the object level versus the bucket level.
But you only have a few different options.
So you can use these for certain use cases such as enabling public access.
They're really good for that.
They're also quite good for enabling cross account access.
The other thing to remember is that they are different between the object level
and the bucket level.
So sometimes you have to specify the settings in multiple places.
Okay, so that's it for this lesson and I'll see you in the next one.