In this lesson, we're going to work with user policies and bucket policies
to control access to Amazon S3.
Now, there are a few things you need to do for this particular lesson.
So we already have this bucket we created before.
Now, what I am going to do is go back to permissions, click on edit,
and I'm going to restore the block all public access.
So I don't actually want any public access to this bucket.
Let's click on confirm.
That's done.
If I come back to objects, we have our objects here.
And I go to permissions.
What we'll find is now that we've done that, it's removed
that ACL that allowed read access. So that's great.
So let's come back and what I'm going to do is go back up to the bucket level
and I'm going to create a couple of folders.
One is going to be called confidential.
Let's create that folder.
Create one more folder.
And this one will be called department.
And let's create that folder.
So now we have these two folders and one image.
So next I want to go back to the management console,
go to users,
we've got the second account called Paul.
And I just want to make sure that Paul doesn't have any permission.
So we don't have any groups assigned to Paul
and we don't have any policies applied to Paul. So that's great.
And you'll need to go and log in as Paul in a separate browser window.
So use a private window so that you can still stay logged in as yourself as well.
So I'm logged in as Paul.
And if I click on S3,
what we should find is that we don't have any permissions.
That's exactly what we should expect.
Now, you'll find this file in your course, downloads so go to the code directory,
Amazon S3 and then user policies and bucket policies.
Now this first policy statement here
simply allows the action S3 list all my buckets
and it uses this wild card, so this is any S3 bucket.
So let's just copy this code to our clipboard.
And back where I'm logged in as myself, under Paul's account
I'm going to add an in-line policy.
Go to JSON.
I'm going to copy over the top of this code,
paste my code in,
click on review.
We'll give it a name,
and then create the policy.
So that's done.
Now let's go back to where we logged in as Paul.
Here, I'm going to simply click refresh.
and now we can actually see the bucket.
But it's still saying insufficient permissions so we can
list it but we can't really do anything else.
If I click on the bucket name,
I can't see any of the objects including the folders inside the bucket.
So back in my JSON file, what I'm going to do now is use this second user policy.
So this one allows us to see the root level bucket items.
Now, we do need to add something in here, so we need to add in the bucket name.
So let's go back and get the ARN of our bucket.
So back in S3, let's click on properties next to our bucket,
copy the ARN.
And then in my policy here I'm just going to paste it over the top here.
So now I have that policy configured.
So I'm going to copy that to my clipboard.
And back in IAM,
what I'm going to do is just click on this policy, expand, edit,
go to JSON, and then we'll copy the code over the top.
So this policy is going to allow us to list all the buckets in the account.
So, with the wild card for the resource
and then it's going to allow us to list
the contents of the bucket for this specific bucket.
So let's review this policy.
Click on save.
Come back to where Paul's logged in.
I'm going to refresh.
Just give it a couple of refreshes
and now I can actually see the contents of the bucket.
Now, we don't have anything in here yet, but if I go in I can't find anything.
So let's go back and what I'm going to do, under S3,
I am actually going to add some content into those folders.
So let's go to confidential.
I'm going to upload,
add files, add my confidential report,
upload.
Let's go back to the other folders and that's department.
Upload.
I'm going to add another file.
And this one is going to be just the company goals.
So let's upload that document.
And we now have some files. Now, that won't make any difference to Paul.
He still won't be able to see anything because there aren't any permissions to do so.
So back in our JSON file, what we're now going to do
is we're going to enable Paul to be able to view the department folder contents.
So now we're going to need to get the ARN again.
So let's go up and I've already got it here.
So I'm just going to copy this ARN.
We've got a couple of places to put this first.
We need to put it in here.
So this is the list bucket, it's the same statement as before.
And then we also need it in here, this is the new statement that we're adding in now.
So this is going to allow the list bucket
for the specific resource which is the ARN of the bucket and then the department
folder and the contents, the /* means the contents of that folder.
So let's copy this user policy.
And I'm going to edit the policy for Paul again.
It's going to JSON.
Paste it in,
review,
and save and you get the odd warning here and there but it should work as expected.
So let's come back to Paul.
And Paul should now be able to see the contents of the department folder and he can.
Now, though Paul can see in this folder is he able to actually download
anything from the folder?
So let's try and download this file.
And we get an access denied.
Now what about uploading? Can Paul upload?
Let's try and add a file at the beach.JPEG.
Click on upload.
And again, we get an access denied.
So let's close that out
and let's go and enable those permissions for Paul.
So back in the JSON file, we have another user policy here.
What I'm going to do is just first update my ARN.
There's a few places to do this.
That's the first one.
Then there's this one here which allows us access to
the department folder contents to be able to list those contents.
And then we have this new statement here and I'm going to copy
over the top of the ARN making sure that I leave /department/*.
Now here we've got the S3 get object and S3 put objects api actions.
So those should allow us to retrieve, so download and also upload objects.
So I've copied my code.
And let's edit this policy again.
Click on JSON.
Paste it in,
review and save.
So coming back to where Paul's logged in, let's try and download this file.
And that worked, that happened on another screen.
So you can't see it but that did download successfully.
And now let's try and upload an object.
So let's add files. Trying to add the same image file as before.
Click on upload.
And that worked successfully.
The next policy is a bucket policy.
So what this will do is grant access to Paul to list the confidential folder
and we're going to use it with policy two above.
So this is going to show you that you can use a combination
of bucket and user policies.
So firstly, let's go back and get the user policy number two.
So back at the top here, let's grab this policy. It's already configured for us.
And I'm going to go back in and edit this policy.
Save the policy.
And of course now
Paul will have access to view the bucket
but won't be able to see anything in the confidential folder.
Next we need the actual bucket policy here.
And so what we need to do is copy over the bucket name here.
And we also need Paul's ARN.
So back in IAM, I'm going to copy the ARN for Paul's user account
and then paste that in here.
Then let's copy the code.
And this is going to be a bucket policy.
So back in S3, let's go up to the bucket level,
go to permissions, and let's add a bucket policy, so we click on edit right here.
Remove all this code,
paste this code in,
and make sure that you've got the ARNs correct.
And then save changes.
Now let's go back to Paul
And let's see if Paul can actually see the objects in the confidential folder.
And that all works.
So that's just a simple demonstration of using user policies to provide access to S3
and also bucket policies.
And of course we can use them in combination as well.
So I hope that worked well for you. I will see you in the next lesson.