There are a couple of ways we can use Multi-Factor Authentication with Amazon S3. So, Multi-Factor Authentication
means you have a second factor of authentication above and beyond your password.
So you have a username and password and then you have to supply something else.
And that something else is typically a code that's generated by either a physical device like a token
generating key card or it's actually an app on your phone like Google Authenticator.
So, the first one is Multi-Factor Authentication Delete. This simply adds a requirement for a second factor
of authentication when performing certain operations. That is, changing the versioning state of a bucket
and permanently deleting an object version.
It's important for the exam to remember those two specific operations. And those are the operations
for which the extra requirement for MFA will be enforced.
When you use MFA Delete, the x-amz-mfa requests that it gets included in the requests for those
specific operations.
The second factor of authentication is typically a code that's generated by a hardware device or software
program. And the image here is from Google Authenticator.
Now it does require versioning to be enabled on the bucket.
Versioning can be enabled by bucket owners,
the AWS account that created the bucket, or authorized IAM users. MFA Delete can only be enabled by
the bucket's owner, so that's an important distinction to remember.
The next use of MFA is something called MFA Protected API Access.
This is used to enforce another factor of authentication when accessing AWS resources,
not just this S3, other resources as well using the API or the CLI. It's enforced using the AWS
MultiFactorAuthAge key in a bucket policy.
So you might have a bucket policy that looks like this.
What this does is it denies any principal, any S3 action on a specific resource in this case.
But it could be, you know, broadly across all S3 buckets as well.
And the condition is if the AWS Multi-Factor authentication age true is not set if it's null. And that
particular attribute will be included in your request if you have authenticated using MFA, if you haven't,
then it's going to deny the access.
Now, if you log in to the console with MFA, but then you issue a command via the CLI or the API,
it doesn't matter.
The MFA from the console is completely separate from this.
What this means is you actually have to supply a token from an MFA device to the CLI or API to get
your temporary security credentials, and then you go and issue your API request to S3
and that information gets included. So you must be authenticated with MFA at the command line or the
API rather than through the console.
So I hope that was useful and I'll see you in the next lesson.