In this lesson, we're going to use Amazon S3 event notifications.
What we're going to do is create an
event notification that triggers an email using SNS
whenever objects are uploaded to our bucket.
Now, the first thing we need to do is create our SNS topic.
So in the Simple Notification Service, I'm going to create a new topic,
choose standard,
give it a name,
and then I'm going to scroll down a little way and create this topic.
Then I'm going to go to subscriptions
and I'm going to create a subscription to my topic.
Choose the ARN,
select the protocol,
here I'm going to choose email.
And for endpoint, I'm going to give it my email address.
Then I need to go to my email and confirm the subscription so that it starts working.
We now need to configure the access policy for our topics. So I've gone to topics.
I've selected the name of my topic and here we can see the access policy.
Now what I want to do here is I simply want to copy
the resource ARN. That's all I need.
Then I'm going to come to this file here which is in the course download,
Amazon S3 and it's called S3 Event Notification.
What I need to do is paste the topic ARN
next to resource.
I'm then going to take the account number which is this piece here
and I'm going to paste it down here where it says bucket owner account ID.
And then lastly I need the ARN for my bucket.
So I've pasted the ARN for my bucket
and now I can simply copy all of this code.
And back in SNS I'm going to click on edit for the topic.
Come down to access policy again,
and let's just delete all of this code, paste my code in,
click on save changes.
So what we've just done is we've granted the SNS publish API action to the S3 service
for a specific resource which is the SNS topic
and then the ARN for the bucket.
So anything coming from this bucket with this account number is going to be allowed
the SNS public API action. So those are the permissions we need.
Now we can go back to S3 and create our event notification.
So back in S3, on the properties page for my bucket,
I'm going to scroll down a little way,
find event notifications, click create event notification,
give it a name.
You can optionally specify a prefix or suffix to apply this to.
I'm going to leave those blank.
I'm going to select all objects create events.
That's Put, Post, Copy, and multipart uploads.
Let's scroll down a little way
and now we get to choose
the destination so we can choose Lambda functions, SNS topics, or SQS queues.
So we're going to choose topic.
I'm going to choose the Email-Me topic I just created
and then save changes.
So that's all there is to it.
Now if you did get any access denied issues when you were trying to save then
that's because you haven't properly specified those permissions in SNS.
So just go back to that policy we created and make sure that you have correctly
specified the ARNs for your bucket,
for your topic as well, and also the account number.
So now what we're going to do is go to objects
and just upload an object.
Doesn't matter what it is. So I'm just going to upload the file.
Click on upload,
and upload.
And now I can go over to my email inbox and see what's been delivered.
And this is what turned up in my email inbox.
Here we can see an event notification that's just told us
an event has happened, and clearly there's quite a bit of information in here.
Things like the region, the event time, what type of EPI
action was actually initiated.
So this was a PUT operation, an object-created operation.
We can see the principal ID, so who actually performed this, what IP address
they came from and much, much more.
So that's really useful information that could be
then used by another service to process that information in some way.
So that's it for this lesson.
And if you are going to be uploading lots of objects to this bucket,
make sure you go back and delete your
event notification or you're going to get lots of emails.