Hi guys. In this lesson we're going to use presigned URLs.
And what we're going to do with a pre-signed URL
is you're going to see how we can actually add an object to a bucket
that's not publicly accessible and then give someone a URL that
can make it accessible to them without authentication.
We're going to use the CLI to actually run a command to create our presigned URL.
So this is the command that we're going to run. It will generate a presigned URL.
The response will look something like this.
So we're actually then going to have this information returned
and this is the URL that we're able to then use to access the objects.
And it actually has some information about expiry in here.
So you can see it says expires in 3,600 seconds.
I'm back in S3.
And what I'm going do is I have this beach JPG in my bucket.
So I'm going to select this object, click on object URL.
Let's go to a new window and let's try and access that.
Now, I just want to make sure that I cannot access it and that is exactly the case.
So it's not publicly accessible.
We did make an object publicly accessible earlier on
in this section but we then removed those permissions.
So make sure that you don't have any bucket policies
specified and you don't have the block public access disabled.
So it should be on.
So we now know that we can't access this object.
So what we're going to do is see how we can make
this available to us using a presigned URL.
So I'm going to take the bucket name,
copy it to my clipboard,
on a command line I'm going to type AWS S3 presign then S3://
provide the bucket name,
and then I'm going to provide the file name.
Now, I also need to specify my profile information for my account.
So that should be it. That should be all I need to specify. I just hit enter.
And this is the URL that I'm now going to use, so I can copy this to my clipboard.
Let's come back to our browser window here
and I'm going to paste this one in.
And now we can see this nice image.
So that's it. That's how a presigned URL works.
And once the 3,600 seconds expire, I will no longer be able to access this object.