Server Access Logging is simply a way that we can log around the events that happen in our Amazon S3
buckets.
So, what we do is we can go to our bucket and enable logging.
And we choose a target bucket.
Now, you do want the target bucket to be a different bucket to the source bucket.
Otherwise, you can get a circular loop where every time there's an update you're writing to the same
bucket, which causes another update, and the loop kind of just goes on and on.
Now, you can also choose a target prefix as well.
So, this provides detailed records of the requests that are made to an S3 bucket.
And the information that you can log includes the requester, the bucket name, the request time,
action, response status, and error code
if it's applicable. It is disabled by default, so you have to go in and manually enable server access
logging and choose your target bucket.
You only ever pay for the storage used, and you must configure a separate bucket as the destination,
so always do that.
You also need to grant write permissions to the Amazon S3 Log Delivery group on the destination bucket.
So, you remember when we were looking at ACLs on a bucket, there was an option to configure permissions
for the Amazon S3 Log Delivery group.
That's where you would tick the box, which allows write access.
Now, it's very easy to implement if you want to go and have a practice. It does take a bit of time sometimes
to actually see the logs come through, but just create yourself a target bucket and then go to your
source bucket,
enable logging,
specify the target and optionally a prefix.