Cross-Origin Resource Sharing or CORs can be a little bit of a confusing subject. So, I'm going to
try and make it as easy as possible in this lesson for you to understand.
So, with S3, you do sometimes need to enable CORs.
What it means is it will allow requests from an origin to another origin.
Now, that in itself probably sounds rather confusing.
Let's first define what an origin is. Now,
an origin is defined by the DNS name that you're connecting to, the protocol you're using, and the
port that you're connected to as well.
So, if you're connected from a client to a specific domain name using HTTP on port 80, then that's your
origin.
Let's look at this in a quick diagram to help you to understand.
So, we've got a client who's using a browser and they're connecting to an S3 bucket.
Now, that S3 bucket is configured as a website, in this case for mycompany.com. We then have another
bucket. And that bucket is holding some web font assets, which we're going to need to access.
Now, firstly, the browser is connecting to mycompany.com, so the DNS name is mycompany.com.
The protocol is http and the port is port 80, so that now becomes the origin.
And in this case, we're using JavaScript, so a JavaScript web client has been loaded on the browser.
Now, we need to actually connect to the S3 endpoint for the other bucket with the web font assets in
it.
So, we're going to issue a connection request.
And what happens is something called a pre-flight request is going to check if we are allowed to make
a request to that specific bucket.
So remember, we're connected to one origin, but now our browser is trying to connect to a different
origin.
Now, whether we're able to do that or not is defined on that bucket with the web font assets.
That's where the CORs configuration is.
So, you have to add a configuration that's going to allow requests from the other origin.
Now, how do we do that?
Well, we enable it through a series of settings.
We've got the access control allow origin, the access control allow methods, and the access control
allow headers.
You don't need to use all of these, but these are the available settings. And we define these settings
through rules.
The rules are added using JSON files in Amazon S3.
So let's have a look at an example.
Here's an example rule in JSON format for a CORs configuration. And we can see we've got the allowed
headers in this case is *, methods is PUT, POST, and DELETE, and the origins is www.mycompany.com.
So that would have to be the origin. That would allow www.mycompany.com.
It might not actually allow mycompany.com because that's a slightly different domain name.
This is a subdomain. So, you'll need to make sure that's hopefully set correctly.
So, that's CORs. Now,
the key thing to remember is that you don't implement your CORs configuration on the origin, you
implement it on the other bucket that you're trying to connect to.