Amazon CloudFront is a content delivery network, a CDN. The purpose of a CDN is to improve the performance
of accessing objects.
And what I mean by objects here, it's basically files. So, it could be image files, it could be video
files, it could be pretty much any file type.
Now, we're specifically looking here at helping performance over a large geographical area, perhaps
the entire world.
So, you might have some content that's somewhere like North America, but you have users all the way over
in China, in Japan, and Australia, and that's a big physical distance.
And that long physical distance means that there's more latency and poor performance.
So, what we're trying to do is get the content closer to those users. And we have two particular things
that you really need to understand that are components of CloudFront, and that's an origin and a distribution.
So let's have a look.
So, CloudFront origins are literally the origin of where the content is coming from.
So, for instance, you can have Amazon S3, so your content can be sitting as objects in Amazon
S3 and you want to get that closer to users.
Or it could be Amazon EC2.
So maybe your content is on an Amazon EC2 instance.
Maybe it's a website, maybe it's a mounted file system on EFS, but the content is being served
by EC2. And those EC2 instances can also be behind a load balancer.
So, that's the origin, and the origin is within a single region.
So, it's in one physical place in the world.
Now, we then have something called edge locations.
Edge locations are actually all over the world. And there's hundreds of edge locations located in different
parts of the world.
And what happens is the content from the origin gets pushed out and cached in the edge location.
And so, the idea being that those edge locations are distributed broadly around the world, and that
means your content is somewhere where it can be closer to the users who want to access it.
So, we have users accessing the edge locations.
So as you can see, these users are in all sorts of different places around the world.
So, as you may know, latency is essentially the delay.
So it means that the greater the latency, the poorer the performance. If you have high latency when you're
trying to access a video, you're going to get a really bad experience.
Latency is primarily a factor of distance.
The farther you are from, wherever you're trying to play that video, then the greater the latency.
But there are also other factors as well such as the number of hops, the number of routers and switches,
the amount of congestion and oversubscription on the line somewhere between you and the content you're
trying to access.
So, CloudFront aims to resolve a lot of this. And it does say a couple of ways.
Firstly, the content gets cached in an edge location, which means hopefully it's physically much,
much closer to where your users are, so they can then access the content in the edge location.
And what happens is users are directed automatically to the closest edge location.
So, if your users are in Asia, they might have a different edge location than if they're in Australia
or India or so on.
So, they get access to that content faster.
Now, if the content doesn't happen to be on the edge location at that point in time, maybe it expired
from the cache, then it has to be pulled from the origin.
But even here, it's going over the AWS global network, not the internet.
And that means lower latency and better performance.
Let's look at origins and distributions in a bit more detail.
So, a distribution is what you create in CloudFront.
When you create a distribution, you get a name or an access endpoint for that distribution. And the
standard endpoint looks something like this.
You'll have some combination of characters and numbers .cloudfront.net.
You can then use your own custom domain.
That's something you can do, so you can have your own domain name like dctcloudlabs.com,
or whatever you have available.
Now, when you create your CloudFront distribution, you also specify the origin. And your origin
is where your files are.
You can even have multiple origins as well.
You might have an S3 origin and a custom origin.
The custom origin is EC2 or EC2 behind a load balancer.
With CloudFront, we're creating something called a web distribution. And this speeds up the distribution
of static and dynamic content.
So, any of those file types on the screen there. You access your web distribution using HTTP or HTTPS,
and you can add, update, or delete objects and even submit data through a web form.
You can even use live streaming for real time events as well.
Now, there used to be something called an RTMP
distribution.
These were discontinued.
So they're not actually available anymore. And you shouldn't see these coming up in the exam.
We also have something called a behavior that we can configure within our distribution.
And this means we can look for things like a path pattern. With a path pattern
you might say that if somebody is looking for a specific path/something, then they should go
to the S3 origin.
If they're going to a different path, then maybe they have to go to the customer origin.
You can configure the protocol policy you want to use, whether you redirect to HTTPS to stop people making
unsecured connections and that kind of thing.
You can define the cache policy, which helps you to work out how long things stay in the cache and
the origin requests policy.
So, how do you configure the security and other factors of the connection from your edge locations to your
origin when they need to request content.
And by the way, you can also use a static website as an origin running on S3.
So that's it for the theory.
What we're going to do in the next lesson is create a web distribution in CloudFront.
And we're going to have a look at how we can configure caching behaviors so that we can send certain
requests to two different S3 origins.
So I hope that was useful.
I'll see you in the next lesson.