In this lesson, I'm going to cover Amazon cloudfront, signed
URLS and
OAI
slash
OAC
So let's start with signed
URLS. These provide more control over access to your content.
So it's essentially a way of creating a
URL that can be used to access to content that otherwise would not be accessible.
You can specify the beginning and expiration date and time for the
URL. So it expires and can no longer be used and also IP addresses.
So what IP addresses are allowed to use the signed
URL.
Here we have a mobile application, cloud front and a serverless application.
The mobile actually uses the serverless application in order
to authenticate to the application and then request a signed
URL. So normally the content is restricted
and what we're doing here is using this authentication via a function, for example,
that might be on lambda and we're gaining
that authorization to then access the content.
So the signed
URL is returned and then the mobile client can actually use the signed
URL to access the distribution and the content which
has been granted for access to this particular application.
So that's the third step.
Then of course, the content is delivered securely to the clients. Signed
URLS should be used for individual files and clients that don't support cookies.
So next we have cloud front signed cookies. These are very similar to signed
URLS, but you can use them when you don't want to change
URLS. Also when you want to provide access to multiple restricted files.
So now a cookie is used for accessing the content.
Let's now have a look at origin access identity.
So what we have here is an origin, in this case,
a custom origin which is an S3 bucket configured as a static website.
We have cloud front and we have our users on the internet,
the users access the distribution from there, they can access the content
and it's secured using an OAI how it's secured is via a bucket policy.
So the bucket policy will only allow
the cloud front distributions OAI
which is essentially a special type of user to access the bucket.
We can see that in the principal element here,
we have the cloud front user and it's specifying a specific origin access identity.
So this is essentially like a user account within cloud front
and the bucket will only allow access from this user account. OK.
So it's restricting access to the OAI only.
That means that if you try to access the bucket directly,
then that would not work.
So that's the purpose of an OAI
and OAI
is only useful for S3.
It's no use if you're using an origin, that's an EC2 instance or a load balancer.
For example
only S3. Also the OAI
has been deprecated.
There's actually a new thing called an origin access control or OAC.
So what is an OAC? Well, it's like an OAI
but it supports additional use cases. And
AWS recommend using the OAC instead of the OAI.
It also requires an S3 bucket policy that allows the cloud
front service principle to access the contents of the bucket.
And it looks like this. It's a little bit similar to the one that we looked at before.
But instead of the cloud front
OAI
user, the principle is the service. So cloudfront dot Amazon
Aws dot com, then we have a condition where a string equals condition for the
aws source ARN
of the cloudfront distribution itself.
Other than that, it's essentially performing exactly the same purpose as the
OAI
It's ensuring that you can restrict access to your content such
that it can only be accessed via the cloudfront distribution.