this section is all about amazon DynamoDB.
So an entire section about one database service and that's because
the developer associate has a lot of coverage of amazon DynamoDB.
So DynamoDB is a no SQL server list database that runs on AWS. It's an AWS service.
It's one of the services that they've created themselves. So it's their technology
with DynamoDB. We create tables and then we can populate those tables with our data.
It's extremely flexible, it's extremely high performance and low latency.
So for the exam you will need to understand quite a lot about DynamoDB.
So we're going to be building through the knowledge as we go
through the section with lots of hands on exercises as always.
Now you'll definitely need to understand the pricing and how you allocate R C U.
S and W. C. U. S. You'll know what they are a bit later on in this section.
Make sure you do follow those exercises closely because there's quite
a few questions coming up in exams where you need to calculate
RCUs and WCUs for a specific requirement.
So you need to know how to do that math in the exam without any calculators.
And there are many other features of DynamoDB that get covered in exam questions.
Hence the large amount of coverage in this section.
So it is quite a long section with lots of hands on and lots of theory.
I hope you enjoy it and I'll see you in the next lesson