Hi guys. In this lesson, we're going to look at how we can create
a local secondary index and a global secondary index.
Back in the DynamoDB console, I've selected my table.
And if we go to indexes,
you'll see that we're able to create a global secondary index.
But there's no option to create a local secondary index.
Now that's because we must create the LSIs at table creation time.
So really important to understand that. That comes up in lots of exam questions.
You need to know that you can create a GSI at any time, but the LSI
is only creatable at the table creation time.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to delete this table.
And let's just type delete and we're going to recreate our table but with an LSI.
So that deleted very quickly.
Let's now create a new table.
And it's basically going to have the same name. It's going to be called My Store.
Partition key will be client ID
and the sort key will be created just as before.
Now, if we choose customized settings,
scroll down, leave all these as they are,
and here we can create a secondary index.
We can create both the local secondary index and the global secondary index.
So we're going to create a local index.
Now note that the local secondary index has the same partition
key as the base table but a different sort key.
So all we need to specify here is the sort key.
And I'm going to use SKU as the sort key and that's going to be a string.
And I'll leave the index name and attribute projections is going to be all so
all actual attributes will be projected into the index.
Let's create that index.
That's specified now. So what we can do is go down and create our table.
So the table is being created and we now need to populate some values.
I'm going to run the same command that we used earlier on in the section
to batch write items and use the mystore.json to populate the table.
So on the command line, I'm going to simply run that command.
And that should have now populated the items in our table.
Back in DynamoDB, let's look at how we can scan and query using our index.
So here I have scanned, selected, and my store so that's the main table.
And we can see all the items down here.
Now if I change that to index, I can then run.
And the items have been added to this table
and the attributes have been projected along with them.
If we then go to query, it's gone back to my store.
So with my store, we can query based on the client ID.
So that would be the email address of the client in this case
and the sort key which is the created date.
We can then add filters but we can't search on any other attributes.
It has to be the client ID and the created date.
Now if we change to the index,
now we see that changes so now we can use the client ID.
So let's just copy one of these client IDs so PJ@example.com.
And now we can use these sort keys, so we can actually then go and find
an SKU ID here and put that in.
And now we can run a more efficient query because we're now able to
use a different sort key.
So that's how a local secondary index works.
Now, with the local secondary index were able to
change the sort key so that gives us some benefits
for some more efficient queries.
But we might also want to change the partition key too.
And that's where we need a global secondary index.
So let's go up to update settings,
indexes,
and we're going to create an index.
And this will create a global secondary index.
So this time for partition key I'm going to enter SKU.
And then for sort key
I'm going to enter QTY so quantity.
And that's going to be a number value.
We're going to leave the index capacity as it is.
You do need to have sufficient capacity here.
You can get performance problems if your GSI
does not have sufficient read and write capacity.
So let's scroll down. We'll project all attributes
and let's create that index.
So that took a few minutes. My table is now ready.
So what I'm going to do is go back to explore items,
choose scan query, and we now have two indexes.
So we have the index which is the local secondary index with SKU index
and then we've got this one which is SKU
quantity index, that's our global secondary index.
So if I go to query and select my GSI,
now you will see that we have the SKU and the quantity.
So this gives us a whole lot of different options for how we can query efficiently.
So for example, let's put in that partition key again
and say that the number value is equal to one.
And let's see what gets returned.
And so here we have the responses where we have an SKU value of a specific value
and the quantity of items purchase were one.
So that's how we can use LSI and GSIs
to scan and query the information in our tables efficiently.
So that's it for this lesson. And we are going to delete this table.
We don't need this one anymore.
We do need to create another one a bit later on in this section.
But because this has indexes,
I'd rather get rid of this now as it can slow down some operations.