Hi guys in this section, you're gonna learn all about AWS Lambda.
Lambda is a service that is known as a serverless service.
That means there's no actual underlying EC2 instances or other
servers that you have to manage that's all done for you
with lambda.
What happens is you add code to lambda,
so units of code that you upload through various different mechanisms through the
console or from an S3 bucket or from the command line,
which we'll see
in this section
and once you've added your code in then there's
various different ways that your functions get triggered.
Now you do really need to understand all of
these different mechanisms like synchronous and asynchronous invocation.
So we're going to be practicing with those
after we've been through the theory lessons.
So there's lots of theory and lots of hands
on exercises where you're going to work with lambda
for the exam.
You also really need to understand things like lambda versions and aliases.
So we're not only going to do theory on those will also have lots
of hands on sessions where you'll get to practice using versions and aliases.
So you'll learn lots about lambda in this section.
Now at the end we actually cover the AWS Serverless application model as well.
AWS SAM it's fairly brief because it's not covered in a lot of detail on the exam but
I just want to let you know what it is and we'll see how it actually works.
So I hope you enjoy the section, I'll see you in the next lesson