Hi guys. In this lesson, we're going to test asynchronous and synchronous invocation
from the command line using the AWS CLI.
So we'll be creating a Lambda function and then using the CLI from our computers,
we're then going to initiate an invocation of the function
and then the function is going to execute
and it will write an event to CloudWatch logs.
I'm in the Lambda console and I'm on the dashboard. You can also be under functions.
And what you want to do is click on create function.
Now there's a few options here, you can author from scratch,
you can use a blueprint and there's a whole lot of
different blueprints for various functions that will include the function code.
You can use container images
or the serverless application repository,
which we'll look at later on in this section.
What we're going to do for now is author from scratch.
I'm going to call my function MyTestfunction.
We then need to choose the runtime.
Now I'm happy using Node.js16.x.
There's a whole load of different supported runtimes in here as well.
So I'm just gonna leave it on Node.js16.
For architecture, I'm happy with x86 64.
Now, under permissions,
your function needs permissions to call other AWS services.
So there's a few different things you can do here.
You can create a new role with basic Lambda permissions,
use an existing role
or you can create a new role from AWS policy templates.
If you use the policy templates, you'll see here
we have lots of different policy templates to choose from,
which give us permissions to various services.
For this exercise,
I'm happy creating a new role with basic Lambda permissions.
And that will include the permissions that I need for Amazon CloudWatch.
At the bottom we have the advanced settings.
Here, you can enable code signing,
you can enable a function URL so that you can assign an HTTPS endpoint.
You can enable tags,
and if you wanted to deploy your function to a VPC,
this is where you would do it and you need to specify the VPC
and then the subnets where you will deploy it.
Now, I don't want to change any of those settings so, I've left them all blank
and I'm going to create my function.
Now in this case as we create the function,
it's going to create that new IAM role for us with the permissions.
And we'll go and have a look at that to make sure
it's got all the permissions we need.
So here is the main page for the function.
Here, we can see the function name in the center console.
We've got triggers and destinations, we'll look at all of that in this section.
And then a bit further down, you'll see
there's various different panes you can go into.
So here we're looking at code and you can see
the index.Js code here, and this is a simple Hello from Lambda function.
If you go to test, we can run test events, we'll be doing that shortly.
Under monitor,
this is where you can actually then go across and see information
in CloudWatch view AWS X-Ray traces in service lens.
You can view Lambda insights and profiles in code guru.
You can also see the metrics on the page here coming from CloudWatch.
So the function reports the information to CloudWatch
and then we can display that information on this page.
We've also got configuration.
Here, there's lots of different tabs for configuration.
For example, let's go to permissions.
If I click on permissions we can see the role name.
If we click on that, that will take us to IAM.
We can see the role.
We can see the trust relationships. In this case,
we're allowing the Lambda service to assume the role.
Under permissions, we can see that we have this policy applied.
And this policy is going to allow
some permissions for Amazon CloudWatch logs. In this case we can create a log stream
and we can put event logs into that stream.
Now note that this particular execution role
is limited to the ARN
of the actual Lambda function itself.
So you can't use this with another function because if you do
it's not going to work unless you go in and actually modify the resource ARN.
Now, back in Lambda, we've also then got aliases.
We'll look at those a bit later on in this section, and versions.
Now for now, for this particular lesson, we're not going to change anything else.
Let's come back to test here
and create a new test event.
I'm just gonna call it T1.
And I'm going to leave the default settings, which has
the template Hello World and it has this Event JSON.
If we save that,
and then run test,
we've now executed our function.
And in the details here we can see what the response is.
So this is a successful response. A status code 200 is a success
and the body is Hello From Lambda. So it's just returning that information,
echoing it on the screen.
Further down we can see some information about the initialization duration,
the billed duration, so how many milliseconds we actually got billed for?
How much memory was used and more.
And you can see the log output here.
So this output is actually also going to be recorded in CloudWatch logs.
Let's go over in a moment and have a look.
You can see the start, the end of the request, and then the report
which also includes the bill duration and that other information we just looked at.
So coming back up, let's go to monitor.
and in CloudWatch logs, we should now have an entry.
So a log group has been created
and within that log group we have this log stream,
and in the log stream, we can see the start,
the end of the request, and then the report.
So that's how we run a test event using the console.
Now the purpose of this lesson is to go to the CLI
and using the CLI, we're going to run
some invocations synchronously and asynchronously.
You'll find this file in your course, download.
So it's in the code directory, AWS Lambda, and it's called invoking-functions.md.
Now, there's a couple of different ways we can invoke our function synchronously.
And so what we're going to do first is we're going to run
AWS Lambda invoke --function-name.
I've already filled out my function name, is called mytestfunction.
If you chose a different name for your function, make sure you update that.
And then we have payload,
And this is a base64 encoded string.
We'll see how to create that in a moment.
And then the output gets recorded in response.json.
So to get this command ready, we need to get this base64 encoded payload string.
Back in Lambda, on the test pane, what I'm gonna do is copy this event JSON.
I'm then going to go to a new tab and I'm gonna search for base64.
So just use Google or whatever your search
engine is and you should find this website, base64decode.org.
So I click on that link, choose the encode option at the top here.
So it changes to encoding our information
and then we paste the event data here
and click on encode.
We now get this string.
So what I'm gonna do is copy
this base64 encoded information which is our test event
and I'm going to paste that into my file here.
So I've now got the base64 encoded information here,
and I can copy this entire command to my clipboard.
And on the command line, I'm going to paste in this information.
In my case, I have a profile that I'm using to execute under my account.
So I'm going to add that information in and then hit enter.
So a status code 200 response is good.
That means that our function did execute successfully.
So we should have a response.json file in our directory now.
And if I look into that file, this is what I get. I get that status 200
and then the body, the Hello From Lambda. Exactly the same result
as we got when we executed the test event through the console.
Back in my file, you'll see that there are other ways we can execute.
So we don't necessarily have to enter the base64 encoded information.
We can just give it the function name. We already have a test event anyway.
So I'm gonna copy this to my clipboard and in this case I
just called my out file Out. So that's where the information will go.
So let's paste that in.
I'm going to use my profile.
Let's execute the invocation and again we get a status 200
and this time we need to go and check our out file.
And we get exactly the same result.
So we've synchronously invoked our function.
The next test is to use the event invocation type.
That causes an asynchronous invocation.
So the command is the same up to that point.
And then we have the --invocation-type and then we specify events.
And then for the payload again, we're going to use this base64 encoded information
to run the same test event. So I'm just going to copy that to my clipboard,
simply paste that in,
and then I can copy this entire command,
paste that in,
and let's execute our function.
Now note that this time you get a status code 202, so that is a success code,
but it's indicative of an asynchronous invocation.
Now we've used the same response file, so we can actually go and just open that up
and let's see is the information any different?
Well, yes, actually there is no information in this case.
So with the synchronous invocation we do have the response body returned to us.
But with the asynchronous invocation, we don't so even though the file is there,
the file is actually empty.
So that's how we synchronously and asynchronously invoke our functions
using the command line.
And that's it for this lesson. I'll see you in the next one.