Hi guys. In this lesson,
we're going to cover Lambda destinations and Dead Letter Queues.
So firstly, success and failure destinations.
With these, you can send invocation records to a
destination of your choice when your function is invoked.
And here's a snippet from the console where we configure our destinations.
Firstly we choose the source and this works for asynchronous invocations
and for stream based invocations. Stream based would be kinesis or DynamoDB streams.
Then we have the condition, so this is either success or failure.
So did our invocation succeed or fail?
And then we choose the destination type.
That can be an SQS queue, an SNS topic, a Lambda function, or EventBridge event bus.
The execution record contains details about the request and response
in the JSON format.
The information that gets sent includes the version, timestamp, request context,
request payload and response context,
and also the response payload itself.
A DLQ is a dead letter queue
and this saves unprocessed events for further processing.
So for some reason, the processing of a specific event does not succeed
then what we want to do is send it to a dead letter queue
and then later on we can work out what to do with it.
This applies to asynchronous invocations.
The DLQ can be an SQs queue or an SNS topic.
When editing the asynchronous configuration,
you can specify the number of retries.
So this is where Lambda is re-trying to see
if it can succeed with processing the specific event.
So here for example, we would retry two times
and then after six hours the event will be discarded and sent to the DLQ.
Then from the DLQ,
maybe we've got another Lambda function or something else that processes that
event and tries to work out through some kind of analytics what happened,
what went wrong.
And that's it for this lesson. I'll see you the next one.