In this lesson, I'm going to cover monitoring,
logging, and tracing for our AWS Lambda functions.
So firstly we've got performance monitoring and this
is where we use the Amazon CloudWatch service.
Lambda will send metrics to CloudWatch for performance monitoring.
And we can see some of the metrics here. We've got the duration of the execution,
the number of invocations, how many concurrent executions there were.
So how many instances of the function were actually running concurrently.
Any errors that were experienced and any throttles that occurred.
And so we can see those being charted out here.
Next we have logging.
And the execution logs are stored in Amazon CloudWatch logs.
Now really important to understand for the exam,
this comes up in pretty much every exam.
You need to understand that when you're working with Lambda and it's
actually trying to use another service such as storing logs in CloudWatch logs,
then the function execution role will need to have,
IAM permissions to write to CloudWatch logs.
So for example,
you would want to make sure that you have a policy like this.
Here we are allowing action, logs CreateLogStream and logs PutLogEvents.
And we have a resource here that specifies the ARN
of the log group with the function name in it.
Next up we have tracing with AWS X-Ray.
This gives you a way to visualize
the different components of your application and look
for performance bottlenecks and you can troubleshoot
any requests that resulted in an error.
The Lambda functions send the trace data to X-Ray and then X-Ray will
process that data and generate
a service map and searchable trace summaries.
And it looks something like this.
So we can see here we have an AWS Lambda configuration with a Lambda function,
on the backend we've got a DynamoDB table
and we're also specifying recognition that's part of the application stack.
So what's happening here is selfies are getting uploaded,
processed, recognition is doing some work to look for information in the images
and then we're storing some data about the results perhaps in DynamoDB table.
So we can see this service map and we can see the latency that's occurring
and we would also be able to see if any errors occurred.
The X-Ray Daemon is a software application that gathers
raw segment data and relays it to the X-Ray service.
And the Daemon works in conjunction with the X-Ray SDKs
so that data sent by the SDKs can reach the X-Ray service.
When you trace your Lambda function, the X-Ray Daemon will automatically run
in the Lambda environment to gather trace data and then send it to AWS X-Ray.
And the function again will need permissions to write to X-Ray in the execution role.
Another thing that comes up in exam questions. It's going to be the various services
that your Lambda function needs to communicate with,
DynamoDB, S3 maybe, or CloudWatch logs or maybe AWS X-Ray.
You've always got to have the permissions.