In this lesson,
we're going to look at how we can connect our functions to a VPC and also use an ALB
in front of AWS Lambda.
So here we have a diagram of a VPC
with two AZs, couple of private subnets with instances
and a couple of public subnets.
Now we've got our Lambda function and we want to connect our function to this VPC.
Now when we specify the configuration information in Lambda,
what it will do is establish an Elastic Network Interface in a private subnet.
So we now have connected our function so
that it can communicate with our application instances
in the private subnet or whatever else we want to communicate with in that subnet.
Now, it's important to understand that once you connect
your Lambda function to a private subnet,
you then will not get internet access.
So your Lambda function won't be able to call any service that's internet-based.
So what we need to do then is establishing NAT Gateway.
Now, a NAT Gateway is always established in a public subnet
and we specify the destination in the route table of the private subnet.
And then that gateway will use the internet gateway to then access the internet.
So that's how you make sure your Lambda function can
still communicate with any internet-based service it uses.
You must connect to a private subnet with a NAT gateway for internet access,
as I've just explained, as you don't get a public IP in a private subnet.
Be very careful with DNS resolution of public host names as it could
add to the function running time and that does incur a cost.
You cannot be connected to a dedicated tenancy VPC.
And only connects with VPC if you need to, as it can slow down the function execution.
Now of course we do need some permissions.
So your functions execution role must have the following permissions.
We need the CreateNetworkInterface,
DescribedNetworkInterfaces
and DeleteNetworkInterface.
And those are all associated with EC2.
These permissions are included in a managed policy
and you can see the policy name right there.
We can also put an ALB in front of our Lambda function.
Now it must be an application load balancer.
We cannot use a Network Load Balancer and have a Lambda target.
You can register your Lambda function as targets and then configure a listener
rule to forward requests to the target group for your Lambda function.
Now, here's a diagram, we've got a Lambda function and an ALB.
And we've got our internet client connecting to the ALB
over HTTP or HTTPS.
And then it has a registered target using the Lambda function.
The content of the request is passed
to the Lambda function in JSON format
and then the Lambda function is going to execute the information it receives.
So why would you want to put your Lambda function behind an ALB?
There are a few use cases.
So for example you might have different
functions in different target groups and you
can use the routing rules like path-based routing and host-based routing.
You can also use an SSL/TLS certificate on the ALB,
so you add that to your front end for your website or whatever you're running.
A bit of information, there are some limits to understand.
The Lambda function and target group must be in
the same account in the same AWS region.
The maximum size of the request body that you can send to
a Lambda function is one megabyte.
And the maximum size of the response JSON that
the Lambda function can send is also one megabyte.
Websockets are not supported. Upgrade requests are rejected with an HTTP 400 code.
And lastly, local zones are not supported.