In this lesson,
I'll cover some best practices for developing and working with Lambda functions.
Now, I'm going to focus on the best practices around developing function code.
There are some more best practices that's useful to know for the exam
and you can find those in the reference link that's attached to this lesson.
So let's have a look at some best practices for how we write our function code.
Firstly, AWS recommend that you separate the Lambda handler from your core logic.
That allows you to make a more unit testable function.
So for example, in this code here, which is based on Node.js,
the core logic is separated from the Lambda handler.
So we've got the handler specified up here
and then we separate out the core logic.
The next best practice is to take advantage of execution environment
reuse to improve the performance of your function.
This means you might initialize SDK clients and database connections
outside of the function handler.
You might cache static assets locally in the /TMP directory.
And this means that subsequent invocations processed by the
same instance of your function can reuse those resources.
And that can save cost by reducing function runtime.
You should also use a keep alive directive to maintain persistent connections.
After a period of time, Lambda purges idle connections.
So if you try and reuse them then that can result in an error.
Next you should use environment variables to pass operational parameters
to your function.
For example, use environment variables instead of hard coding
S3 bucket names in your code.
Next, control the dependencies in your functions deployment package.
Now, libraries and runtimes in the execution environment are managed by
Lambda itself and they can get updated at any time.
And that could cause issues with your code because
the runtimes and the libraries that it's dependent on
may change, whereas you haven't updated your code to reflect any
changes you need to make to your code.
So to avoid those errors,
you can package your own dependencies in the deployment package.
And that means you then have full management control of those dependencies.
You should also minimize your deployment package size to its runtime necessities.
That will reduce the amount of time
it takes for deployment packages to get downloaded
and then unpacked ahead of invocation.
You should also avoid using recursive code in your function.
So don't use code that calls itself until an arbitrary criteria is met.
That can cause large volumes of invocations and of course that will increase cost.
And that's it for this lesson, there are more best practices.
So please follow the link attached to this lesson and just give it a few minutes
to read through and understand some of the
best practices around working with Lambda functions
in addition to these recommendations for how you work with the code.