Hi guys. In this lesson,
I'm going to give you a brief overview of the Serverless Application Repository.
So back on the AWS console,
I'm just going to search for SAR and serverless application repository comes up.
Okay, so what is this?
Well, essentially here we have some applications that have been preconfigured
and are ready for deployment.
Now it defaults to published applications, but I don't have any of my own.
So what we can then do is go to available applications
and you'll see all of these public applications that have been deployed.
So there's a lot here and there's actually
some really interesting ones that you can deploy.
So let's say for example, if we head over there is an API with Lambda and DynamoDB,
the problem is a lot of these are out of date, unfortunately.
It's a great idea
when using serverless application repository to package up your own applications,
is a really useful utility.
And does pop up in the odd exam question.
But what you'll find is, when you actually go into these
and you can see the information that is included here,
and this is the template for deployment.
Quite a few of these are using
programming languages that are not supported by Lambda.
Well, this one should be I think nodeJS12 is I found quite a lot of these have really
old versions of the runtime and that means that they
will often fail when you try and deploy them,
which is a shame.
But you know, on a positive side,
anyone can create these packaged applications and of course you have to
be authorized but then you can actually upload these and present them.
Unfortunately, AWS doesn't seem to have any kind of ongoing
incentivization to make sure that people keep these up to date.
But they are quite useful.
So if you find some that work,
then it's a good way to sort of play
around and then deploy some pre configured applications.
Many of these applications will have links to source code on GitHub so you can follow
that link and then you'll find
the various information here. So we've got our template.yml, package.json,
there's a readme and then there is SRC directory.
You'll see the code files and the files for deployment.
So that is the Serverless Application Repository.
It does have some useful examples in here,
so feel free to have a play around and understand how this works.