Welcome to this section.
In this section,
I'm going to cover the amazon elastic container service (ECS) as well as
the elastic kubernetes service e k s and the elastic container registry (ECR)
So these are all services related to running and managing Docker containers on AWS
amazon Ec s is a service we can use for running docker containers on AWS,
either in a serverless manner or with
the underlying infrastructure within our control.
Then elastic kubernetes service is used for management of containers.
You might be using Kubernetes in your on premises data center or on another cloud.
EKS allows us to run a managed implementation of Kubernetes in the cloud.
And then, lastly,
the elastic container registry is where we can
actually store the images for our containers.
So all about containers in this section,
exciting technology and certainly interesting to learn about and to use.