With Amazon ECS, we can distribute incoming connections using a load balancer.
Now, the Application Load Balancer specifically has what we call container awareness.
And in this lesson, I want to teach you what that means.
So, in this case, we have multiple availability zones with private and public subnets. In the private
subnets I've got two container instances.
So, each of these is an ECS container instance, which is essentially an Amazon EC2 instance.
On top of it, we have two ECS services, and each service is running the Nginx and Apache containers.
So, as you can see, Nginx and Apache are both web services and they both run on port 80.
So, we have multiple containers on each container instance running on port 80.
Now that's okay.
But from a host networking perspective, the actual ECS container instance can only receive connections
coming in on port 80 once. You can't have multiple port 80s.
So what happens when an incoming connection on port 80 reaches the container instance?
How does it know where to forward that connection to?
Well, what we have is host ports and the host ports are unique. So, each task is running a web service
on port 80.
But then we have a dynamic port allocated on the host. And the host knows that any connections coming
in on this port should be forwarded to this specific task.
Now with an Application Load Balancer,
it is actually aware of this, so it's able to communicate with ECS and it knows about these host ports.
So it's not just going to try and forward to port 80, it's going to forward connections to the various
host ports. So, we can have a single listener on port 80 and all connections are coming in on port 80.
But then, they're getting distributed to the host ports.
And then when they come in on a specific host port, the container instance knows which container it
should actually forward that connection on to.
Now, it's worth noting that if we have our containers running in a private subnet, we should have a
NAT gateway in a public subnet and an entry in the route table for the private subnet, for any
internet access that those containers might need.
So that does pop up in the exam.
Sometimes you might need to download some code or connect to an internet-based API service.
So, for that, you will need a NAT gateway.
So that's how container awareness works with an Application Load Balancer.