Hi guys and welcome to part two of the U C S lab in
this lesson we're going to create the
task definition and the application load balancer.
We're really building the building blocks for our cluster
and service that will create in the next lesson.
So in the CS will create a task definition. We're gonna do that via the command line.
We're going to then create an application load balancer.
It's gonna have to listeners the primary on Port 80 for our active application
and then a secondary testing listener on port 80 80.
And you'll see when we get to the next section
of the course where we finish off this lab exercise,
we add in a codepipeline and you'll see how
we could use codedeploy to automatically swap the ports
the listeners rather and also the target groups when we do a blue green deployment.
So for now this is what we're going to build out.
Now, back in the file, you will see that we're on part two now.
So we've got some instructions,
you need to change to a command line on your computer with pcs permission.
So just run AWS configure, make sure you've got access keys configured for that,
give you permissions to e c s
and then we're gonna change to the directory with task def dot Jason.
You'll see that in a moment.
Now, before we actually do any of this,
we need to update this file.
So this is the file,
you'll find it of course in your code directory amazon ec s
and you'll see there's an execution role and that's
not set up correctly at this point in time.
So I don't have my account number in there
but this role should exist. If it doesn't in your account
then you can just search on google for creating
the tcs task execution role copy and paste that.
You will find the instructions.
It's very simple but you should have it because we've already been using E C.
S and it creates it for us.
So what I'm gonna do is just grab my account number and
put it into here and then we should be ready to go.
So I've copied my account number in.
You'll see that the task definition name is sample dash website. It's an engine.
X image. It's going to use poor 80 because it's a web service.
It's gonna have fargate capabilities,
the AWS VPc network mode
and then 256 CPU and 5 12 of memory.
So I'm happy with that. I'm gonna save my file
and back in the instructions here. I'm gonna copy this command.
So this is for registering the task definition
and let's head over to a command line.
So on the command line you should be in your pcs directory that's in your code,
download wherever you put that on your computer
and what you should find in here is you have the task def dot Jason file.
So if I just open that file
we can see the file we just
configured.
So let's clear the screen come down to the middle
and I'm gonna try and register my task definition.
That looks good. It has registered the task definition for me.
So let's go back over to our file
and see what we need to do next.
So now we're going to create the application load balancer,
you can see the various settings that we need to
create here so you can refer back to this.
I'm going to go to the console now and configure according to these settings.
So in the console, in the Ec two management console,
I'm going to go down to low balances.
Let's click on load balancer, create a load balancer
and click on create under application load balancer.
Let's call this
my E C S dash
A or B.
It's going to be internet facing.
It's gonna use IPV four,
it's going to be in the default VPc.
We can select the subnets. So what I would do is choose two subnets that are public.
So I'm just going to choose us East one a and one b.
We can then scroll down under security groups.
You can choose a security group that's in your default VPc.
That's going to give you the correct ports.
I'm gonna choose my web access security group and we'll go and check that
out in a moment and make sure that it has the relevant ports open
next for listeners.
We want to add an additional listener.
But first we've got to create our target group for this one.
So it's great target group.
We're going to choose iP addresses,
The target group name. I'm going to paste in Target Group one.
It's going to listen on ports 80. So the containers are on port 80
it's going to be in the same VPc. Of course
we leave the remaining defaults
and we can go down, click on next,
scroll down again
and create target group.
So that's that created. Let's go back to here. We should be able to refresh.
We should be able to find our target group.
Let's add another listener.
Now it's also going to be HTTP but of course it needs to be a different ports.
So this will be 80, 80
and we're going to create our second target group
safe. Right. Second target group,
what we're gonna do is also choose I P addresses.
We're going to call it target group-2.
Support will be 80, 80
and the remaining settings are going to be left
as defaults.
Let's create that target group.
So we now have our two target groups.
Let's go back to the wizard where we're adding our second listener,
make sure we refresh and we should find target group too.
So that's set up
and now we can simply scroll down to the bottom and create our load balancer
and that's been created for us. So we now have our application load balancer.
You should see your listener configuration like this.
So you've got the http port 80 listener going to target group one.
So it's forwarding any connections to target Group one then 80
80 is the second listener going to target group too.
So that's the way that should look make sure
that your target groups are set up correctly.
So we've added using the I. P. Target type. That's very important
And that should be the same for both.
And of course the poor is 8080 on target group too
And 80 on Target Group one.
So if you've got all those settings then that's it for this lesson.
And what we're going to do in the next lesson is continue by creating our
Fargate cluster and service that's going to use
this load balancer and our task definition.