Hi guys and welcome to E C S lab Part three in this lesson,
we're going to create our Fargate cluster and a service
and we're going to leverage the components we've already created,
including our image in our pcr repository,
our task definition in e C s and our application load balancer.
So this is where we are.
We have our task definition and our load balancer with our target groups
in this lesson, we'll create the Fargate cluster, we'll create the E C S service
and we're going to run a task and that task is going to be based off our task definition
and our task definition of course is going to use the image in the repository.
So it's configured to pull the image from
the CCR private repository that we created earlier.
So let's head back over to the instructions and see what we need to do.
So in the instructions were now on part
three here create Fargate cluster and service.
We need to go and create our Fargate cluster.
Now I'm going to call it this particular name.
My C E C S lab cluster with some dashes in the middle.
So in the CS management console I'm going to create a new cluster.
I'm going to paste in my cluster name
for networking.
What I want to do is remember we actually specified us
East one A and one B for our load balancer.
So I'm just going to remove the other subnets so that I only end up with A and B.
So it moves them around a little.
So watch out which ones you remove or you can always add them back in again. Very easy.
So I've now got one A and one B.
Now this is going to use the Fargate type so this is going to use serverless.
We're gonna leave that selected of course you can't change it
anyway but we don't need to select either of these options
and we're just gonna create our cluster so that will just take a moment to create.
Now back in our file here, we can see that the next thing we need to do
is we need to change on the command line to
a directory with the create service dot Jason file.
And we're going to run these two commands. Now let's have a look at this file.
This is gonna take a little bit of work to set up.
So here is the file.
Now make sure first
that your cluster name is set up correctly.
So it needs to be
my e CS lab cluster if you've copied
the same as me,
we then got our task definition here.
So let's go to E C s and check what our task definition is called.
So back in the CS let's go to task definitions and sure enough we have this E C S
lab and if I click on it then the revision is that it's ccs dash lab colon one.
So here it was called the CS Demo. So I'm just going to change that CCS Lab one
and it's got the correct
cluster name
Next we need to get the A R N. For our load balancer so we need to paste that into here.
That's gonna be the A R N for our primary target group.
So let's head back over to ec two.
I'm gonna come scroll down on the left here to target groups
and I'm gonna copy the A. R. N. Of target group one
and I'm gonna paste that into my file.
Next we have our launch type. That's fine. Replica is fine.
The deployment controller, we're going to use codedeploy a bit later on.
So that's all correct. The only other things we need to change A here.
So the Sub Net I D s and the security group I. D.
So the sub net idea,
let's head over to the VPC management console and we want to find the I
D S for RV Pcs are subnets within us East one A and one B.
So I'm in the VPC management console. Let's go to subnets
And what we're looking for. I know that these ones with a tag on them with a name.
Those are in my custom VPC. And so what I'm looking for our us East one a
and one B.
And I know that these subnets are the ones from my default VPC.
So I can simply copy the sub net I D. From here. That's us East one
A
back in my file here. I'm simply going to paste that in. So I've got the first Sub net I.
D.
Let's then find
us east one B.
And I want to make sure it's the one,
this is the one here. So let's just follow that across.
So this is now my Sub Net I. D. For my
subnets in the default VPc. And US East one B. So I'm gonna copy that Sub Net I. D.
Back in the file. Let's just paste that in.
And the last thing that I want to do
is find my security group ID.
So what I'm going to do now is go to security groups,
we use the web access security group and that is in the default VPc.
So I'm gonna just find the security group I. D. Here.
Let's just copy that or I can copy it from here. That's probably better.
So copy my security group I. D. Let's come back and let's paste that in.
So that file is now set up correctly. I'm gonna save that file.
Let's go back to our instructions so we can see that we now have this
command to run.
Everything should be correct in that command. I don't need to change anything.
They're back on the command line so of course I'm in the directory in the code E. C. S.
And in here I should have that file so create dash service dot Jason.
So now I can run this command
and that looks like it's worked successfully. So we should now have a service
that's going to run,
let's go back to the Ec two management console and see how that looks.
So back in the CS under clusters,
I'm going to choose my CS lab cluster
and we can see I have a service here
and if I click on that service it's gonna give
me quite a bit of information about the service.
Now the other thing I can do
is I can actually go back up to my cluster level,
let's go to tasks and we should see we have a running task
and that task has a public I. P. So I can go straight to that task
and we can see engine X is actually working.
And then also if I come back to load balances,
let's copy the DNS name of my load balancer
and check that we can access here. So that looks good.
And you know,
if you don't get if you get it timing
out then your security groups aren't set up correctly.
But this is what you should see now that's all working correctly,
which means everything that we've run has worked.
Now the other command here which does have the
cluster nine minutes to make sure that's correct.
This just helps you to describe services on the command line.
So if you want to run that one,
it's just another way of retrieving this information on the cli
so that's it for the E C. S. Lab in this section.
But we're gonna leave things running so don't destroy anything.
Leave it running and we're gonna pick it up in the next section.
So between now and then you're going to learn a bit about the developer tools.
The various developer tools including a codecommit codepipeline and codedeploy.
And there's also going to be a few more hands
on lessons before we get back to this where you're
going to start learning some of the building blocks of
codepipeline codecommit and codebuild as well using elastic beanstalk.
But do leave this running and hopefully if you
can get to this fairly soon you know it's
not gonna be running for too long and it should mostly be within the free tier as well.
So hope you enjoyed this so far.
Leave things running and we'll pick it up in the next section.