Hi guys and welcome to this section.
This section is on the AWS management services as well as some security services.
So we're going to look at things like performance monitoring
tools like amazon cloudwatch auditing tools like AWS cloud trail
services for creating and managing encryption keys like the
key management service.
And we're also going to look at services for storing our secrets,
including parameter store and AWS secrets manager.
Those are ways that we can store things
like database connection credentials or passwords or access keys
so that they're securely stored and can be accessed via an API call.
And lastly, we'll look at amazon Cognito,
a service that doesn't come up too often in an exam but we'll cover some basic theory.
Cognito is used for enabling Sign in and sign up for mobile applications.
So I hope you enjoy it. And I'll see you in the next lesson.