Hi, guys. In this lesson, I'm going to cover Amazon CloudWatch. Now, we've already used CloudWatch
a few times in the course so far.
So, as you know, it's a performance monitoring tool. And we've seen some of the metrics that get sent
to CloudWatch by certain services like EC2 and Lambda.
Now I'm going to give you a bit more the theory around CloudWatch, what its use cases are, and a few
of the details about the types of information that's collected by CloudWatch.
CloudWatch is principally a performance monitoring tool.
You can also use it to trigger alarms
based on that performance information, you can have automated actions set up,
and it collects log files from your resources and applications as well.
So, what are some of the use cases and benefits?
Well, you can use CloudWatch for collecting performance metrics from your AWS services as well as
on-premises resources as well, which we'll look a bit later on in the section.
You can automate responses to operational changes, so state changes in your resources or performance
metrics that are coming in telling you that a resource is overloaded or underused.
You can improve operational performance and resource optimization.
So, helping you to understand how your resources are performing, do they need more resource or less?
You can derive actionable insights from the logs that are collected and get operational visibility and
insights.
There are a few core features of CloudWatch.
First, you've got CloudWatch Metrics.
These are time audit data that's sent from your service like EC2 to CloudWatch. CloudWatch then
collects that data and you can graph it and respond to that information.
We then have CloudWatch alarms.
This means you can monitor metrics and then initiate actions.
We've seen alarms working when we used auto scaling groups and we responded to the amount of load on
our EC2 instance.
CloudWatch Logs is a centralized collection system for your system and application logs.
And then we have CloudWatch Events.
Now this is responding to state changes in your resources. As you know from earlier in the course Event
Bridge is a service that's based on CloudWatch Events. They're basically the same thing, but it's separated
into a different console. So, you can think of CloudWatch Events and Amazon EventBridge as being the
same thing.
Let's drill into metrics in a bit more detail. So, the metrics are sent to CloudWatch by AWS services.
Now, with EC2, it's important to remember that they're sent every five minutes by default and
you don't pay for that.
Or every one minute if you enable detailed monitoring and you do have to pay something for that.
There's then the Unified CloudWatch Agent.
This sends system level metrics for your EC2 instances and your on-premises servers as well.
It's called unified because it also collects log files as well as metrics.
System level metrics include memory and disk usage.
So, you do have to use the Unified CloudWatch Agent if you want to monitor memory and disk usage, something
that comes up in quite a few exam questions.
It's important to understand without the Unified CloudWatch Agent, the default metrics sent by EC2
do not include memory utilization or disk usage.
So, quite simply, the way it all works is you have EC2, you have CloudWatch, and your EC2 instance is
sending metrics either every five minutes or every one minute.
Then if you install the Unified CloudWatch Agent, you also get additional information which includes
memory and disk usage.
There's more than that, but those are two of the important ones to remember for the exam.
I've concentrated a bit on EC2 here, but of course, metrics get sent by almost all AWS services.
You can also publish custom metrics. So, this means you can collect whatever information you want to
from your instances or from your other applications and send that via the CLI or the API to CloudWatch.
Custom metrics come in two different resolutions.
You got standard resolution or high resolution. With standard,
the granularity is one minute and with high, your data granularity goes right down to one second.
The AWS metrics are standard resolution by default.
Next up we have CloudWatch Alarms.
There's two types of alarm.
You have a metric alarm which performs one or more actions based on a single metric and you have a
composite alarm. And that uses a rule to take into account multiple alarms at the same time.
There are multiple different alarm states.
OK
is when the metric is within a threshold.
Alarm is when the metric is outside of the threshold.
And then insufficient data is when the service simply doesn't have enough information yet to make a
determination.
So, we've seen alarms working with auto scaling
earlier in the course. We had Amazon EC2 sending data to CloudWatch about the CPU utilization of the
instances. When a threshold is breached,
CloudWatch then sends an alarm to auto scaling and auto scaling knows to run more instances.
That's it for the core theory on CloudWatch.
And in the next lesson, we'll see how we can send a custom metric to CloudWatch from EC2.