Hi, guys. In this lesson, we're going to use the command line to send a custom metric to CloudWatch
from Amazon EC2. There's a file here from the course download in the CloudWatch folder, EC2-custom-
metrics. And we're going to use these commands to PUT metric data.
So, it's an AWS CloudWatch command.
The API action is PUT metric data. And then we supply some information about the metric.
Now, I'm just making this up, right?
This is just information which I'm putting in.
So, in other words, I can send whatever metrics I want.
Now, what you might want to do in the real world is actually find information from your EC2 instance.
There's things like Perl Scripts from AWS that can do that for you.
In fact, I've added a link to an article from AWS which shows you how to do that.
Now, that article is deprecated because what it's actually trying to do is now covered by the Unified
CloudWatch Agent which is a much better way of doing it.
But essentially, what it does is run some scripts and finds out information about the resource utilization
of your instance.
And then it will send PUT metric data API commands to CloudWatch.
So what we're doing is just creating our own.
So, I've created a metric name of Bytes.
I've got my own custom namespace.
The unit will be bytes. And then the value is whatever value I want to put in there.
And the dimensions is then where we can put in the instance ID of our instance.
So we need to get that in a moment.
The second one has a metric name of Latency in the same namespace.
The unit is milliseconds, and then we have a value for the latency.
And again, we need to enter our instance ID.
So there's a couple of things we need to do to get moving.
Firstly, I've already launched a t2.micro Amazon Linux 2 AMI.
I need to get the instance ID here. Back in my file where it says instance-ID,
I'm just going to paste the real instance ID over the top.
So, I have that now.
The next thing I need is a role which I'm going to attach to my instance using an instance profile.
And that role will supply the permissions to be able to put the metric data in the CloudWatch.
So let's create a new role.
Use case will be EC2. Click on next.
I need to attach a policy.
I'm going to search for CloudWatch agent and I want this CloudWatch agent server policy.
If you expand this one and look at the JSON, you'll see the action CloudWatch PUT metric data here.
So that's going to be allowed. So, I'm going to select this policy.
Click on next.
Go to review.
I'm going to give it a name, which in this case is the same as the policy name and then create that
role.
Now, I've created the role. I can go back and attach it to my instance using an instance profile.
So, in this case, we're going to select our instance, choose actions, security, modify
IAM role, and then we're going to select the role which we just created, which is this one here,
CloudWatch agent server policy.
So let's save that role. And now we should have the permissions we need.
You'll now need to connect to your instance using SSH. And then we're going to copy this entire command
making sure your region is specified correctly and you've updated your instance
ID. I'm connected to my instance using SSH. So, I'm going to put in this command, hit enter. That's
been accepted.
Copy the second command and run that command now as well.
So, those two commands have been run.
The next thing to do is to go over to CloudWatch and let's see if we can see those metrics being
recorded in the CloudWatch console.
In CloudWatch, let's choose all metrics on the left hand side here. And straightaway
we can see under custom namespaces that I've got this my custom namespace. And that's the one that
we defined in our command line.
We can then see that we have the dimensions of instance ID and instance type. And then we have the
two metrics which we just sent, bytes and latency.
So that worked correctly.
Now that's it for this lesson. But I'm going to leave my instance running. And in the next lesson,
we'll see how we can add an alarm for our custom metrics.