Welcome back. So, this is continuing on from the previous lesson.
And you should have your EC2 instance running and you should be connected to it via SSH. And you also
need an IAM role allowing you permissions to put metric data to Amazon CloudWatch.
Back in Amazon CloudWatch, I'm going to select all alarms under alarms, create alarm, select metric.
I'm going to choose my custom namespace and then drill into the dimension and I'm going to choose the
latency metric.
Let's select that metric. And what I want to do here is under statistic, I'm going to set it to maximum.
Period,
I'm going to set two one minute. And then under whenever latency is greater than, I'm going to enter
my threshold, which I'm going to set as 30. I can then click next.
I'm going to remove the notification.
I don't want a notification
in this example. I'm going to add an EC2 action when the state is in alarm, and what I'm going to
do is terminate the instance.
So what should happen here is if the latency value exceeds 30, then the instance will be automatically
terminated due to the CloudWatch alarm.
So that's all I need to do here. Let's click on next.
Give it a name.
Mine will be called Latency Too High. Click next. And then I'm happy with all the settings here.
So let's scroll down and create the alarm.
So, the alarm has been created. At the moment
it's saying insufficient data because there isn't enough data for it to make a determination.
Now, back in the command line, we have this third command here which is going to trigger the alarm.
I just need to make sure I copy my instance ID from the previous command there and paste it in where
it says instance-ID.
And then I can copy the entire command. And back on the command line here where I'm logged in to my
EC2 instance, I can hit enter. Now
in this case, we are running the PUT metric data for the latency metric and the value is 35,
so it definitely exceeds the threshold of 30.
So let's hit enter there. You can even run it a couple of times if you want to see a little more data.
And now we can just go back and see what happens.
Back in the CloudWatch console, we can see that our Latency Too High alarm is in the alarm state.
So what should happen now is our EC2 instance should be terminated automatically. Back in EC2,
let's refresh the page here.
And sure enough, it's been terminated.
So, that's it for this lesson. And there's nothing to clean up.
It's all been done for us.
I'll see you in the next lesson.