In this lesson, we're going to look at cloudwatch logs.
So Cloudwatch logs is used to gather and centralize application and system logs
in Cloudwatch. So these can come from your applications from system logs.
They can come from AWS services and they can
come from on premises systems with the agent installed.
You can define expiration policies and you can enable encryption using a KMS key.
You can send data to Amazon S3, that's an export
kinesis data streams
and kinesis data firehose.
So we've got cloudwatch logs here,
EC2
on the left hand side
and some on premises systems on the right hand side,
the unified Cloudwatch agent is installed on EC2 and on the on premises servers.
And then
those different servers can send information to Cloudwatch logs
that includes application logs
and system logs.
AWS LAMBDA can also send
to cloudwatch logs and it will require permissions to cloudwatch logs.
So remember,
you've always got to make sure you give the right permissions to LAMBDA.
Now, information from Cloudwatch logs
can be sent to
the Amazon Elasticsearch service as well and you
get real time log processing with subscription filters
that can apply also to lambda
and kinesis.
So let's have a look at some features of cloudwatch.
Cloudwatch logs insights can be used to interactively search and analyze
the log data in cloudwatch logs.
You can monitor applications and systems using log data.
You can create alarms based on API activity
that's captured by cloud trail.
By default, the logs are kept indefinitely so they don't expire,
but you can adjust the retention period for each log group.
And that can range from one day to 10 years of retention.
Cloudwatch logs can also be used to log information about DNS queries
that are received by the Amazon route 53 service.
Now, some of the core concepts, of course, we've got log events,
that's a record of activity recorded by a service that's monitored.
Log streams are a sequence of log events that share the same source
log groups are groups of log streams that share the same retention monitoring
and access control settings.
Metric filters are used to extract metric observations from ingested events
and transform them to data points
in a cloudwatch metric.
And then lastly,
the retention settings specify how long events are kept in cloudwatch logs.