In this lesson, we're going to go and have a look at CloudWatch logs and a few of the features.
So back in CloudWatch, on the left hand side we have logs and then log groups and log insights.
Let's choose log groups.
Now we've already logged quite a few times.
Sometimes you wouldn't have realized it in this course because the applications that we created automatically
logs to CloudWatch Logs. For example, our Fargate cluster sent some information here
based on the performance. We can actually see that there's telemetry data.
Now, you can also see that the retention varies. So that information has expired now because it was only
held here for one day.
You can also set it to never expire or whatever value you want, like five days, for example.
The top level here is the log group. And you can see through this hierarchy what service is being referenced.
So here we have AWS Lambda and then a function.
So, all of the information related to that function will be in here.
We have another one here, the product visits data handler, which is from an earlier lesson in the
serverless section.
If we go into the log group, you'll then find the log streams.
If you open the log streams, you then get the log events.
Each series of events will have a start, an end, and a report.
And then in the middle you might have these info events as well.
So, if you expand the start, then it just simply gives you some information on the request and a timestamp.
The end tells you when it finished with a timestamp and a request ID.
And then the report in this case gives you information such as the duration that the function ran,
the build duration, and the memory size.
And then you also see these info events.
Here you can see the JSON code that went into the SQS message.
And then the next one along shows the JSON of the actual product that was purchased through our online
store.
Back up a level, we can see we have a few additional features.
Metric filters allow you to monitor events in your log group and do things like counting the specific
terms or values that are coming up in the log data.
Then we have subscription filters. Here
if we create a subscription filter, we get to choose from a few different services.
We've got ElasticSearch, we've got Kinesis, Kinesis Firehose, and Lambda.
And that means that the information as it comes in the CloudWatch logs is going to get forwarded to
the subscribers like an AWS Lambda function, which then might want to process that data as it
arrives.
Now, I also want to show you the log insights. Within logs insights,
what you can do is select your log groups.
So let's say that we select several different log groups here, and then you can run a query.
And this particular query is going to find the most recent 20 events from across the log groups. So, we
can choose a time.
I'm going to use absolute and let's just put in the last few weeks and then click on run query.
And what we get is the most recent 20 events that have been logged into CloudWatch logs.
And of course, you could just go and change that to 200 or whatever you want, and you can run all
sorts of other queries with logs insights.
So, logs insights is a great way of finding those insights into whatever's happening in your logging.
So, that's all I wanted to cover in this hands-on lesson.
I'll see you in the next one.