In this lesson, I want to cover a few more details around the Unified CloudWatch Agent.
So, the Unified CloudWatch Agent enables you to collect internal system-level metrics from Amazon EC2
instances across different operating system versions.
You can collect system-level metrics from on-premises servers as well. And you can retrieve custom
metrics from your applications or services and it uses the StatsD and collect the protocols.
You can also collect logs from your EC2 instances and on-premises servers for Windows and Linux operating
systems.
The agent must be installed on the server and you can install the Unified CloudWatch Agent on Amazon
EC2 and on-premises servers with the Linux, Windows, or macOS operating systems.
So, there are a couple of things which I want you to take note of in terms of exam questions.
Firstly, of course, I've made it very clear that you can install this agent on both these servers,
in EC2 and also your on-premises servers.
Now also remember that this is sending log information. And it's essentially in near real time.
So, one of the things that sometimes comes up is you want to be able to capture log files when EC2 instances
might be terminated by something like an auto scaling group.
In that case, once the instance is terminated, you've lost access to that data.
But if you were using the Unified CloudWatch Agent, those log files would be sent as they're being generated.
So, you'll have that record of the log files in CloudWatch.
Another thing that comes up a lot is the difference between standard metrics and the metrics that you
get from the Unified CloudWatch Agent.
Now there's an AWS article linked to this lesson and I'm going to take you there now to go through
a few of those metrics.
When you install the Unified CloudWatch Agent, you get some more advanced metrics.
Now, if you have a Windows server instance, what will happen is it will collect the metrics associated
with the Windows performance monitor.
So, whatever information is included in Windows performance monitor is now going to be put into Cloud
Watch logs.
There's then some advanced metrics for ENA,
it doesn't really come up much. But then there's the metrics that you get for your Linux and Mac OS
operating systems.
And as you can see, there's really quite a long list here.
Now, don't worry, you don't need to memorize all of these.
I'll just focus on the ones that do come up a lot.
So, if I keep scrolling down to disk,
we'll see that there's quite a few metrics associated with the disk.
We can see the free space on the disks, we can see the used space on the disks, the percentage that's
being used.
None of that stuff comes through in the standard CloudWatch metrics for EC2.
So, you always need the Unified CloudWatch Agent to get that sort of on-disk level metrics.
If we scroll down a bit further and come down to where we have some memory statistics, here, again,
you've got things like the percentage of memory that's available, the amount of memory that's active,
and the amount of memory that's available to be used by some process.
So, these kind of utilization statistics with disk and memory don't come through in the standard metrics
for EC2.
So that's where you need the Unified CloudWatch Agent.