As CloudTrail is a service that you can use for capturing information about the API actions that are
happening in your AWS account. So, as you know, whenever you do anything in AWS like launch an EC2
instance or create a Lambda function or modify a resource, every single time you do that, you're
generating an API action.
Now, it doesn't matter whether you're using the management console, the CLI, the API, or the SDK.
Whichever way you're doing it, you're always generating an API action. And lots of that information
related to that API
action can be logged by CloudTrail so you can monitor it for auditing purposes.
So, CloudTrail logs API activity and the principal use case for that is auditing.
It gives you a chance to understand who did what and when and on what resources.
By default, management events are logged and retained for 90 days.
Now, that might be insufficient for you.
So, what you can do is create what's called a CloudTrail trail, and then you can log events to S3 for
indefinite retention.
Each trail that you create can be within a region or it can be applied to all regions.
We can even use CloudWatch events to trigger actions based on API calls that are made and logged in
CloudTrail.
And we'll see that in the hands-on in this section.
Events can also be streamed to CloudWatch logs as well, so that's another place that you can record
them.
Typically, they go to Amazon S3 and then you can additionally log them to CloudWatch logs as well.
And that might be useful if you want to do things like use metric filters,
subscription filters, or logs insights.
So, we have AWS CloudTrail. And it's going to log API actions for 90 days by default.
We can then choose to create a trail and log our events to Amazon S3 and then they're retained
indefinitely.
We can also enable something called log file integrity validation.
What this does is it checks whether the events that are being logged have been tampered with. Because
this information is used for auditing and compliance,
we need to be sure that the information is accurate and has not been modified.
Using CloudTrail, we can trigger notifications through SNS topics when CloudTrail publishes log
files.
We can also forward our data to CloudWatch logs and then through logs we might do things like use alarms
or subscription filters. Our alarms might trigger Lambda functions or SNS topics, and then we might
want to process that information in CloudWatch Logs.
We can also forward information to CloudWatch Events and then we might want to trigger a Lambda function
that way.
And remember, this is all based on API actions.
So when an API event occurs, we're then responding to that, logging that information, perhaps generating
some kind of event
so we have an automated action, or forwarding the data to CloudWatch Logs so that we can process it
or create alarms based on that information.
So there's lots of ways that we can use the information that's generated by CloudTrail.
Now there are a few different types of events.
Firstly, we have management events.
These provide information about the management operations that you perform on your resources.
So, if you launch an EC2 instance or terminate an instance or create a database or create a Lambda
function, all of these are management operations.
And when you enable management events, the information about who generated the API action, at
what time, and on what resource will all be logged into the CloudTrail logs.
Next, we have data events.
These provide more detailed information about the resource operations performed on or in a resource.
And there's a few different types of service that we can use here.
I'll show you in the console so you get a better idea of that shortly.
But S3 is one example.
So, you can get more detailed information about what's happening within Amazon S3 if you enable data
events.
And then we have insights events.
These are relatively new. Here
you can identify and respond to any unusual activity that's taking place in your account that's associated
with write API calls.
So that's the core theory.
And in the next lesson, we're going to go into CloudTrail and create our first trail.