Hey guys.
In this lesson, you're going to learn about the AWS key management service. KMS.
KMS is a service that's used to create and manage encryption keys.
You can create symmetric and asymmetric encryption keys with KMS.
The KMS keys are protected by hardware security modules or HSM
that means they're stored very securely.
So perhaps a developer wants to create and use KMS keys for encrypting information
on AWS.
In that case, the developer can create customer managed keys.
These are keys that are created and managed by the developer. There's also AWS
managed keys,
these are created and managed by AWS,
but you can use them with certain services and AWS KMS
integrates with many AWS services.
I'm just showing a few examples of some of the keys that they provide.
So for example, for SQS the simple queue service
and ACM, the AWS certificate manager,
EBS the elastic block store
and FSX for storing data in the FSX file systems.
So you can encrypt data in all of those
different locations using keys that are managed by AWS.
Don't forget that when the developer here creates their own keys,
those are called customer managed KMS keys.
Now KMS keys are the most important resource to understand with KMS
KMS keys are the most important resource to understand in KMS.
They used to be known as customer master keys or CMKs.
So you might occasionally even on the exam, see that terminology still used,
the KMS key contains the key material that is used to encrypt and decrypt data.
And by default, KMS will create the key material for KMS key.
But optionally, you can import your own key material into AWS as well.
Now,
you need to remember that KMS key itself can
only encrypt data up to four kilobytes in size.
So that's a fairly small amount of data.
Now, you might want to encrypt very large volumes of data.
In that case,
the KMS key can be used to generate encrypt
and decrypt something called a data encryption key.
And the data encryption key is what you use for encrypting large volumes of data.
There are also alternative ways that you can store your KMS keys outside of KMS.
One is known as an external key store.
Here
keys can be stored outside of AWS and you
might want to do that for meeting regulatory requirements.
When you use an external key store,
you can create a KMS key in what's known as a KMS external key store or XKS.
All keys are generated and stored
in an external key manager.
And when using an XKS,
the key material does not leave your hardware security module.
Another option is a custom key store.
You can create KMS keys in what's called AWS cloud HSM.
That's the custom key store. It's a different service.
All keys are then generated and stored in the cloud HSM cluster
that you own and manage.
So that's dedicated infrastructure just for you. When using a custom key store.
The cryptographic operations are performed solely in the
cloudhsm cluster that you own and manage.
By the way, custom key stores are not available for asymmetric KMS keys.
Now let's look at the AWS managed KMS key.
So as I mentioned,
there is integration with hundreds of AWS services and
KMS will manage some of those keys for you.
So these ones are created managed and used on your
behalf by an AWS service that's integrated with AWS KMS.
You cannot manage these keys, you cannot rotate them or change their key policies.
So you don't have control, you can just use them.
You also cannot use AWS managed KMS keys
in cryptographic operation directly.
It's the actual service that you're utilizing that does that for you.
So for example, if you're configuring
Amazon S3 to use A KMS key that's managed by AWS,
all you're really doing is enabling encryption.
It's A W S that are handling all of the cryptographic operations.
You're not doing it in your code on your application.
So let's look at data encryption keys. Now,
these are the ones that you can use to encrypt large amounts of data.
So remember if it's over four kilobytes, you need to you a DEK,
you can use KMS keys to generate encrypt and decrypt.
The data encryption keys and KMS doesn't storm manage or track
these keys or perform the cryptographic operations with the data keys.
So that means that must be done
in your code and also you must use and manage data keys
outside of KMS. So that means your writing code in your application to utilize
the data encryption keys. One important topic for the exam is rotation of KMS keys
and this table helps you to understand the differences depending on the type of key.
So we have the customer managed key. That's something you can view,
you can manage it
and it's only used within your account. Now, automatic rotation
is optional, but you can perform it every 365 days.
So this is changing the key material that your key users
with the AWS managed keys. You can see them,
you have no management capabilities
and they are actually used Within your account only.
And in this case, automatic rotation is required. You can't configure that
and it happens every 365 days.
Lastly, there's something called an AWS owned key.
These you cannot view you cannot manage and they're not only used for your account,
they're just used in general.
So really these are just encryption keys that are
being used that are completely outside of your control.
But AWS is encrypting data.
For example, network traffic, you cannot enable or disabled key rotation
for AWS own keys and automatic key rotation is supported only
on symmetric encryption keys with key material that's generated by KMS.
That means the origin equals AWS underscore KMS.
Now, as I mentioned before,
AWS will rotate the keys every single year and
that is optional for the customer managed keys.
Now, when the keys are rotated,
it means the key material used for encryption changes.
But the actual encryption key ID will stay the same as you can see
in this little diagram here.
So that means you don't need to change your applications. They can still use the ID
of the same key.
But we have some new key material that's being
used for encrypting data with automatic key rotation.
The properties of the KMS key
including its key ID
ARN region policies and permissions
do not change when the key is rotated.
You don't need to change your applications or aliases that refer to the key id or ARN
of the key.
So that means minimal disruption for your
applications after you enable key rotation,
KMS will rotate the key automatically every year.
Automatic key rotation is not supported for certain types of KMS key.
Those are asymmetric KMS keys,
HMAC KMS keys,
keys in custom key stores in other words, cloudhsm
and KMS keys with imported key material.
So that means you imported some key material of your own
rather than using the key material that AWS KMS generates.
Now, by the way, you can rotate these KMS keys, but you need to do it manually.
So what is manual rotation? Well, that's when
you create a new KMS key with a different key ID.
You need to then update your applications with the new key ID.
So it's a little bit more disruptive, you can use an alias, however,
to represent a KMS key.
And in that case, you, you don't need to modify your application code.
So you might have an application
that application utilizes an alias
to refer to the key.
Now when you generate then a new key, well,
the alias just points to the new key and
you don't need to change your application code.
So essentially the alias is associated with the new KMS key.
It's important to understand KMS key policies,
these define the management and usage permissions for KMS keys.
Now this one here defines the administrative actions
that are permitted for a KMS key administrator.
So we can see this is an allow and then we have a variety of KMS actions
including describe and put and create an update and so on.
So these are the administrative actions that are
permitted for the administrators of the keys.
Multiple policy statements can be combined to separate
administrative and usage permissions.
So this one defines the cryptographic actions for
encrypting and decrypting data with the KMS key.
So you see this is not administrative, this is actual usage of the key.
So encrypting, decrypting and re encrypting data
permissions can be specified for delegating use of the key to AWS services.
And these are known as grants.
Grants are useful for temporary permissions as they can be
used without modifying the key policies or IAM policies.
So here we can see
the actions here are create grant list grant
and revoke grant.
Now let's go over some additional exam tips
to share snapshots with another account
You need to specify the decrypt and create grant permissions
so that it is possible
the KMS via service condition key can be used
to limit the usage to specific AWS services.
So for example,
you can create a condition such as this one where the string equals KMS via service.
And then we have two services listed EC2 and RDS.
That means
this key policy is restricting usage of the key to those two specific services.
Cryptographic erasure
is a technique for removing the ability to decrypt data.
Now, you use this technique when you have imported key material
and you subsequently delete that key material.
So if you think it's been exposed and you don't
want somebody to be able to decrypt the data,
then you can use the delete imported key material API to remove the
key material and then it's never going to be possible again to decrypt that data.
So be sure you know what you're doing an
invalid key ID exception when using SSN parameter store
indicates the KMS key
is not enabled. Another one that comes up in the odd exam question
and also make sure you know the differences
between AWS managed and customer managed KMS keys,
especially in the area of automatic versus manual rotation.