AWS Systems Manager is a service that's not really covered much in the Solutions Architects associate
exam.
You'll find it a lot in the SysOps
Administrator Associate. Now, systems manager is used for managing resources such as Amazon EC2. And
there's quite a few different components to Systems Manager.
Now, the one which I want to discuss for this lesson is Systems Manager Parameter Store, also known
as SSM Parameter Store.
This service is used for storing secrets and configuration information, so it's essentially a hierarchical
storage solution that allows you to store this information securely.
It's highly scalable, available, and durable. And it's used for storing things such as passwords,
database connection strings, and license codes. And those are stored as parameter values.
You can store values as plaintext, so unencrypted information or as ciphertext, so you can encrypt
that information in SSM parameter store as well.
You can reference values by using the unique name that you specify when you create the parameter.
And as I mentioned, it's hierarchical as well, so you can create a hierarchy of paths to those values,
which you can then use in your application code.
Now there's no native rotation of the keys, and that's a difference with Secrets Manager, which does
do it automatically, and we're going to cover AWS Secrets Manager in another lesson.
So what this effectively means is there's no native function within SSM parameter store for updating
a password value.
Now you can do it, but you have to do it externally using a service like AWS Lambda.
Let's have a look at how this works in a very simple diagram.
So we've got Amazon EC2, we've got parameter store, and an RDS database. And what we want to do here
is connect from our EC2 instance to our RDS database.
But maybe we don't want to store the password or even the connection string in the EC2 application
code.
Instead, we store that information in parameter store and in our application code, we reference that
information so we can now make a call to parameter store to find out what the connection information
is.
Then, once the EC2 instance has that information, it's able to connect to the RDS database.
So that's just one simple example of where you would store your connection string and maybe your password
in parameter store.
So that's really it. It's fairly simple.
You don't need to know much more than that.
And as I mentioned in a couple of lessons time, we're going to cover Secrets Manager, which is very
similar and it has some different characteristics.
And I'll point out the differences between the two at the time so that you're clear on how they are
different from each other.