AWS Secrets Manager is designed for storing your secrets like your database connection information
or your passwords.
It's similar to the SSM Parameter Store that we looked at earlier on, but there are a few key differences.
Secrets Manager will store and rotate your secrets safely without needing to create your own custom
code.
So, in other words, it's offering automatic rotation, and that's built in for a few specific services.
We've got Amazon RDS with these specific engines.
We've got Redshift and Amazon Document DB. For any services that are not in that list,
you'll need to write your own custom Lambda function to rotate your secrets
same as you would with parameters store.
So let's have a look at a diagram.
We've got Lambda, RDS, and Secrets Manager.
Our Lambda function is going to pull a secret from Secrets Manager and use that to actually connect
to and authenticate to the RDS database.
Now, the additional thing that we have here with Secrets Manager is in this case because it's Amazon
RDS, we can have automatic rotation of those secrets under some kind of periodic change.
So let's just summarize the differences between Secrets Manager and Parameters Store.
Automatic key rotation is built in for some services with Secrets Manager. For any other services
you can write a Lambda function to rotate them for you.
There's no native key rotation with Parameters Store, so your only option is to write your own custom
Lambda function. With Secrets Manager,
the key value type is string or binary, and it's always encrypted with KMS.
Now you get to store up to 64 kilobytes, so you got quite a lot of information that you can store there
which is more than with Parameters Store. With Parameters Store,
you can store a string, a string list, or secure string, and you can enable encryption, which is also
through KMS.
Now you don't get hierarchical keys with Secrets Manager, but you do with Parameter Store.
The price for Secrets Manager is per secret and with Parameters
Store, it's free for the standard up to a certain volume and then you pay charges for the advanced
and also, for higher throughput as well.
So that's what I want to cover in this lesson.
I will see you in the next one.