Welcome to this hands-on lesson.
In this lesson, we're going to go into AWS Secrets Manager,
have a look at the console,
create a secret and then we're going to go to the command line
as well and see how we can work with Secrets Manager using the CLI.
So I'm on the Secrets Manager console here.
Let's click on store a new secret.
And straight away we have a few decisions to make. So what's the secret type?
Is it going to be credentials for an RDS database, DocumentDB,
a Redshift cluster, or some other type of database or any other type of secret,
like an API key and an OAuth token and so on.
Now, if you do choose
the RDS database, you do actually need to have a database.
And we don't have one.
So what we're going to do is choose other type of secrets.
And we're simply going to create our secret as a key value pair.
So for example, maybe it's a password for our administrative account.
So I'm going to put in admin
and then I'm just going to say my password.
Now, as you can see it's going to use an encryption key
and by default it's going to use an AWS Managed Key.
So you know that because it says AWS/ and then Secrets Manager.
So you can choose other keys if you want to
as long as Secrets Manager does have the permissions to use that key.
I'm going to use the default key here
and click on next.
Just give it a name.
I'm just going to call this My Credentials.
You can then optionally add tags,
you can edit the resource permissions and you can choose
to replicate your secret if you want to as well.
We'll click on next, and this is where
we have the configuration for automatic rotation.
So remember Secrets Manager does do automatic rotation
but it's only going to work out of the box for certain databases.
So if I enable automatic rotation here for my custom secret,
I'm going to need to choose
a Lambda rotation function, and of course I don't have one.
I would need to write my own Lambda code
that rotates the secret.
So I'm just going to disable rotation.
Click on next.
Scroll down.
And we can see some sample code here for using our secret in an application.
And I'm just going to choose store.
And it's as simple as that. We now have our secret stored in AWS Secrets Manager.
Now if we come in here we can see some information,
the encryption key that's being used, the name, it has its own ARN.
And we can retrieve the secret value if we wish to as well.
So of course you've got to be careful who has permissions to view this information.
Now, that's it for the console. What I want to do now is go to the command line
and we're going to see how we can work with the command line.
Now, you'll find this file in the course, downloads.
Obviously it's in the code directory,
AWS Secrets Manager and it's called Secrets Manager CLI commands.
And these are the commands that we're going to use.
So I'm simply going to copy the command one by one to my clipboard.
And on the command line here I'm going to type in AWS Secrets Manager list secrets.
And of course we did create a secret before so we can see the ARN,
the name of that secret, the last change date, access date,
and some more information.
So let's quit out of there and go and see what the next command is.
So the next command is to actually create a secret.
So we're going to run AWS Secrets Manager, create secret,
we give it a name, it's going to be called deV DB secret.
And then we can give it a description
and then the actual secret string.
So this is the actual secret we're trying to store.
So I'm going to copy all of this to my clipboard
and back on the command line,
let's hit enter.
And that should have created the secret for us.
So now if I go back up to my previous command to list secrets,
I can now see that I have two, so I have my credentials and dev DB secret.
Now what if I actually want to retrieve the secret value from the command line?
Well, I can do that with the Secrets Manager get secret value command.
And again we just need to identify
the secret by ID which is actually the name of the secret.
So back in the command line let's put that in,
and it actually retrieves the secret string and we can
see it in plain text here on the screen.
Another command you can use is described secret.
So let's copy this to our clipboards,
paste that one in and hit enter.
Now, what you'll notice is this provides quite a bit of
information but it doesn't actually retrieve the secret value.
So this is useful when you want to know information
about the secret but not the actual secret itself.
The next command is to update the secret.
So we can run this command and what's going to happen
is it's going to change the secret value that's stored.
So if you needed to rotate your secret,
this is a way that you could do that using the CLI.
Of course, you'd be able to use the API
and there will be a very similar option for how you can update
the secret using the API that you could then put into a Lambda function code
to actually perform that for you.
So here we are running update secret.
We give it the secret ID, the name of the secret and then the new secret string.
So I pasted that onto my screen.
That has now applied the new secret.
So let's run the get secret value command again.
And we should now see that we have the new secret string returned.
So that's it for this lesson.
I just wanted to show you how to use Secrets Manager from the CLI.
Of course, in many instances you'll be using the API in code
to actually work with Secrets Manager.
Now the last thing I'm going to do here is delete my secrets.
The first one is the DEV DB secret.
So I'm going to copy this command to my clipboard,
paste that in and that will be deleted.
And then I'm simply going to go back and delete
my credentials as well.
And that's both of my secrets deleted.
So I hope that was useful. I will see you in the next lesson.