Hi guys welcome to the exam cram for management and security.
So let's get into IT.
Cloudwatch is used for performing monitoring alarms,
log collection and automated actions.
Core features are cloudwatch metrics. Cloudwatch alarms, Cloudwatch logs
and cloudwatch events
metrics are sent to cloudwatch for many AWS services.
Ec two metrics are sent every five minutes by default and that is free or you enable
detailed monitoring and then they get sent every one minute and you have to pay a fee.
Unified Cloudwatch agent sends system level metrics
for easy to and on premises servers.
They include memory and disk usage.
The unified cloudwatch agent enables you to do the following,
collect those internal system level metrics for your ec.
Two instances across operating systems
collect system level metrics from on premises servers
retrieve custom metrics from your applications or services using the stats.
D and collect the protocols
and collect logs from ec. Two instances
and on premises service for Windows and Linux.
The agent must be installed on the server. It can be installed on ec. Two on premises.
Windows server or Mac. Os.
Cloud trail logs aPI activity for auditing
by default management events are logged and retained for 90 days.
A cloud trail trail logs any events to s free for then indefinite retention.
A trial can be within a region or it can span all regions.
Cloudwatch events can be triggered based on aPI calls that are logged in.
Cloud trail
events can be extreme to cloudwatch logs.
Management events provide information about management operations that
are performed on resources in your account.
We then have data events. These provide
information about the resource operations performed on or within a resource
insights.
Events identify and respond to unusual activity associated with write
aPI calls by continuously analyzing cloud trail management events.
Kms keys are the primary resources
in AWS key management service.
They used to be known as customer master keys or C. M. K. S.
The KMs key also contains the key material used to encrypt and decrypt data
by default, KMs creates the key material for a KMs key.
You can also import your own key material.
A. K. Meskhi can encrypt data up to four kB in size.
A KMs key can generate encrypt and decrypt data encryption keys.
Automatic rotation generates new key material every year
and that's optional for customer managed keys.
It's supported for symmetric keys with key material that AWS KMs creates
to share snapshots with another account.
You must specify decrypt and create grant permissions.
The KMs via service condition key
can be used to limit key usage to specific AWS services, cryptographic.
Ihr asia means removing the ability to decrypt data and you can
achieve that by using imported key material and deleting that key material.
You must use the delete imported key material A. P. I. To remove the key material
and invalid key I. D. Exception when using the S. S. M. Parameter store
indicates the KMs key is not enabled.
Make sure you know the differences between AWS managed and
customer managed KMs keys and automatic versus manual rotation.
That's super important for the exam.
Systems manager parameter store provides secure hierarchical
storage for configuration data and secrets.
It's highly scalable, available and durable.
You can store data such as passwords, database strings and license codes
as parameter values.
It will store values as plaintext, unencrypted data or cipher text,
which is encrypted data.
It stores and rotates secrets safely without the need for code deployments.
We then have Secrets Manager,
it offers automatic rotation of credentials and that's built in
for RDS with these specific engines
or red shift
amazon document DB
and for other services you can write
your own lambda function for automatic rotation.
A cognito user pool is a directory for managing
sign in and sign up for mobile applications.
Users can also sign
in using social I. D. P. S.
Cognito acts as an identity broker between the I. D. P. And AWS
identity pools are used to obtain temporary
limited privilege credentials for accessing AWS services
identities can come from a cognito user pool
and they can also come from Social I. D. P s.
Identity paul's used the security token service to obtain the credentials
and I am role is then assumed providing access to the AWS services
and that's it for this exam Crown