Hello and welcome to this section.
In this section I'm going to cover the amazon virtual private cloud (VPC).
elastic load balancing and amazon EC2.
Now you are expected to understand these as kind
of prerequisite knowledge for the developer associate exam.
In this course I go over it at a basic level
but I do move through quite quickly.
If you want more background on these services then I go
into much more detail in the solutions architect associate course.
But for what you need to know for the developer associate exam,
this should be enough.
So in this section you're going to learn how to create your own custom VPC.
You're going to launch EC2 instances and elastic load balancers and see
how you can scale your application and load balance it for high availability
and there are plenty of hands on exercises to make
sure you get your hands dirty and enjoy the practice.