In this lesson, you're going to learn about the Amazon Elastic compute cloud, also known as EC2.
Easy two is really one of the oldest and most important services on AWS, and it's the service that
we can use to run virtual servers in the cloud.
So let's have a look at what EC2 is and how it can help businesses in the US data center.
Eight AWS have lots of servers and we'll call those easy to host servers.
Now the ESI two instances run on top of the host server, so this is an example of server virtualization.
The AC two hosts, the actual physical servers are fully managed by AWS and we then launch our EC2 instances
and those instances can run Windows or Linux or Mac OS.
So that's the operating system.
And of course then we can install our applications like websites or whatever our application is on top
of our EC2 instance.
So the instance is a virtual server, there's a variety of instance types and they have a different
combination of CPU memory storage and networking.
So you can choose the instance type that is best suited for your particular use case.
So you get to choose your instance type and then the operating system that you want to run and that
can be Windows, Linux or Mac OS.
Now AC two is an example of infrastructure as a service.
You learned about that earlier in the course, IaaS or IaaS.
So with infrastructure as a service at AWS are going to manage the physical hardware and they manage
the software, the virtualization and management layer that sits on top of the hardware.
But the key to instance is something that you manage.
So you have to manage Windows and whatever application you put on top, that means things like patching
are your responsibility.
Now each instance will be attached to a network and that network is within your virtual private cloud,
your VPC, and you will choose the subnets that you want to assign to your EC2 instance and that determines
where they're launched and what they can access from a network perspective.
Now each instance will have one or more IP addresses, and as you can see from this table, there are
three different types of IP address.
The first one at the top of the table is a public IP address.
If your instance is running in a public subnet within the VPC, it will have a public IP address.
Now these are lost when the instances stopped, that means they're assigned dynamically and if you stop
the instance and start it again, it will have a different public IP address they used in public subnets
and there's no charge for them.
Now.
They're actually associated with a private address on the instance and you can't move these addresses
between instances.
We then have the private address.
Every instance, whether it's in a public or a private subnet, will always have at least one private
IP address.
Now these are retained when the instance is stopped and they're used in public and private subnets.
Lastly, we have something called an elastic IP address and there's a bit more flexibility with these.
Now these are also public IP addresses.
The difference between the elastic IP address and the public IP address is that rather than being dynamically
assigned and lost when the instance is stopped, the elastic IP address is static and it isn't lost
when you stop your instance.
So if you want to have a specific public IP address that you can use to connect to your application,
then you would use an elastic IP address so that it doesn't change over time.
Now you are charged if they're not used.
So as long as they're in use, you don't get charged and they're always associated with a private IP
address on the instance, just like the public IP address.
Now another level of flexibility is that you can move them between instances and the network adapters
called Elastic Network adapters.
On the instance, you might want to do that if you need to remap the address to another instance.
In the case of a failure or some other incident, you've learned previously about VPC and subnets.
So remember that public subnets are where we launch our AC two instances and they have either a public
IP address or an elastic IP address.
So in both cases that's an IP address that can be used on the Internet.
So we can connect to the instance from the Internet if we want to, and we can connect out to the to
the Internet via the Internet gateway and in the route table for the public subnet, there's always
a route that goes to the ID of the Internet gateway.
Now, secondly, we've got private subnets, so that's when we're launching our instances and they only
have private IP addresses.
Now if we want to connect our instances in private subnets to the internet, we have to do so of.
Something called a nat gateway, or there's another option called a net instance.
But gateways are the better choice these days.
Usually the Nat Gateway is deployed in the public subnet and the instance can use it to connect to the
internet.
And we can see that a route to the NAT Gateway is added to the private subnet route table and in the
public subnet route table, the Nat Gateway uses the internet gateway to access the internet.
Now this is for outbound traffic only, so it's to enable your EC2 instance to access the internet.
So Nat, by the way, stands for network address translation.
It basically means that when the instance with the private address wants to connect to the Internet,
to connect to the Internet, it will need a public address that can access the Internet.
And so translation happens and that happens within the Nat Gateway, and that allows the Nat Gateway
to forward the connections to the Internet.