Hey, guys, you've already learned lots about Amazon EC2 and how to deploy EC2 into VPC.
Now we're going to look a little more into the storage layer for our EC2 instances, specifically at
the Amazon Elastic BLOCK Store EBS and Instant store volumes.
So first, let's look at EBS volumes and by default, when we launch our instances, they have one attached
EBS volume, but you can attach more.
So an EBS volume is a block based storage that's actually attached over a network.
So the EBS volume does not actually exist on the AC to host.
It actually exists over a network, but it's attached at the block level.
And of course that means that the volumes appear as disk drives, which can be formatted and have a
drive letter assigned to them on a Windows machine like this.
In this case we've got our C and our DD drive, so the volume is attached over a network and of course
we can attach EBS volumes to any EC2 instance, whether it's a Windows Linux or Mac OS instance.
The EPS volumes exist within and availability zone.
And as we can see here, they are in the same availability zone as our EC2 instance.
The volume is automatically replicated within the availability zone, so AWS are replicating it on the
back end to ensure durability for the data.
There are several types of EBS volume.
These are a few.
There are other types as well.
But I just want to give you an overview of some of the more commonly used volume types.
Now the GP2 has been around for a long time.
That's our general purpose SSD and in the provisioned IOPS on the right here we have the IO one.
So these are both solid state drives.
That means they're very high performance.
Now the older style of hard disk drive is still available, but it's less commonly used.
So most of the time you're going to be using solid state drive options, which are all of these here
on the screen.
Newer options are the GP free, the IO two and the IO two BLOCK Express.
And of course you can read all about the different features and limitations and performance characteristics
on this page here and us have lots more information on their website.
A couple of features to point out at the bottom of the table here we can see boot volume is supported
for all of these different types.
So that means that any of these volume types can be used as a boot volume where your operating system
is installed for your EC2 instance.
EBS multi attach where we attach one EBS volume to multiple instances is not supported except for on
the right hand side here.
And of course we have the performance characteristics here.
So we have the volume size ranging up to 16 TB bytes for general purpose and then up to 64 here for
the BLOCK Express, IOPS is one of the performance characteristics of the volume.
So here where it says Max IOPS 16,000, that stands for having up to 16,000 input output operations
per second.
And we can see the BLOCK Express has a huge number of IOPS.
They're very high performance and of course you will pay for that.
And throughput is essentially the measurement of how much data can be read and written to the disk.
And we can see that for the different volume types here as well.
I mentioned before that there's two different volume types that we're going to discuss.
We've got the EBS volume and then we have the instance store.
So what is an instance store?
Well, in this diagram you can see we have the easy to host server.
So remember that your AC two instances are running on a physical server in the data center at us.
Now our EBS volumes are attached over a network instance.
Store volumes.
Are these ones here within the host server, They're actually physically attached to the host and they
offer extremely high performance, whereas the EBS volumes are actually attached over the network.
So what else is different?
Well, instant store volumes are ephemeral.
That means non persistent.
And what non persistent means is your data is lost if you terminate your instance.
So if you launch an instance with an instance store volume, the data on the instance store volume is
only accessible for the lifetime of that instance.
You can't actually stop an AC two instance that has an attached instance or volume.
You can restart it and you won't lose your data.
But if you terminate your instance, there's no way to keep that data.
Whereas with an EBS volume, the volume exists independently of the issue instance.
So you can terminate your instance and you can keep your volume and then reattach it to another instance
to read that data.
EBS volumes are persistent, so that means the data is kept there, it's not deleted and it exists independently
of the instance.
So why might you use instance store volumes?
Well, they offer extremely high performance and they come with some instance types.
So the storage is available and it can be used for things like data that's only temporary.
For instance, it can be used as a scratch volume.
That's where data is getting stored for a temporary basis.
It's used, but it doesn't need to be kept and retained or backed up.
In another use case, you might have some data that requires high performance and it's replicated to
other instances, so you always have multiple copies of the data.
So how do we back up our EBS volumes?
Well, we can back them up using something called a snapshot.
So we have an AC two instance here in an availability zone.
It has an attached volume, a snapshot can be taken and it captures a point in time state of the data
that's actually in that volume.
So that data can then be created as a snapshot and it's actually created in Amazon S3 So it's outside
of the availability zone.
Then we can take additional snapshots and each snapshot is incremental.
So it captures the changes since the previous snapshot because our snapshots live in Amazon is free,
which is outside of the availability zone.
We can also use our snapshot to create volumes in different availability zones.
So here we've created an EBS volume in availability Zone B from the snapshot, and then we can attach
that volume to an easy to instance in availability zone B So we've been able to essentially move that
data between availability zones.
You can also create images, the Amazon machine images from our snapshots, and they can be used then
to create instances in different availability zones.