Hey, guys, let's look at the Amazon Elastic file system.
Amazon FS.
Now, FS is a file based storage system that we can use to attach to our EC2 instances.
So how does it look?
Well, in FS we create our file system.
We can then attach easy to instances to the file system.
Now, as you can see in this diagram, we have instances in multiple availability zones and they are
connected to the same file system.
So that means they can read and write data to that file system.
They both see it as a mount point and they can both read and write data and see each other's data.
So FS is a great way to attach a shared storage location to multiple instances in different availability
zones.
You can't do that with EBS.
Now, as I mentioned in a previous video with the Elastic BLOCK store EBS, you do have the option for
multi attach, but that's limited to within an availability zone.
There's a limited number of instances you can connect and they must be built with a certain architecture.
So there's quite a few constraints.
Now with FS you can attach many, many instances across multiple availability zones within a region
to the same file system.
So it's a really great storage location.
Now it is mounted using an FS mount point, so that means a path in the file system.
Now it is Linux only and it uses the NFS protocol.
So that's the network file system protocol that's used to access the file system.
And because it runs on Linux only, we have mount points rather than drive letters.
So remember with Windows you might have a drive letter like your D, e, F drive, Z drive and so on.
In this case, because it's Linux, you have a mount point and that is just a location in the file system
of the instance.
If you save data to that location in the file system, it actually gets written to FS.
You can also connect an on premises client in a corporate data center to an FS file system.
And in that case you would want to connect a direct connect connection or at the very least a VPN.