Hi, guys. In this lesson I'm going to cover EC2 user data and metadata.
These are both really important features of EC2.
So firstly, let's have a look at what user data is.
So let's say we go into the management console and we're going to launch an instance.
Now, when we do so on the configuration page, we're able to enter some code and this can be our code.
Now, don't worry, you don't need to understand this particular code here,
but this particular code is actually installing a Web service.
Now, the point is that you're able to run this code and it runs the first time the instance starts up.
So you can configure certain things to happen through these commands on your instance
when it first boots.
So in this case, it's actually going to install a Web service on our EC2 instance.
Now, EC2 user data is limited to 16 kilobytes.
So there's a certain amount of code that you're able to run.
If you're using a Windows instance, then you can run Batch scripts and PowerShell scripts as well.
And what we're doing here is, as you can see, we're entering the text.
You can also upload a file as well.
So that's user data.
Now, what is metadata?
Metadata is some information about your EC2 instance, and it's available at this particular address.
So this address, you can run this from a command window on your computer and it's a local address.
This IP address here corresponds to your local computer.
It doesn't actually connect over a network.
It's just finding this information on the computer that you're actually running this on, on your EC2
instance.
So the path is HTTP://169.254 and then it repeats 169.254/latest/meta-data.
Now, don't worry, you won't have to remember that for the exam, but it's a very useful path to know.
So what do you find when you actually put in this URL?
Well, this is some of the information you can return.
Here we're using a command called curl, which just checks this URL.
And if we just put in this path here, we get a list of information.
And this is data about our instance.
So we can query any of these different pieces of data and we'll find some information.
So let's have a look at some examples of what you might find.
Well, in this case, we're putting in the path we saw before and then we're adding local-IPv4 on the end.
And that actually returns the IPv4 private IP address of this instance.
And you can see it here just before the command prompt.
If we run another command here, you can see this time we're asking for the public IPv4 address
and it's showing us the public address.
So remember the difference between user data and metadata.
User data gives you the ability to run commands when the system is starting and metadata can return
information about the instance that's recorded locally.
And that's really about as much as you need to know for the exam.