There are going to be multiple situations where you need your EC2 instance to be able to connect to
another service.
For instance, you might want to save data to a storage service or
you might want to save information to a database.
So there are a couple of ways that you can do that.
The first is what we call access keys.
Now, access keys are configured on the EC2 instance.
This is some secret information that is stored on the file system of the instance.
Now, the access keys are actually associated with a user account and the user account has a policy.
So it has some permissions assigned to it.
Now the access keys will pick up whatever permissions the policy allows that user.
And then the EC2 instance using the permissions assigned to the user account is able to
connect to, in this case, a storage service.
So that's how that works.
Now, there is a bit of a downside.
The downside is that the access keys are stored on the file system of the instance, and it's not a
very secure way of storing that information.
So if the instance was compromised, it's possible an attacker could get access to that information.
In the next lesson, you'll see a hands-on and I'll demonstrate how accessible this information is.
Now, there is another way.
So the other way is when we use something called an instance profile.
The instance profile is a way that we can connect an IAM role to our EC2 instance.
So in this case, the instance has an IAM role attached to it.
That role is then assumed by the EC2 instance and the EC2 instance will gain access to whatever
permissions the policy attached to the role provides, and is then able to access the S3 bucket.
The great thing about this is there's no credentials stored on the EC2 instance.
The EC2 instance has assumed the role and it's been given the permissions assigned to that role.
But it doesn't actually have any credentials stored on its file system.
So this can be a much more secure way of allowing your EC2 instance to access AWS services.
And in the next lesson, we're going to see this in action.