In this lesson, I'm going to launch an Auto Scaling web application on Amazon EC2.
I'm in the EC2 management console.
And the first thing I need to do is create a launch template.
So the launch template is going to specify some information about how to
configure the EC2 instances that are launched by the Auto Scaling group.
So I'm going to click create launch template.
We're going to give it a name.
I'm going to call it my EC2 web app.
And then I don't need to give it a version description at this stage.
Let's just scroll down and specify some information.
So what I'm going to do is click on the quick start.
I'm going to choose Amazon Linux.
The Amazon Linux 2 AMI is selected and that's fine.
We're going to leave this information as it is.
For instance type I want to specify to use the T2 micro instance type.
For key pair, I'm going to select the key pair that I already have in my region
so MyNV-KP.
If you don't have a key pair,
just go back to the EC2 management console and create a key pair.
Under network settings, I want to select an existing security group.
I'm going to choose the web access security group which is in my VPC.
Under advanced network configuration,
all I want to do here is change the auto assign public IP to enable.
Then let's scroll down.
The storage can be left as it is. I don't need to change anything there.
In advanced details at the bottom,
the only thing I want to do is scroll all the way down
and enter some user data.
Now, in the course download which you can find at the end of section one,
you'll have the code directory, EC2, and then this file EC2-user-data-web-app.shh.
And all we need to do is copy all of this information to our clipboard.
This will simply install HTTPD, sort of create an Apache web server.
It's then going to use the instance, metadata service
to find the name of the availability zone into which this instance is launched.
And then it's going to add that to the index.html.
So what we'll see when we go to the website is it will say
this amazon EC2 instance is located in availability zone and then the name of the AZ.
So back in the console we simply paste in our user data
and create our launch template.
So that's done. So now we can go back up to EC2,
come down to the bottom,
select Auto Scaling groups.
We're going to create an Auto Scaling group. This one is going to be called ASG1.
I'm going to find my launch template, scroll down, click on next, choose my VPC.
So remember, I did choose a specific security group that's in this VPC.
So I need to make sure that the security group
specified in the launch template matches the VPC.
So I've selected my VPC.
And then I'm going to choose the public subnets, public-1A and public-1B.
If I come down a little further, I can just select next again.
I don't have a load balancer at this stage
and I don't need to modify any settings. So let's click on next.
Now for desired minimum and max capacity, for now, I'm going to leave it on one.
And I'm not going to use a scaling policy at this point in time.
So let's click on next.
Next again. Next again.
We get the summary of information and then we can create our Auto Scaling group.
So that should launch a single EC2 instance.
And once that instance is launched, we should be able to go
to the public DNS or the public IP of that instance and we should see a web page.
Now, make sure that your security group does have a rule for HTTP.
So I'm going to go to my web access security group.
Under inbound rules, let's just have a look.
I only have RDP and SSH. So it's not going to work. So I need to edit inbound rules,
add rule, and then I'm simply going to choose HTTP.
Under source, I'm going to say anywhere IPv4.
And then save rules.
So now my rules are configured correctly.
Now if we go back to Auto Scaling groups,
select the group
got activity,
and here you can see some of the activity that's happening and
at the moment it's launching a new EC2 instance.
So if we go up to instances,
we can see that this instance is running.
Now, these two were terminated there from a previous exercise.
This is the one that is just being initialized by the Auto Scaling group.
So in a couple of minutes we should be able
to connect to the website running on our instance.
With the instance selected, I can now see lots of information about the incidents
including the public IP.
So I'm going to select to copy the public IP to my clipboard.
Alternatively you can use the DNS.
And in a new tab I'm going to enter
and we can see that there is a website running on this instance
and it's telling us the availability zone that the instance is running in.
So that's exactly as expected.
Now back in the console, what I'm going to do is just go down to Auto Scaling groups,
go into ASG1, and I'm going to click on edit next to group details.
And I'm going to change the desired capacity to two
and the maximum to three.
So that should launch another EC2 instance.
If I click on update, it's going to save those changes.
Now another thing you can do is use dynamic or predictive
scaling policies to scale based on whether it's something dynamic such as
the CPU utilization or predictive where it's going to scale because it knows
when certain activity is going to happen like an increase in traffic.
With dynamic, you have some options. You've got target tracking where it tries to
keep the certain metric at a specific value.
So for example you can say keep the CPU utilization around 50% aggregated across
the instances in the Auto Scaling group.
Or you can choose step
where you can have different reactions to different levels of change.
So if you have a small increase in traffic you launch one instance if you have a larger
increase in traffic then you launch a few instances at a time.
Or otherwise there's simple scaling where you simply add a certain
number of capacity units or percent of the group
when it's needed, so based on a specific alarm in CloudWatch.
So we're not going to do that. Let's just go back to details.
In fact let's go to activity.
And we can see that a new instance is being launched.
So that should now be launched in the console.
Let's just refresh EC2. Now, we have two running instances.
And that's it for this hands-on lesson.
Please leave your Auto Scaling group running as we're going to be launching an
Application Load Balancer in another hands on lesson
and attaching it to our ASG.