Hi guys and welcome to the first exam cram of the course.
So there's lots of exam crowns, they're not in every section,
but they are in many sections of the course.
Now the exam crowns are a very quick walkthrough of some
key facts that are important to know for the exam.
They're not a substitute for doing the lessons,
There are some facts that won't be covered in the exam
crams and there might be some additional ones that are.
So the idea is that you use both the lessons
in the section as well as the exam cram and exam cram will
just give you a fast way to get to some core facts.
This exam cram is about amazon VPc, easy to and elastic load balancing.
So let's get started.
So VPC is a logically isolated portion of the cloud within a region.
The VPc router will take care of routing within the VPc and outside of the VPc.
And the route table is used to configure the VPc router,
an internet gateway is attached to a VPC
and that's used to connect to the internet
and the VPc will span all the availability zones
in the region.
Each VPC has a different block of IP addresses and that's known as a cider block.
Subnets are created within availability zones
and each sub net has a block of I P addresses from the overall cider block.
Security groups are applied at the instance level,
specifically at the elastic network interface level.
Security groups can be applied to instances in any sub net.
They're also used for allow rules only. You can't create a deny rule.
Separate rules are defined for outbound traffic versus inbound traffic.
And a source
in a rule can be an iP address or a security group ID.
Nichols apply at the sub net level
nickels which are network access control lists apply only to traffic entering and
exiting the sub net not traffic that's
crossing between instances within the subnets.
Rules are processed in order and they're numbered
and Nichols will have an explicit deny at the end.
An Ec two instance is a virtual server running in the cloud.
The ec two instances can run Windows, Lennox or mac. Os
and the hosts that they run upon are managed by AWS
an amazon machine image and am I defines the configuration of the instance
and you can customize your instance and create a custom am I?
A snapshot is a point in time backup of an instance.
User data is code that's run when the instance starts for the first time. Only
instance metadata
is data about your easy to instance
and you can find the instance metadata using this U. R. L. So take note of this. U R. L.
It is worth understanding.
Access keys are composed of the access key ID and a secret access key
and you can use them to sign programmatic requests to the Cli or the A P. I.
It's a best practice to use temporary security credentials.
I am rolls That is instead of using access keys whenever possible.
Also you should disable any AWS account root user access keys.
The access key
is associated with an I am account.
The access key will use the permissions assigned to the I AM user
I am roles should be used instead of access keys wherever you can.
Elastic load balancers provide a single endpoint for your application,
lbs distribute connections to back end instances,
addresses, containers and functions.
Target groups are used for attaching the target applications to the E L. B.
The application load balancer. The A. L. B.
Is used for web applications with layer seven routing,
that's http and https protocols and also advanced request routing as well.
The NLB the network load balancer is used for TCP and
UDP based applications and offers ultra low latency static I.
P addresses and VPc endpoint services.
The G L B, which is the gateway load balancer distributes connections to appliances
like I. DS systems, I P. S.
Next generation firewalls and web application firewalls.
Session state data can be stored in databases such as dynamodb and elastic cache.
This type of data can include temporary data,
metadata authentication information and more
sticky sessions can be used on lbs to bind a session to an easy to instance
sticky sessions uses cookies
that get generated at the MLB level.
You can use a combination of duration based stickiness,
application based stickiness and no stickiness across your target groups,
sticky sessions are not supported with TLS listeners
and TLS target groups when you're using an NLB
and that's it for this exam, cram.
Hope that was useful and I'll see you in the next lesson.