Hi guys, the Amazon Elastic Container Service, ECS
is used for running containers on AWS.
So we're talking about Docker containers primarily here.
So let's have a look at the architecture of ECS.
So we have the Elastic Container Service
and within ECS we create what are called clusters.
The cluster is a logical grouping of tasks or services within ECS.
So we create our cluster and then we can run a task.
An ECS task is actually a running Docker container.
So you can think of it as an instance of a container running.
Now the task is executed using a task definition.
So this is how you create the configuration for your task.
You specify in a task definition, and then you create a task that uses
that task definition for its configuration input.
There's also an image.
So each task will come from an image and that can be
stored in a repository such as the Amazon Elastic Container Registry.
So these are the Docker container images
and they're stored in Amazon ECR.
Now, we can create something called a service.
A service is used to maintain a desired count of tasks.
So if you know exactly how many tasks you need to run, you create a service
and then it ensures that that many tasks are always running.
In ECS there's a couple of different ways we can run our containers.
Now, one of them is where we have some
container instances which we actually manage ourselves.
We'll look at the other option later in this lesson.
So in this case, the ECS container instance
is actually an EC2 instance with the ECS agent running on it.
And it's become part of this cluster through configuration that we add.
So this is an EC2 instance that you can see in your account in EC2,
and you manage it yourself.
And then you can run your Docker containers on that instance.
So you can have lots of containers running on a single instance.
You can also use auto-scaling for your container instances to scale the number that
you need to support the amount of tasks or containers that you're actually running.
So let's look at some key features.
So there's another launch type where you don't manage those underlying EC2 instances,
the ECS container instances as you saw in the previous diagram.
That's called Fargate and that's fully serverless,
so everything is managed for you.
You get fully managed container orchestration.
So the control plane is managed for you.
Docker is supported so you can run
and manage docker containers with integration into the Docker Compose CLI.
You also get Windows container support.
So ECS supports management of Windows containers.
And you get elastic load balancing integration
so you can distribute your traffic across containers using an ALB or an NLB.
A slightly newer feature is called Amazon ECS Anywhere.
And this enables the use of the ECS
control plane to manage your on-premises implementations.
These are the core components of Amazon ECS.
Firstly, we have a cluster.
This is a logical grouping of tasks or services.
Then we have the container instance.
This is actually the EC2 instance running the ECS agent.
You then have a task definition,
that's the blueprint that describes how a Docker container should launch,
so the configuration of the container.
You then have a task, and this is a
running container using the settings in a task definition.
And then lastly here, we have a service.
That defines long running tasks
so you can control how many tasks you want to have running.
And you can use auto-scaling with a service
and use it to configure an ALB that you
want to attach in front of your containers for load distribution.
So let's go into a bit more detail on clusters.
These are a logical grouping of container instances that you place your tasks on.
A default cluster is created but you can
then create multiple clusters to separate your resources.
ECS allows the definition of a specified number, a desired count of tasks to run in
the cluster.
Clusters can contain tasks using the Fargate and the EC2 launch type.
EC2 launch type
clusters can contain different container instance types as well.
And each container instance may only be part of one cluster at a time.
Clusters are region specific.
You can create IAM policies for your clusters to allow or restrict users access
to specific clusters.
So you've got full access control.
Now, if you're going to use the EC2 launch type,
then you have your EC2 instances with the ECS
agent running on them.
You can use any AMI that meets the amazon ECS AMI specification.
The instance is used as container host must run an ECS agent.
And the container agent allows the container instances to connect to the cluster.
The container agent runs on each infrastructure resource on an ECS cluster.
Next, we have the images.
Containers are created from a read only template and that is called an image.
That has the instructions for creating the Docker container.
Images are built from a Docker file
and only Docker containers are supported on the ECS.
Images are stored in the registry and that can
be Docker Hub or Amazon Elastic Container Registry, ECR.
ECR is a managed Docker container registry service
that is secure scalable and reliable.
ECS supports private Docker repositories with resource-based permissions
using IAM in order to access repositories and images.
And you could use the Docker CLI to push, pull, and manage images.
And we'll look a bit more into the details of how you use the CLI
later on in the section.
So then we have the tasks and the task definitions.
A task definition is required to run Docker containers in ECS.
The task definition is a text file in JSON format
and it describes one or more containers up to a maximum of 10.
And we can see some of the contents of a task definition here.
In this case it's a Wordpress container,
it's got links to a MySQL container
and we can see some information about the ports
that are being used and the memory and CPU allocation.
Task definitions use docker images to launch the containers
and you specify the number of tasks to run
and that's the number of containers that you want.
Some of the parameters you can specify in a task definition
include the Docker images to use with the containers in your task,
how much CPU and memory to use with each container,
whether containers are linked together in a task,
the Docker networking mode to use for the containers in your task,
what if any ports from the container are mapped to the host container instances?
Whether the task should continue if the container finished or fails,
the commands that the container should run when it started,
environment variables that should be passed to the container when it starts,
data volumes that should be used with the containers in the task,
and the IAM role the task should use for permissions.
So those are the fundamentals of ECS and we'll
dive into some more detail now on various components.