Hi, guys. In this lesson, we're going to go over how you assign permissions to your container instances
and your actual containers, your tasks themselves.
So let's have a look at how we use IAM roles with ECS.
So, in this example, we have the EC2 launch type.
So, we have an ECS cluster,
we have a service, and we have a container instance that we manage.
The container instance has an IAM role assigned to it.
This is known as the IAM instance role.
This provides the container instance with permissions that it needs.
So, for example, the permissions policy for the container instance role may be like this, where it
has some EC2 and ECS permissions. And these are permissions assigned to the host.
We then have the tasks that are running on our container instance, and those tasks will have an IAM
task role.
So, the role assigned to the task is a different role than the container instance.
The permissions assigned to this role are supplied to the container instance, not to the host.
Now, a really important point for the exam is that the permissions assigned to the instance role are
also supplied to the tasks that are running on top of that instance.
So, you want to be very careful what permissions you apply there because your container instances are
going to run them.
If you have different containers that should have different permissions, then you should use IAM task
roles.
Now, what about on Fargate?
Fargate is a bit simpler.
You only have the IAM task roles.
There's no such thing as a container instance role because you don't have any actual operational control
over the container instances.
Now, the task roles are defined in the task definition or in the run task API.
So when we run a task, we can define the role that we want to assign to it, or we assign it through
the task definition.
And that's where if you have multiple applications running in containers and they come from different
task definitions, then you can have different roles for those different applications specified in that
task definition.
And that's how you will use the principle of least privilege and only assign the permissions that that
particular application needs.