In this lesson, I'm going to cover task placement strategies for ECS.
So what is a task placement strategy?
Well, it's an algorithm for selecting the instances
for task placement or task termination.
Task placement strategies can be used when either
running a task or creating a new service.
And this is relevant only to the EC2 launch type.
ECS supports multiple strategies you can use for task placement.
Firstly, we've got binpack.
This places tasks based on the least available amount of CPU or memory.
And that will minimize the number of instances in use.
Next, we have random. That just places the
tasks randomly across the instances that are available.
We have spread, that places tasks evenly based on a specified value.
Accepted values are instance ID or host.
And they actually have the same effect.
Or any platform or custom attribute that's applied to a container instance,
such as attribute ECS.availability zone.
So that means you can use this variable to spread
the tasks across availability zones evenly.
Service tasks are spread based on the tasks from that service.
Standalone tasks are spread based on the tasks from the same task group.
So how does this look?
Well, the following strategy would distribute the
tasks evenly across availability zones.
So this is how we can define it. We've got the placement strategy
and we've defined a field of attribute ECS.availability zone
and the type is spread.
The following strategy will distribute tasks evenly across all instances.
So here we just have the field instance ID and the type has spread.
In another example, the strategy will binpack the tasks based on memory.
So now the field is defined as memory and the type is binpack.
You can also combine strategies.
So this example will distribute tasks evenly across availability zone
and then bin packs tasks based on memory within each availability zone.
So now we have multiple strategies at the same time.
We got the spread across availability zones and then binpack based on memory.
We then have task placement constraints.
These are rules that are considered during task placement.
We've got distinct instance, where it will
place each task on a different container instance.
And then we've got membersof
which places tasks on container instances that satisfy and expression.
Another thing you need to know for the exam is
the cluster query language, at least what it is.
So cluster queries are expressions that enable you to group objects.
So for example you can group
container instances by attributes like availability zone,
instance type, or some custom metadata.
Expressions have this syntax, subject, operator and then argument.
So let's have a look at an example.
This expression selects instances with the specified instance type.
So we specify instance type and in this case t2 small.
In another example, this expression selects instances in the
us-east-1A or 1B availability zones.
So we specify availability zone in
and then we have the specific availability zones in question.
In another example this expression selects instances that are hosting tasks
in the service production group.
So we're looking for a specific group in this case.
Now that's it for this lesson.
Now, I'm quite sure you will see some questions
about the task placement strategies on the exam.
So make sure you fully understand those.
Cluster query language can occasionally come up as can constraints.
But the task placement strategies are 100% gonna come up in the exam.
So make sure you understand them fully and you'll be good.