Welcome back.
In this lesson, we're going to go into lots more detail on how you can scale Amazon ECS.
So remember, first that there are two different types of scaling.
We've got the service auto scaling, that's about the containers, the tasks that we're actually running.
The second is cluster auto scaling.
So let's have a look at the differences with service auto scaling.
We're using the application auto scaling service to automatically change the desired count of the actual
container tasks that are actually running.
There's a few different policies we can use.
We can use target tracking step and also scheduled scaling policies.
Now, cluster auto scaling is different.
This is using something called a capacity provider to report information about the utilization of the
underlying EC2 instances, and it will then use the EC2 auto scaling service to actually scale the
number of the container hosts.
The ECS container instances that run your tasks.
Now let's have a look at it visually.
So we have an ECS cluster with a service running and multiple container instances.
We then have three tasks running across those instances.
Now these tasks are actually going to be sending information to Amazon Cloud Watch.
So they're reporting metric information.
And let's say that the metrics report that the average CPU utilization has exceeded a certain threshold.
What happens then?
That information gets reported to the application
Auto scaling service and auto scaling will then launch an additional task.
So we now have more tasks running.
Now, in most cases, a container instance is going to run many, many, many tasks because they're
only using a tiny amount of resource each.
But you get the idea of how this works With service auto scaling, we can use target tracking scaling
policies.
So remember, we've target tracking just like with EC2 auto scaling.
What you're doing is specifying a target value and it's going to try and utilize that amount of resource.
Then we have step scaling policies which change the amount of run in tasks based on alarm breaches and
the size of the alarm breach defines how many extra tasks to run.
And then we've got scheduled scaling where we can say that a specific time of day
That's when we want to add a certain number of tasks to our cluster.
Next up, we have cluster auto scaling.
So here what we're doing is we're not looking at the task level, but we're looking at the container
instance level because we don't want to run out of resources on our container instances.
We might need another one, a metric called the capacity provider reservation reports information
of the utilization of the container instances.
So let's say they've breached a certain amount like 80% CPU.
Now, as you can see, we have an auto scaling group here.
The auto scaling group is linked to ECS using something called a capacity provider.
So here what can happen is Cloud Watch is able to notify the auto scaling group and now AWS will launch
an additional container instance.
And the ECS service knows that a new instance is now being brought into the cluster and it can start
launching new tasks on that new container instance.
So with cluster auto scaling, it's using an ECS resource called a capacity provider.
The capacity provider is associated with an auto scaling group, and the ASG can scale using manage
scaling and managed instance termination protection instance.
Termination protection means that the ASG is aware of any tasks that are still running on the container
instances.