Hi guys and welcome to this lesson.
So this lesson is going to be a hands on with amazon Ec s.
What we're going to do is we're going to create
a cluster that uses the Ec two launch type.
So we're gonna have instances in our account.
Ec two instances that are configured as part of the cluster.
And then we're gonna run our tasks on top of the cluster.
Now in this particular lesson we'll create the cluster,
will launch the instances and configure them so that they added into the cluster.
And then in the next lesson, what we'll do is we're going to start launching tasks,
will create a task definition,
launch a task and then we're gonna launch a service with a load balancer as well.
So it should be a great couple of labs, let's head over to the console.
So I'm logged into the console and what I need to do is create a role and this role is
going to be used by our ec two instances in order to be able to speak to e C S.
So we need to provide the permissions to E C S.
So we're gonna create a role.
Now, what I'm gonna do is use EC two as the common use case.
If you look at the AWS documentation,
they ask you to choose the elastic container service.
It actually adds a very similar policy but I found it didn't work recently.
There's a lot of nuances with pcs at the moment.
So what I want to do here is choose ec two
click on next
and I'm just going to paste in
amazon ec two container service for ec two role.
So you can just type that in or type part of it in and you'll see a number of options.
Just make sure you select the one with the exact name, you can see on your screen here.
And if you expand that to look at the permissions, you can see
there's some Ec two
permissions and lots of CCs and ec our permissions
and then cloudwatch logs as well.
So I'm gonna select this policy,
click on next, we're going to give it a name.
Mine's gonna be e C s instance role
and we can see that the trusted entity is easy to
so easy to instances will be able to assume this role
and they'll have the permissions to e C s.
So let's create the role. We now have our role.
The next thing to do is go to Pcs and we're gonna create our cluster
Now. I'm using the new E C s experience.
They've actually been working on this for I think over a year now.
It's taken a really long time. Most of the updates to the console.
The major updates were completed quite a while ago.
This one is ongoing
and I've been quite patient because I've been waiting for them to get to a point
where I can actually record the entire labs
without switching between the old and the new.
Now at this point in time, I can do pretty much everything,
in fact everything that we are going to do in these labs, I can do in the new console.
Sometimes you do get flicked to the
old console for instance when you're updating clusters
and there's quite a few nuances,
a few weird things that you've got to watch out for when
using UCS and I'll point those out as we go through.
So I'm gonna click on clusters
so I'm gonna click create cluster,
I'm gonna give it a name, I'm gonna call it my
e c s dash cluster
for vPc networking,
we're in the US east one north Virginia region and we have the default VPc selected.
I'm happy with that.
And there's six subnets and I'm happy to use all of those that all public subnets
for infrastructure. Fargate the serverless option is selected by default.
You can't deselect it either
if you wanted to use this configuration easy to instances.
This is where it will actually create an
auto scaling group for your instances for you
and it does a bit more configuration.
Now, what I want to do for this particular exercises, show you how to do it manually
and we're going to use external instances using E c s anywhere.
Now we're not really using easy. S anywhere, but this is the option we need.
So E c s anywhere would allow you to run your containers managed by AWS outside of AWS.
So we've got that one selected
and I'm going to click on create
and that should just take a moment and then we'll have our cluster ready.
So my cluster is ready. That's all worked.
Next thing to do is to go to the Ec two management console and what we want
to do now is actually run our Ec two instances which are going to be the container host
Now we do need to use a specific am I that's optimized for E C.
S and has the agent installed on it.
Now, the best thing to do is to follow this link,
I've provided the link in the attached to the lesson.
So when you go to this link you can scroll down a little way
and you'll see that there's a link to get the am I am I I D for your particular region.
So if I click on view, am I I D.
That takes me to this page and you can see there's a value here
am I dash and then a big long
combination of letters and numbers, just copy that value.
Let's come back to ec. two
click on launch instance,
you can give them a name if you like. So for instance e CS
dash instances
and then here what we want to do
is in the search bar, I'm going to put the am I I D.
It's going to take us over here.
Just takes a second and we can see that it's come up with the E C s optimist am I?
So we can select this instance,
click on, continue
now it does then default the instance type to an M five dot large.
We don't need to do that. We can keep this in the free tier.
So I'm just going to find the T two micro
instance type
to keep a I'm going to select my key pair for this region
for security group. I'll let it create a new one
and that will allow ssh it doesn't allow anything else.
We'll need to make sure our containers do have the right
security groups to allow access to the application
but that's fine for the host.
So then I can come down everything there looks normal.
Let's expand advanced details.
And here we want to change the instance profile.
We want to select the e c s instance role.
So now we have the correct permissions
and finally under user data we need to enter some user data
to configure the cluster.
So in the course download, you will find yours will be in the code directory
amazon ec. S and then you'll find this file easy to cluster instances dot M d.
Now what you need to do,
just in case you changed your cluster name to something different.
Just enter your cluster name here. So it should
echo
underscore cluster equals. And then the cluster name
and that's going to be saved into this file.
The e c s dot conflict file.
So mine is set up correctly. I'm gonna copy that code
and then back in the console just paste that into the user data.
So that's going to configure
the cluster name.
And of course this, am I already has
the E C s agent installed if you just choose another, Am I?
It might not have the E C s agent installed, so you must
use an AM I that does have it installed or install it manually.
So in this case we've got the permissions
and we have our cluster name correctly configured,
so I'm just gonna launch this instance.
So our instance is being launched,
we can now go back to e c s,
choose my e c s cluster,
go to infrastructure
and in the bottom here
under contained instances very shortly. We should see our instance.
So you'll need to give it a minute or so and then click on refresh.
So mine has been refreshed and I can see now that I have my container instance,
type Ec two, you can see the instance I D we can see the availability zone
and of course we don't have any running tasks.
Now we don't have a huge amount of CPU and memory available because we
chose the T two micro so we won't be able to run many containers
on this house but that's okay for demonstration purposes.
So that's it we have our cluster created,
we have our instance added and we're gonna finish this lesson in the next lesson.
We're then going to actually launch some containers on top of our host.