Welcome back in this lesson. We're going to continue from the last lesson.
In the last lesson we created our pcs cluster,
we added a container host to it running on Ec two.
So we're using the EC two launch type.
And in this lesson we're going to create a task definition.
Launch a task on our cluster
and then we'll see how we can also create a service
with an elastic load balancer and a lb application load balancer.
So let's head over to the console.
So back in the console I have my Ec S cluster under infrastructure,
I have my running E C.
S container host so we can see that that's active and working.
So what I want to do now is go to task definitions,
we're going to create a new task definition for this lab and it
will also be Engine X but I want to show you the setting.
So I'm gonna call it my dash Engine X
then
for the container and we're also going to call this one just engine X.
And then for the image, this is where we actually specify
the engine X image with the latest revision
and it's gonna pull that image down
and that's gonna be the application running So Engine X is a simple web service
and that's what we're going to run
now. I'm going to leave the container ports here as paul.
This is a web service.
I don't need to make any other changes here
so let's click on next.
What I want to do now is change the Ec two instances.
I don't want to use this one with Fargate. So I'm just going to enable EC two.
I'm gonna leave
the setting here for
X- 86-64
for V C p U. I am going to change this, I'm gonna change this right down to 0.25.
Now, make sure you leave V CPU there
And under memory just .5
and then G B now you do this is where there's a bit of a it's a bit of a strange console.
You can't just specify, for instance, 0.5 or 0.5, it has to be 0.5.
Space G B same with the CPU.
So those do have to be specified exactly as I show them here,
we're not going to specify a task role And for network mode,
I'm gonna change this to AWS VPC
so then we can scroll down,
click on next,
scroll down again
and create.
So we do need to be very specific with these
settings to make this task definition work with the easy to
launch type in the old console actually gave you an
option to configure the launch type that you are using.
They don't seem to have that anymore. And that's why it can be a little bit tricky
if you don't know the specific settings that will work.
Now we can go back to our cluster,
click on tasks,
run new task
Now you need to change the compute configuration because it's
gonna default to fargate using a capacity provider strategy.
We want to use launch type and then we can swap to ec two
we're gonna launch a task at this point in time,
choose family
and I'm gonna choose my engine x. The one I just created
and it's there's only one revision so that's easy
For networking.
What we should see is it's also going to go into
the same default VPC with all of those subnets enabled.
So I don't need to change anything there. So that's okay.
The security group we will need to have a
security group which allows access to ports 80.
So if you've got one use that right now.
Otherwise you can always go and change this
default security group and add in the rule.
So I'm gonna just deploy
and the task has been successfully launched.
We can see the task is here and it's provisioning
so it shouldn't take long to actually start this container.
The task is now running
If I click on the task I. D. Here we can see some more information.
Now,
one thing to note is we don't have a public
ip address so how can we connect to this task?
Well, when you're on the Ec two launch type using the AWS VPc,
it's not as the network mode that is it's not going to give you
a public I P you actually have to put a load balancer in front
and for that we need a service.
So what I'm gonna do
his head back up to tasks,
choose my task. We're just going to stop this task. We don't need this one anymore.
So we have to confirm by typing stop
that should just take a moment.
We can see
what's going on at the top pair.
Our task has successfully stopped.
So now I'm gonna go to services,
click on deploy,
change the compute configuration again
Back to Ec two.
We've got service specified,
we're going to choose the same task definition and revision.
I'm gonna give it a service name. Just going to call this my E C S dash service.
You can now specify the number of tasks you want to be running at any time
Now we've only got one contained hosts.
I'm happy just leaving it as one Of course if you have more container hosts you
can or you have more capacity in your container host then you can run more.
We could probably run a couple but one's
fine just for the purposes of demonstration.
So I leave it at one
next we're going to choose load balancing.
We're going to choose application load balancer
and create a new load balancer.
I'm going to call it my dash pcs
dash lb.
It's gonna listen on port 80 protocol http.
I'm going to create a target group.
My dash e C S T G
protocol is going to be http.
Health check path
is simply a slash
and the health check grace period is 30.
Now you can use existing low balances and target groups.
It does become a little bit more tricky getting the settings correct.
So it's often easier just to create it through here.
So those settings look good.
Let's check the networking for networking we have
the same configuration so that looks good to me.
Let's click on deploy
so that's gonna take a few minutes because
it will create our application load balancer and our
target group and then a service and a task that's running on top of that service.
My service is now deployed successfully.
Let's go to ec two and see what's happened.
So in Ec two I go down to low balances.
I've got an A. L. B.
So that looks good.
I'm just gonna copy the DNS name here. We're gonna check that out in a moment.
So I've got my A L. B. In target groups we have a target group
note that it uses the I. P target type
for pcs containers running on the Ec. Two launch type
and under registered targets. You can see that we have a registered target.
So that's our task running on our cluster.
Now we do need to make sure that our security groups are set up correctly.
So I launched mine in the default VPc, which I can see is the one that finishes with
seven F 4.
So if I now go over and find the default
security group for that particular. VPc,
I need to just go in because that's a security group we use for our container,
I need to make sure that the inbound rule does allow http and I've got one.
If you don't have one, just edit inbound rules
at the rule
and choose http
and anywhere I p V four.
So mine is set up correctly.
So I'm going to go to a new tab paste in the DNS name for my A L. B.
And you can see that we are accessing our container.
So it just tells us welcome to Engine X.
So that's the container running on the service on top of our E C S cluster.
So that's all there is to it that is now running successfully.
So what I'm gonna do is go back, I'm finished with this particular exercise.
So what we can do
is we can go to our service
and we need to edit the service.
You won't be able to delete it when you have tasks running.
So you specify zero as desired tasks,
click on updates
that will update it and it should remove that task.
If we come back into tasks here we can see we do have one running
but that should go quite soon.
Then we can delete our service,
click on delete
and that's deleted to service. Now if we go back to have a look at R A L. B.
It should still be there.
So if we come back to A. L. B, you'll note that it doesn't delete that for you.
So make sure you go back and clean that up, delete your A. L. B.
Once that's gone successfully.
You can go and delete your target group if you wish
to or you can keep that doesn't cost you anything.
I'm gonna delete my target group
and then I'm going to go to instances
and here I have my Ec two instance running, I'm going to terminate my instance as well
and that's really cleared up anything that's gonna cost us any money.
So that's shutting down.
You can leave the cluster,
it won't cost you anything if you're not running the container
instances or you can just go and delete your cluster as well
and that's it for this lesson.