Hi guys.
We've discussed Amazon ECR quite a bit so far in
this section but now we'll go into a bit more detail.
So the Elastic Container Registry is a fully managed container registry.
It's integrated with ECS and EKS.
And it supports the Open Container Initiative and Docker Registry
HTTP API V2 standards.
You can use Docker tools and Docker CLI commands such as push, pull, list and tag.
It can be accessed from any Docker environment in the cloud,
on-premises, or on your local machine.
The actual container images and artifacts are stored on Amazon S3.
And you can use namespaces to organize your repositories.
Public repositories allow everyone to access the container images.
Access control only applies to private repositories.
And we got a couple of options.
We've got IAM access control, where we
can set policies and define access to container images in our private repositories.
And resource-based policies.
So here we can have access control right down
to the individual API action like create, list, describe, delete, and get.
Now these are the components of ECR. Of course, first we have the registry.
An ECR private registry is provided to each account
and you can create one or more repositories
in your registry and then store your images in those.
Next, we have an authorization token.
Clients must authenticate ECR registries as an AWS user
before it's possible to push and pull images.
The authorization token will give them that authentication.
The actual repository is what contains your Docker Images, OCI Images
and OCI compatible artifacts.
We then have the repository policy for access control to our repositories.
And then of course, we have the actual images.
And we'll see in the hands-on how to push and pull images to ECR.
With ECR, you get lifecycle policies, so you can manage the lifecycle of the images.
You get image scanning, so you can identify software vulnerabilities
and you can enable cross-region and cross-account replication.
There's also a feature called pull through cache rules.
What this means is you can cache repositories from remote public registries
in your private ECR registry.
So let's have a look at a few processes working with ECR.
So let's say we download and customize an Ubuntu image.
We can then upload that image by pushing it to the registry.
We're then able to run a task using the image.
So that seems quite simple and that's what we're going to do in the hands-on lesson.
Now to push an image to a private repository, you do need to have IAM permissions.
And these are the permissions you need at a minimum to be able to do that.
So we've got the CompleteLayerUpload,
GetAuthorizationTokens so we can authenticate to the repository,
UploadLayerPart, InitiateLayerUpload,
BatchCheckLayerAvailability, and then
PutImage to actually upload our image.
The resource element can also be used to scope to a specific repository ARN
if you want to limit these permissions further.
So let's have a look at the process for pushing an image to a private repository.
First, we need to authenticate the Docker client ECR.
We can do that with this command.
We have AWS ECR get login password, specify the region
and then we're piping to Docker login with a username and a password.
Next, is the tag your image with the ECR
registry repository and image tag name to use.
So we can use the Docker Tag command to do that.
We would then push the image using the Docker push command.
So here we've got Docker push and we give it the account
information with the repository and the tag that we've already specified before.
So that's the process. It's quite simple and we're gonna practice it in the hands on.