Hi guys and welcome to the Bcs Labs Part one.
So this is the first of a five part exercise where we're going to do free parts.
So the first free lessons will be in this section
and the final two are going to be in the next section. These are all hands on lessons.
So we're gonna get quite in depth with pcs,
we're gonna use the elastic container registry.
We're gonna create a Fargate cluster,
use task definitions with a service and an application load balancer.
And in the next section we're going to see how
we can also create a pipeline using codedeploy and Codepipeline.
And we're going to implement a blue green update
where when we make changes to our image,
we can push it through to our running deployment.
So should be a lot of fun. Lots of hands on practice here.
So we're on part One.
And what we're gonna do in this lesson is we're gonna launch an ec two instance.
We're going to install Docker on that instance
and then we're going to create a private repository
and we're gonna push an engine X image up to our private repository.
So it should be an interesting exercise. Let's get started.
Now you'll find this file which has got lots of information in it,
including lots of the command lines that we're going to run
and that's going to be in your code downloads of course download,
go to code e c s and then you'll find pcs labs instructions dot MD.
So the first thing you can see here is we're gonna launch an ec two instance.
It's going to be a Linux two a.m. I T two micro,
we're gonna connect using instance, connect
and then we're gonna run a series of commands.
So let's head over to the console.
So in the console here, I'm going to go to ec two.
Let's launch an instance. We're gonna choose the amazon Linux two.
Am I just leave the defaults T two micro
choose our key pair
for security group. I'm happy just to allow ssh traffic.
If you've got an existing security group, you can use that as long as it provides
that access. I'm happy creating a new one
and for storage, I'll leave the defaults,
we don't need to specify anything for advanced details at at this point in time.
So let's just launch our instance.
So we'll give our instance a moment to launch and then we'll connect using instance,
connect.
My instance is now running
so I'm going to click on connect,
connect again
and that should put me into
the command line on my instance.
So here we are.
Now, what I'm going to do is run Sudo S. U.
That's just going to give us some more privileges that we can use.
And then I'm gonna run yum update
and there are no packages marked for update at this time. So that's great.
So what I'm gonna do is run yum, install Docker.
So this is going to install Docker,
I just type why I do want to do this
and that completed fairly quickly.
Now, I'm now going to just paste in the next couple of commands,
you can find these back in that file I just showed you.
So this is going to enable the doctor's service.
The next one is to actually start the Docker service.
So I'm going to copy that to my clipboard from my file
and then just start the Docker service
so that should be running.
So now Docker is running,
let me just clear my screen and just bring this down
to the middle so you can see a bit more easily.
And I'm going to run Docker
pull
Engine X
so we can see that's downloading
the latest
image for engine X, which is latest here.
So we've got that now. So if I run Docker images,
we should see
that. We've got Engine X
and it's the latest it's tagged as the latest.
So that's great. What else do we need to do? Let's head back to our file.
So this is where we're at. We've just run all those commands.
We now need to create an I am role
and use the policy in this particular file.
So I've opened that file which of course is in the course download and amazon ec. S
and what I'm gonna do is copy
all of this code here.
So this is this is going to provide access to the E
C R service so that we can actually upload our image.
So now in I am I'm going to go to policies create policy,
go to Jason delete this code, paste my code in
and I'm just gonna use this as the name for the policy.
So I'm gonna copy ec our policy to my clipboard,
click on next. Go to review, give it a name, paste that in
and create our policy. So we've now got our E C. R. Policy
That will be what we need to add to the role that we create.
So we're going to create a role of course this is going to be
assumed by 82 so we choose easy to as the common use case.
I then need to find my policy. I can see mine just here.
So I'm gonna select my policy,
click on next
for the role name.
I'm just going to change this to pcr dash role
and that now has the permissions and the trust policy that I need.
So I'm gonna create my role.
The role has been created so we're gonna go back to the Ec two management console now.
And what I want to do is select my instance, go to actions,
go to security modify I am wrong
and then I'm going to select my E C R dash roll
and choose update.
So we now have the permissions we need
to access e C R to upload our image.
So back in our instructions now you can see we now have a series of commands to run.
So we're going to create a repository and give it a
name and it's just going to be called Engine X.
And it's going to be in us East one.
We're then going to tag our container
with latest
and we're going to upload it now.
You need to change this account number here to your account number.
Now mine is set up correctly so I can just copy this entire command.
And we're going to go and create the repository. So back in the command line here
I'm going to run this command
we can see that that has actually created a repository. So if you open up the E C.
R console to go to elastic container registry
then you should find that you now have your repository.
So that looks good.
The next command
is this one so make sure that you have updated
your account number. So this should be your account number.
The rest should be the same.
You should be in the same region as me.
So I'm going to copy that to my clipboard,
paste that one in. I've run that command.
Let me just clear screen and bring stuff down to the middle again for you.
And then the next command again. Make sure your account number is set up correctly.
So now we're gonna run the get log in password
Using the US East one.
We're piping the results of that to Dhaka log in.
So we're going to get the login password
pipe that to docker login user name,
aws password and it's going to be whatever we got from this first part of the command.
And then we've got the account number which you need to update.
And of course the the path to our repository.
So let's run that command.
So I ran that command
and you can see there's a warning but it said log in succeeded.
So that's all we want to see.
And the last command here
is to push
our container image up to the repositories.
So again make sure you've updated your your account number here,
copy that to your clipboard.
Let's come back and let's push
our image
So that's pushing the image up to the elastic container registry service.
That was pretty fast.
Let's go to Ec are now and if we go into our repository
we can see that we have our image with a tag of latest
and that's it for this lesson. We're finished for this one.
Just leave everything as it is.
And in the very next lesson in this series we're
going to create our task definition and our application load balancer