Welcome to the exam cram for amazon E C S and E K S.
Amazon Ec s is used for managing and deploying. Docker containers.
It's serverless with Aws Fargate
that's managed for you and fully scalable,
fully managed container orchestration
is offered with
the control plane is managed for you.
Docker Support means that you can run and manage
Docker containers with integration into the Docker compose Cli
Windows container support means that you can
support management of Windows containers as well.
Elastic load balancing integration means you can distribute traffic
across containers using an A L B or an Nlb
amazon Ec s anywhere, which is new,
enables the use of the DCs control plane to manage on premises implementations.
E C S clusters are a logical grouping
of container instances that you can place tasks on
Clusters can contain tasks using the fargate
and ec two launch type.
You can use any AM I that meets the E C S.
Am I specification.
EC two instances used as container hosts must run an ECs agent.
The E C S container agent allows container instances to connect to the cluster.
The container agent runs on each infrastructure resource on an ec. S cluster
containers are created from a read only template called an
image which has the instructions for creating the Docker container
images are built from a Docker file
only. Docker containers are supported on the CS.
Images are stored in a registry such as
Docker hub or the amazon elastic container registry.
A task definition is required to run Docker containers
in E C s.
The task definition is a text file in
Jason format that describes one or more containers.
The pcs Task I am role provides permissions to the container
the container instance Iron Role provides permissions to the host
tasks have access to all of the permissions
that are supplied to the container instance.
Roll
through instance metadata.
E C. S. Supports the following task placement strategies.
They are been pack which places tasks based on
the least available amount of CPU or memory.
Random places, tasks randomly
spread places tasks evenly based on a specified value.
A task placement constraint is a rule that's considered during task placement.
E C. S supports the following task placement constraints.
Got distinct instance,
which means the task should be placed on a different container instance.
Member of means that you place tasks
on container instances that satisfy an expression.
Cluster queries are expressions that enable you to group objects.
For example, you can group container instances by attributes such as
instance, type or custom metadata
service Auto scaling automatically adjusts the desired task count up or down
using the application. Auto scaling service
cluster auto scaling uses a capacity provider to
scale the number of cluster instances using ec.
Two Auto scaling
amazon Ec R is a fully managed container registry. It's integrated with E C S and E K S
E C R supports open container initiative and Docker registry,
H T T P A P I V two standards.
You can use Docker tools and Docker cli commands such as bush pull list and tag
it can be accessed from any Docker environment in the cloud,
on premises or on your machine.
You can use name spaces to organize your repositories.
E C R also supports lifecycle policies, image scanning,
cross region or account replication and pull through cash rules.
Moving on to
the elastic kubernetes service
is a managed service.
You would use it when you need
to standardize container orchestration across multiple environments.
Using a managed kubernetes implementation
with EKS you have cluster auto scaling,
you've got the vertical pod Auto Scaler
which automatically adjusts the CPU and memory reservations for
your pods to help right size your applications.
We then got the horizontal pod Auto Scaler,
which automatically scales the number of pods in a deployment
replication controller or replica set based on that resources utilization.
Then we have workload auto scaling
E K S supports to auto scaling products.
You've got the kubernetes cluster Auto Scaler or
the Carpenter open source auto scaling project.
E K S supports native VPC networking with the
amazon VPc container network interface plug in for kubernetes.
And that's it for this exam cram. See you in the next lesson