Hello and welcome to this lesson this lesson.
I'm going to cover AWS co pilot now it will be a hands on lesson.
So I'm gonna give you a brief introduction to co pilot and then we're going to go in and
actually see it in action and that's the best way
to understand what co pilot can do for you.
So co pilot is a command line interface for launching and managing containers.
So as you'll see shortly,
it it's going to be a way that we can with a few simple
commands create a containerized application and of
course it uses deployment pipelines if you
wanted to it can use a well architected infrastructure setup process as well and
it can deploy your containerized infrastructure using
ADcs using Fargate or using app Runner.
So those are the free services which it integrates
with in terms of running your containerized application.
It's based on infrastructure as code templates.
So it's actually gonna build out those templates for you.
You run some simple commands to build out your containerized environment
and here's an example of a few of those commands,
simple commands like copilot in it.
To initialize and build your co pilot environment,
then you can look at your applications and show information
about your environments listing the services and so on.
Now we'll see a few of these in action
in a hands on. We're going to build a simple demo containerized environment.
So in the course download, you should find this document,
it's within the AWS copilot directory. It's called copilot commands dot MD.
Now the first command we're going to run
is to launch an ec two instance
so we can run this command AWS Ec two run instances and specify an image I. D.
Now you need to make sure that you've got a current image I. D.
Easy way to do that is in ec two,
choose your region that you're going to perform this exercise in.
I recommend us east one click on launch instances
and then let's just copy the am I I. D. Here
and this is associated with the amazon Linux two AM I
and this is a current I. D.
So when you get to this lab,
almost undoubtedly the idea would have
changed because they change very regularly.
So I'm gonna come back and paste that in,
make sure I've got a space for my next part of the command.
So now I've got the image I. D.
And it's going to be a T two micro
so I can copy this whole command and I'm going to run this on cloud shell
in the cloud shell console. Let's just run this command
and that should launch our ec two instance.
And that has
so let's now go into easy to I just want to check the security group,
I didn't specify a security group, so it's going to put it into the default one.
So under security,
I'm gonna choose security groups and I just need to
make sure I've got an inbound rule for poor 22
from anywhere and I don't in this case. So let's click on edit inbound rules.
Let's add one. I need ssh from anywhere and that's going to allow us to use
ec two instance connect.
So now let's go back to instances our instance
is launching and we should be able to connect
over ec two instance connect.
Great.
So we are on the console and of course it's telling us we should run sudo yum update.
So let's just go ahead and do that, click on Yes and there it
and let's now go over and have a look at the next commands. We need to run.
So the next thing we need to do is we need to install and configure Docker.
Okay, so there's a few commands here that need to be run
in sequence
in order to be able to install and configure Docker
to be ready for use. After that we're going to install Git,
then the copilot cli
then we're going to clone a repository.
Then we're going to run the initialization command to start
the build and that's going to build out our environment.
Alright, so let's get started. The next command is to install Docker.
So I'm just gonna run each of these commands one by one.
Starting with installing Docker.
And you might have to type y and press enter for some of these commands.
Next one is to enable the doctor service
and then start the Docker service.
So let's run that command
created the sim link.
Next one.
Get the service started.
No errors. So everything looks good.
Let me just clear the screen so you can see everything more easily.
Then we need to modify some permissions. Let's paste this command in
and run these final two commands.
All related to permissions,
paste that one in and that's Docker installed and ready for use.
The next thing to do is simply installed. GIT.
Because we're going to clone a repository.
So that's just simply sudo yum install git.
Why and enter and that's going to be installed.
Excellent, that's done.
Next. We're going to install the copilot cli.
So this is the full command online 15 From where
it says Sudo right through to where it says help.
This is going to clone the Cli
to a local directory on
the ec two instance.
So again I'll clear my screen so you can see me run this command
and there we go.
That's done.
The next thing we need to do is install the copilot cli for that. We just run
this entire command from line 15
to run that command
and that has completed successfully.
Next we need to clone the co pilot repository and then change into the app directory.
So we're cloning
from a Git hub repository. It's the amazon ec s cli sample app dot get
And we're going to create our application called demo app.
And for that we need a directory.
So let's clone this repository. I'll clear the screen again.
Let's clone the repository very quickly that has been done.
And then we just changed to the demo app directory.
So back in here let's change in
and let's have a look at what's in here so we can see there's a couple of MD files.
There's a Docker file, there's an index dot html
a license and read me
if you want to have a look at the docker file of course you can just read it from here.
It simply says from engine x copy index dot html to
this location.
The next thing we need to do is run
the
command to start the build. So this is gonna be where we actually use co pilot.
So now we run the co pilot in command
with the app called demo. The name is a P I
it's a load balanced web service. It uses a Docker file which is the Docker file
in the current directory
and the porters 80 because it's a web service and we're going to deploy.
Now of course co pilot is going to need some permissions
so there's a couple of things we have to do before we can run this command.
I'm in the identity and access management service and I'm going to create a role
and this is the role that's going to be used by the
service to create the resources And of course we're using Ec two.
So easy to needs to be able to assume the role so
that it has the permissions to perform the actions via co pilot.
So the use case is easy to now. What permissions do we need?
Well there's quite a few permissions here.
We're going to have some pcs permissions and some low balancing permissions
so you may be able to restrict and create a policy
that gives you exactly what you need for this particular exercise.
Obviously not the best practice but I'm just going to
use administrator access to make sure it works of course in
a real world scenario outside of a demo you'll want to
make sure you lock down the specific permissions you need.
So for the role name I'm simply going to call
this one admin access because that's what the role provides
and create that role.
The role has been created. So let's go to easy to we need to attach
the role. I'm going to use action, security
modify I am role
and give it the admin access. Roll
another thing we need to do is back on our instance
let's just run AWS configure
not because we need to supply any access keys
but because I want to provide the default region name.
Us East one,
that's the region I am using North Virginia
which is US East one.
So press enter and enter again. That's the only variable I needed to supply their.
Alright. So I've got that now I should be able to run my copilot command
so back in the file here,
let's copy the entire command from line six.
Come back, paste that into my ec two instance, connect terminal
and off we go.
So you're gonna see quite a lot happening
as we go through this process,
you can see a lot of feedback in the console
telling you what's being created for instance I am rolls,
we've got ec are repositories and kms keys and s three buckets
so there can be a small cost to this lab
just make sure that when you run this command you
are aware that it's going to do a few things
came as keys for example cost about a dollar each.
So make sure that you're aware of that before you actually
hit that into the command and run this particular setup.
And of course as long as you destroy this environment
at the end it's not going to cost you much
at all if anything because we're not going to be using it for very long
now we can see that cloud formation is being used in the console feedback here.
So let's go over to cloud formation and see
what is actually going on in cloud formation.
So in cloud formation firstly we can see the demo demo
infrastructure roles has been created so that's something that's just happened
and
if we go into that particular stack, go to events, we can see what's being created
and in this case that's simply
the execution roles and administrative roles and so on
that were created
in I am
going to outputs, we've got the administrative role A R N
which is of course and I am and the execution role A R N
which again is an I am roll
the whole setup can take several minutes so you'll be
able to sit back and watch what's going on,
keep an eye on cloud formation for additional resources being created
and in a few minutes time this should complete successfully.
Alright. So that took a little while.
Of course it takes 10 15 minutes, something like that to build out your environment.
And as you can see just by scrolling back through what's happened.
There's been a lot, there's lots of different resources created.
So this is that well architected best practice,
secure configuration for your containerized application
and we'll have a look at some of the components that have been out.
But first it says here you can access your service at
and then it gives me
this Ural.
So I just put this into my browser and there we go.
There's my apps so nothing too exciting but it is working
now let's have a look at the components of course.
If you come back into cloud formation here, I think this is all of it.
You can see that there's been a few different stacks created.
We've got the infrastructure roles here,
we've got the demo infrastructure demo test and test a P I so you can always
have a look through these and then have a look at what resources have been created.
So you're gonna find lots of different resources.
Some of those resources include
multiple lambda functions.
We've of course got an SCS cluster with one running task, we have a demo,
a P I and an image here.
This is elastic container registry.
So this is the container image that was used in S three here.
We can see we have an S three bucket with some assets there.
It's created a co pilot demo test vpc with subnets, internet gateway and so on.
It's also created a private hosted zone called test dot
demo dot local for private DNS resolution within this environment.
So lots of different components and all we did was run one simple command.
So as you can see, it's very, very powerful.
Now there's a few copilot commands that you can
run to check the status of your application,
like copilot app.
Ls
that just tells us that we have this application, you can run copilot app show
and that gives you a little bit more information
about the environment. So that's it for the demo of co pilot.
A very simple way to build containerized environments.
In fact,
once you've set up Docker and you've got your environment configured correctly.
You can run one single co pilot command to build out all of this infrastructure.
So very powerful indeed.
We do want to make sure that we remove our
resources and there's one simple way of doing that.
So just as it's easy to build, it's easy
to destroy as well. So we can run copilot app delete
and that should remove all of the resources.
So back on ec, two instance connects.
I'm simply going to run copilot app delete type Y, press enter and yes,
it's going ahead and it's going to remove all of those resources.
So I would keep an eye on cloud formation.
It should delete all of those stacks,
make sure it does delete everything correctly.
Make sure it has removed all the resources so you
don't end up paying for anything that you don't need.