Hi, guys.
The AWS Cloud Development Kit, CDK, is one of those services that you just about need to
know a little bit of information for the exam.
It doesn't come up very often.
And if it does, it might even just be an incorrect answer rather than a correct one.
So it really it's just about knowing what it is and at a very basic level, what it's useful.
The CDK gives you a framework for defining your cloud applications, using programming languages
that your development team might be familiar with.
It will provision your resources using AWS CloudFormation.
So there's a key point here.
You're taking a familiar programming language, for example, Python, TypeScript, Java, and .NET
and you're then using CloudFormation to deploy your resources.
Now, as you know from our CloudFormation lessons, the CloudFormation templates are written in YAML
or JSON.
So maybe your developers aren't familiar with those languages and they want to define their applications
using Python and TypeScript or Java or .NET.
So that's what the Cloud Development Kit does.
You can then use existing IDE, testing tools, and workflow patterns.
So let's have a look at the flow of how this works.
You download pre-configured application components, you then model your infrastructure using
one of those familiar programming languages like type TypeScript or Python.
And then you deploy with AWS CloudFormation.
So you no longer need to use YAML or JSON.
It means that your developers can stick to what they know.
And that's really it for the Cloud Development Kit.
You don't need to know anything else for the exam, but just in case it pops up, this bit of information
should help you.