Hey guys in this lesson, we're going to talk about aWS app Config. So what is the app?
Conflict service?
This is a service you can use to create,
manage and deploy application configurations.
So the configuration settings that influence your application,
it's actually a capability of AWS Systems Manager.
Systems Manager is constantly being expanded.
There's always new capabilities being introduced. An app config is one of the rela
recent ones within app Config we create something called a configuration and this
is a collection of settings that influence the behavior of your application.
Now of course these settings need to be defined as a configuration in app
config and the application needs to be designed and written in such a way
that these settings do influence the behavior of the application.
So it's a case of making sure your application is coded the right way
and then setting the configuration settings in app conflict and
validating that they are the way they should be.
And deploying settings as well when you want to change the configuration
of your application and that is all done centrally from Systems Manager
applications can be hosted on ec, two instances AWS lambda functions,
mobile applications
and IOT devices.
The app conflict service helps to
reduce errors associated with configuration changes and
it helps you to streamline your deployment
of those configuration settings as well.
Configurations can be stored in a few places.
We've got amazon S three, you got the AWS app config itself,
you've got Systems Manager parameter store.
Systems Manager document store,
you can also put them into bit bucket git hub or codecommit via aWS.
Codepipeline applications must be updated to check
for and retrieve conf configuration data.
So that's something that needs to be coded into your application Now.
Some of the API applications include and these are perhaps
the two most important ones for connecting your applications.
One is start configuration session and the
other is get latest configuration validators are
something that's used to ensure that configuration
data is syntactic lee and semantically correct.
Now validators are either Jason schema validators or
us
validators.
When we deploy our configuration settings using app
config the deployment type is evil linear.
Which uses a growth factor based on a step percentage or exponential,
which uses the formula which I'm not going to try and interpret for you,
but there's a formula there and there's a bit
more information on that one on the AWS website.
If you want to understand in more detail. There's also deployment strategies.
Now these are app config dot all at once,
which is all target at the same time or app conflict dot linear.
50% every 30 seconds.
Which simply means that 50% of the targets are deployed to every 30 seconds.
Let's have a look at a couple of example configurations to help you understand
what sort of configuration settings are we
defining on our applications using app conflict.
Well,
here's an example that enables or disables mobile payments
and default payments on a per region basis.
In another example,
this enforces limits on how an application processes requests.
So we've got throttle limits here in simultaneous connections and so on.
So that's it for app conflict,
that should be enough to help you understand the
basics of this service and what it's there for.
And of course, if you want to do some more reading on app conflict,
there's lots more information on the AWS website.
It's hard to do a hands on on this one without
actually having an application with some settings that we can define.
But there may be some tutorials on AWS as well.