So let's go into the console now and create a CloudTrail trail.
I'm in the management console on the AWS CloudTrail dashboard.
Now if you just click the create a trail button here, it doesn't give you many options.
What I prefer to do instead is just expand the options on the left here.
We're going to come down to trails and create a trail.
Now we're going to do that in a moment.
Firstly, I want to show you some of the information that's already available in CloudTrail. On the
dashboard,
this is where you can see your trails and your event history.
Another way you can see your event history is by selecting this option on the left.
So, as you can see, there's already information being generated in here and being stored.
But this will only be stored for 90 days because we haven't created a trail yet.
But you can see what's happening in the account.
So, for example, we can see a terminate instances event here. With the event selected, in the bottom here,
we can see some information about this particular API event.
We've got the name, where we can see the actual action,
terminate instances, the ID, the time that it happened, the user name, and event source.
Now, as you can see, this is not my account.
This was not me terminating an instance.
This was in response to an alarm
and so it was AWS that actually terminated that instance.
And you've got information like the source IP, which in this case is an AWS domain name.
So there's quite a bit of an information log there.
And at the bottom here we have the resource. We have the resource type which is EC2 instance
and the resource name which is the ID of that instance.
So, we've already got this information, but we want to log it and keep it for a long period of time.
So what we're going to do is go to trails, create a trail.
As per the suggestion, I'll call it Management Events.
Now, I'm not going to enable this one for all accounts, it's just going to be for this account.
But within AWS Organizations, you can enable a trail across all of your accounts.
Now, it's going to need a storage location.
By default, it'll create a new S3 bucket and give it a very unique name.
I'm just going to leave that as the default.
I do want to encrypt my information in my bucket.
So, what I'm going to do is select a new key, call it CloudTrail.
We then have log file validation.
This is enabled by default.
What this will do is it will generate a digest of each log file, which cannot be tampered with.
So, it gives you some information about that log file and
you can now determine whether your log files have been tampered with or not.
So, it's a great way of making sure that you've got that confidence in this information that you might
want to use for auditing or compliance.
Now, I'm not going to enable SNS. And we can optionally enable CloudWatch logs here.
Let's go ahead and do that.
It will create a new log route for us. For logging to CloudWatch logs
it's going to need some permissions.
So, it's going to use an IAM role. In this case,
we're going to allow CloudTrail to create the role for us.
I'm going to call it CloudTrail Role for CW Logs.
Let's click on next.
And here you get to select the type of events. We're just going to choose management events.
You could optionally enable data events.
Now, if you do that and you scroll down, you'll see the different event sources that are available.
We've got S3, Lambda, and DynamoDB. Or if we switch to advanced, then we get more.
We get Lambda, DynamoDB, Outpost and a few more.
Now, we're not going to do that.
It does generate a significant amount of information.
We're going to deselect data events.
I'm not going to enable insights events at this time either.
So, we just have management events enabled.
We're going to log, read and write API activity.
Let's click on next and just scroll down and create our trail.
So that's it.
Our trail has been created. And that's all we're going to do for this lesson.
We're going to leave our trail because we're actually going to use the information that's generated
by that trail with Amazon EventBridge in a couple of lessons time.