Hi guys. In this lesson, I'm going to create a couple of custom KMS keys.
So those will be customer managed KMS keys.
Now, unfortunately they're not in the free tier,
so they do cost $1 for each key per month.
For KMS, there's also usage fees,
but we won't incur any of those because there's a lot of
allocation in the free tier and we won't come anywhere close.
So I'm on the KMS homepage here and I'm going to choose to create a key.
Firstly, I need to choose whether it's going to be symmetric or asymmetric key.
Now I'm going to use these keys for EC2.
In other words our EBS volumes, RDS and S3, so I need to choose symmetric.
Let's choose advanced options. We firstly need to choose the key material origin.
So where is our key material coming from?
Is KMS going to generate it?
Or are we going to provide our own? So external.
Or are we going to use a custom key store CloudHSM.
Well, I'm going to choose KMS and that means
I can then enable automatic rotation if I want to.
For regionality, I'm only going to use this in a single region.
So I'm happy keeping it as a single region key.
And then I'm going to choose next.
For alias, I'm going to call it KMS Key General.
I won't put a description in and I'm not going to put any tags in,
but you can use tags for things like tracking your costs as well.
So let's choose next.
So now, I need to choose the key administrators.
These are the people who are able to administrate the key.
Now remember, from the theory
there's administration and there's usage of the key.
So firstly, we define who is able to administer the key.
Now, I'm just going to set it for myself, Neal.
And I'm going to allow the key administrators to delete this key as well.
Then I choose next.
And here we have the usage permission.
So who is allowed to perform cryptographic operations using this key.
Again, I'm going to choose my own user account.
Then I'll choose next.
And what we'll see here is we get the key policy, so the settings
that we've just applied through the user interface
have now generated this key policy.
And I don't need to modify this policy but I can see here that we're allowing
the account, so this first ARN here
relates to the account not specifically the root user but the account.
So it's enabling IAM user permissions for this KMS key.
Then we get the allow access for key administrators
and we can see the principal and that's my ARN for my account.
I'm able to perform all these various actions.
And then we get the usage of the key, and again it's the ARN for my account.
And I can see that I'm able to use the key by performing these API actions.
And there's also some additional permissions here
for things like delegation, so allowing the creation of grants.
So I'm going to click on finish.
And that's my first key created.
I'm now going to create another key.
Let's create a key. It's going to be symmetric again.
I'm going to leave it as a KMS-generated key material in a single region again.
And for alias, I'm going to specify KMS Key EBS RDS.
Now, in this case, I'm actually going to leave these options blank
because what I want to do is come straight through to the policy editor
and I'm going to delete all of this code.
And we have some code which we're going to use for this exercise.
So in your code directory from the course download you'll find
AWS KMs folder and then this file, KMS Key EBS RDS.
So what is this one going to do?
Well, as before, we're allowing access for key administrators.
and we're going to specify an ARN here and that's going to be
the ARN of my user account again.
We're then going to restrict key usage to EC2 and RDS.
So again, I'm going to specify the ARN for my user account.
I'm going to provide the actions for usage here,
and then I'm going to have a condition.
And the condition will be using the KMS via service condition key
and it's checking that were coming from EC2 or RDS.
So we should only be able to use this key with EC2 and RDS.
So there's a couple of things we need to change here. We need to change the ARN.
And I'm going to put that to my user account and I'm going to do that in two places.
So in the IAM console, I'm going to find my usual account
and then I'm simply going to copy my ARN.
And then I'm going to paste that in here
and make sure I put that into the two different places.
And then we're going to copy this code.
Now note that I have been using us-east-1 region as I mostly do for the course.
And you'll see that we've got us-east-1 in the condition key here.
So make sure if you are using a different region you need to
specify your user account and then you'll need to change the region here.
So mine is good. So I'm going to copy all of this code.
And back in KMS, I'm going to paste the code into the key policy
and click on finish.
So now we have these two different keys.
They're both symmetric and they allow encryption and decryption.
If we go into the first one we created,
we can see under key policy the key administrators and it's set to me
and the key users and that's set to my account as well.
For cryptographic configuration, again, you can see it's a symmetric key.
The origin of the key material is AWS KMS.
And you can see that it's used for symmetric encryption.
Tags, we didn't specify any.
For key rotation because we're using KMS generated key material,
we could enable automatic rotation if we want to for this key.
And you can also create aliases here. So it has one alias.
You can create additional aliases if you like as well.
To go back up and then just check out our other one,
We'll see rather than specifying the user accounts,
all we see is the policy because we actually just generated a policy, added that in,
and we've specified who is allowed to use this key.
Now that's it for this lesson. We now have our two keys and we're going to use those
in subsequent hands-on lessons within this section.