In this lesson, I want to familiarize you with a few KMS, API and CLI commands
and also we're going to look at some of the throttling mechanisms of KMS
and how we can use caching to overcome them.
Something that comes up in exam questions.
So let's go through some of the API and CLI commands.
So in the first one here, we have encrypt. Encrypt would be the API action.
AWS KMS encrypt would be the CLI command.
This one would encrypt plain text into cipher text using a KMS key.
You can encrypt small amounts of arbitrary data such as personal identifiers,
database passwords, and other sensitive information.
You can use the encrypt operation to move encrypted data from one region to another.
Decrypt is used to decrypt cipher text that was
encrypted by a KMS key using any of these operations;
Encrypt, GenerateDataKey, GenerateDataKeyPair, or GenerateDataKeyWithoutPlaintext
and also GenerateDataKeyPairWithoutPlaintext.
Next, we have re-encrypt.
This decrypts the cipher text and then re-encrypts it entirely within KMS.
You can use it to change the KMS key under which the data is encrypted
such as if you manually rotate a KMS key or
change the KMS key that protects your encrypted data.
You can also use it to re-encrypt cipher text under the same KMS key
if you want to change the encryption context of your encrypted data.
Next, we have enable-key-rotation.
This will enable automatic rotation of the key
material for the specified symmetric KMS key.
You can't perform this operation on a KMS key in a different AWS account.
Next, we have GeneratedDataKey.
This will generate a unique symmetric data key.
When you run this API it returns a plain text copy of the data key
and a copy that's encrypted under a KMS key that you get to specify.
You can use the plain text key to then encrypt your data outside
of KMS and store the encrypted data key with the encrypted data.
Then you get GenerateDataKeyWithoutPlaintext.
This generates a unique symmetric data key
and returns the data key that's encrypted under a KMS key that you specify.
If you want to request an asymmetric data key pair,
you can use GenerateDataKeyPair or GenerateDataKeyPairWithoutPlaintext.
Now, of course, there are many more API and CLI commands than these.
These are a few that I thought I would bring to your attention just
because they're the ones that are more likely to come up on the exam.
It may be worth having a look through the various KMS
API just to familiarize yourself with them as well before the exam.
So moving on to throttling and caching.
KMS has two types of quotas that enforces. One is a resource quota.
The other is a request quota.
If you exceed a resource limit and this is where the resource quotas would apply,
then requests to create an additional resource of
that type will generate a limit exceeded exception error.
Request quotas apply to API actions like encrypt,
decrypt, re-encrypt and generate data key.
If you exceed a request quota, you may get a throttling error.
And that might look like this where it says you
have exceeded the rate at which you may call KMS,
reduce the frequency of your calls.
As you can see, there's a status code 400 and error code throttling exception.
And if you really saw this, you'd get the request ID of course as well.
So what can you do about this?
Firstly, you can implement a back off and retry strategy.
In this case you would implement this through your code,
and your code would back off for a period of time
and hopefully be a bit more efficient when it re-tries, so it doesn't overwhelm KMS.
You can also request a service quota increase.
If you do really need to consistently generate a
large amount of API actions against your resources,
then using a service quota increase may help.
You can also implement something called data key caching, and this does come up
in exam questions.
Data key caching stores your data keys
and related cryptographic material in a cache.
So this would be useful if your application
can reuse data keys,
it generates numerous data keys
and it runs cryptographic operations that are unacceptably slow, expensive,
limited or resource intensive.
Now, you can do this by creating a local cache using
the AWS encryption SDK and the local crypto materials cache feature.
And that's it for this lesson, I'll see you in the next one.