AWS Certificate Manager, ACM is a service that we can use for issuing certificates. And we actually
used it earlier in the course.
Now those certificates are SSL/TLS certificates that we can then use for encryption in transit.
So let's look at some key facts about ACM.
You can use it to create, store, and renew SSL/TLS X.509 certificates.
You can have single domains or multiple domains and even wild cards on the certificates that you issue.
It integrates with several AWS services, and those include Elastic Load Balancing,
we saw that earlier in the course, Amazon CloudFronts, Elastic Beanstalk, and AWS Nitro Enclaves. And also
AWS CloudFormation.
The public certificates are signed by the AWS Public Certificate Authority.
But you can also create your own private certificate authority within ACM, and if you do that, you
can then issue private certificates as well.
You can also import certificates from third party issuers.
You can take key material that you've created, and you can actually import that and create a certificate
in AWS.
So those are really the core facts. The exams not going to go to deep in ACM,
there's not too much you need to know about it.
You just need to be able to differentiate from the certificates that you're issuing with ACM, which
are SSL/TLS certificates versus the cryptographic keys that you're issuing using KMS or CloudHSM.
So make sure you remember which service is used for encryption in transit,
that's ACM, and encryption at rest will be AWS KMS.