Hi guys, in this lesson, I'm going to introduce you to AWS Systems Manager,
a product which does come up quite a bit on the Solutions Architect Pro exam.
Now, we'll walk through at a high level the various components of systems manager.
And then I've got four or five hands-on lessons where we're actually going to go in and have a look
at each of those components, not every one of them, but the few key components that make up some of
the questions on the exam.
So systems manager is a way that you can manage AWS resources.
Now, largely we're talking about EC2 but you can manage other resources as well.
Systems manager has several components.
We've got automation, we've got the run command, inventory, patch manager, session manager
and parameter store.
So let's have a quick overview of each of these.
With systems manager automation you have something called a document.
The document defines the actions to perform, and it's written in YAML or JSON.
And you can see a bit of an example of one here where this particular document is going to create a
snapshot for an RDS instance.
The documents are then fed into systems manager automation, which will automate the IT operations
and management tasks across the AWS resources such as RDS.
And in this case, that means taking a snapshot of the RDS database.
We then have run command.
Very, very similar, also has documents.
And in this case they include things like command, automation, and packages.
So, for example, in this example here we are listing the missing Microsoft Windows updates.
And we'll then find out what they are and we'll be able to patch then which we'll look at shortly.
So in this case, you're using the documents in run command and run command will then actually run the
commands on the managed EC2 instances.
And in this case, that means checking for missing software updates.
Next, we have inventory.
Quite simply, this gives you an inventory of the resources that you're managing.
Now with systems manager, we'll look at this shortly, but you need to install an agent on your instances.
You also need to make sure that they have a role so that they can authenticate and actually have access
to send information into systems manager.
And we use tags and resource groups as well, which you'll see in the hands-on.
Now, once the information is collected, we can then gather all this data here, visualize it,
and then drill down into the various components of the inventory.
The next service is patch manager.
This helps you select and deploy operating system and software patches across your EC2
and also on-premise instances.
We have something called patch baselines.
This is where you can set rules to auto-approve categories of patches to be installed and you can also
specify lists of patches that override the rules.
You can also schedule maintenance windows for patches so that they are only applied during
specific times.
Patch manager helps to make sure your software is up to date and meets any compliance policies you might
have in your organization.
So talking about compliance, systems manager will let you scan your managed instances
for patch compliance as well as configuration inconsistencies.
We'll see how this works in the hands-on.
You'll see it visually.
You can collect and aggregate data from multiple accounts and regions and then drill down into
the resources that aren't compliant.
By default, systems manager will display data about patching and also associations.
You can also customize the service, create your own compliance types based on your requirements.
So that means if you have some specific configuration that you want to check is deployed across certain
resources, then you can create that configuration in systems manager compliance and then check if your
instances meet that particular requirement.
We then have something called session manager.
Now, a really useful tool here and something that definitely comes up in exam questions.
The types of questions come up are where the company is using the standard protocols
for connecting to EC2.
That would be SSH for Linux and RDP for Windows, but they might have some kind of malicious
attacks happening or just some general security mandate that says that they don't like to have those
ports open.
So how else can we manage our instances?
Well, we can use session manager.
This allows you to actually connect to a command line on your instances without logging into your servers.
You don't need bastion hosts, you don't need SSH, you don't need remote PowerShell.
And that means you don't need to open up the ports that you typically would for those protocols.
It also integrates with IAM for granular permissions and the actions that are taken can be recorded
in CloudTrail.
So you can see an audit log of what commands are being actually run on your instances through session
manager.
You can store session logs in S3 and have your output going to CloudWatch logs as well.
To enable this to work, you need IAM permissions for the EC2 instance to access
SSM, S3 and CloudWatch logs.
So the great thing here is you don't need these ports open.
You don't need SSH, you don't need the ports for RDP.
You're not using those protocols.
You're connecting based on the systems manager agent on those particular EC2 instances and avoiding
the use of those protocols, so it can be a lot more secure.
And again, you don't need bastion hosts.
So this way you don't have to set up a bastion host that you connect to in a public subnet in order
to then jump into a private subnet.
You can just connect directly using session manager to your instances in private subnets.
That's quite a big advantage.
We then have systems manager parameter store.
This is a service that allows you to store configuration data and secrets and it can be hierarchical
as well.
It's scalable, available and durable.
You can store data such as passwords, database strength's, license codes, and they get stored as
a parameter value in parameter store.
You can store in plain text, so unencrypted or you can use ciphertext so you can encrypt your data in
systems manager.
You can also reference the values by a unique name that you define when you create the parameter
so you can then store that in your application code.
Now there's no native rotation of keys and this is a difference between Secrets Manager, which does
do that automatically for you.
So watch out for exam questions that mention automatic rotation of the actual keys that are stored
in the parameter store or in the Secrets Manager database.
So if you're storing some kind of secret like a database connection string and you need it automatically
rotate it every certain period of time, then Secrets Manager might be a better option
than parameter store.
So quite simply, this works like this.
You've got your EC2 instance, you've got parameter store and you've got a database.
And you're EC2 to instance needs a secret connection string with some kind of authentication
information to connect to RDS.
So it talks to parameter store, pulls the data and now it can talk to RDS.
So it's retrieve that connection string.
And that means it's not stored in the code so it's much more secure.
So that's it for the overview of systems manager.
What we would do over the next few lessons is we're going to configure systems manager
and then we're going to use it.
We're going to look into some of these individual features of systems manager in a hands-on way.