Amazon Cognito is principally used for adding sign in and sign-up functionality to web and mobile
applications, so that's the first thing to remember about Cognito.
Then we need to understand the different pools.
We have user pools and identity pools, and I'm going to show you what those are.
So firstly, we have a Cognito user pool.
Let's say we have a client or mobile application and we have an API Gateway. Behind that API Gateway
we have AWS services we want to connect to.
So, that's used for the application.
Then we have a Cognito user pool.
This is where our identities are stored or it's where we federate to an identity source.
So this is where it really starts to become a little confusing because as I mentioned, there's user
pools and identity pools.
So you've got to remember that the identities are in the user pool.
The actual identity pool is used for getting temporary credentials.
We'll see that in a moment.
So, the client or mobile application is going to use the user pool for signing in or signing up.
Basically, that's going to be where the credentials in the user account is stored for this client or
mobile application.
So the user authenticates using the user pool.
And in this case, receive something called a Java Web token.
The JWT can then be passed on to API Gateway, so a Cognito is essentially acting as an identity broker
between the IDP and AWS.
Then we can connect to AWS Lambda.
In this case, something called a Lambda authorizer is able to accept and process the JWT.
Now, as I mentioned, our identities can be stored in the user pool or we can actually federate to
an identity provider like a social IDP like Facebook or Apple or Amazon or Google.
So that's user pools.
Now let's look at identity pools.
So let's say we want to get authorized access to Lambda or DynamoDB.
So we have a Cognito identity pool.
The identity pool is used to obtain temporary, limited privileged credentials for the AWS services,
so it uses the AWS STS service to do that.
We then have a user pool.
This is where the identities are stored.
So remember, identities can come from a user pool. They don't have to.
You can actually federate to an identity pool directly, but you can store identities in a user pool.
You can create and store them
there or federate the user pool to a social IDP as well.
So, this user pool might be federated to one of these social ID providers.
Now, once the user is authenticated using the Cognito user pool,
they then need to be able to get some credentials for AWS.
So, they go to the Cognito Identity Pool.
The identity pool then uses the AWS STS service to obtain the temporary credentials, and a role is assumed.
Then, once the role is assumed, we can access the AWS services.
So let's have a look at these put together in another way.
We've got a client mobile application.
We've got a region with some services running in it.
We've got a user pool and we've got an identity pool. And we've got a social IDP that's connected to
our user pool as well.
So the first step here is we need to get the JWT.
So, the client application authenticates and gets the tokens from the Cognito user pool and then exchanges
those tokens for AWS credentials using the identity pool, and then uses those credentials to access the
services on AWS.
So, that's how it all works.
I think the key thing to really understand is the difference between user pools and identity pools.
Don't go into the exam until you're clear about the differences.
So remember, the user pools are where you can create your users, your identities or you can federate it
to a social IDP. The identity pool is principally responsible for getting the temporary credentials
from the IWS STS service.