Hi guys.
In this lesson, I'm going to show you how to install the AWS Command Line Interface.
We're going to install it on a Linux instance and also on a Windows instance.
AWS provides some great instructions.
So what I'm going to do is use Google to search for AWS CLI
Now, what you'll see here is the AWS Command Line Interface comes up
and the best way to go here is to choose the installing your updating
the latest version of the CLI.
So now you've got the instructions.
Now, they're really easy to follow, but I'm going to show you on Linux and Windows.
Now, if you use Mac Os, I do as well.
It's also extremely simple.
So you can simply download the package file here
and follow the on screen instructions or you can choose to use
these other options as well. It's much easier just to download the package.
Just double click it and then it's simply a case of running the installation.
So I'm going to show you how to use the installer for Linux first.
Now, what we need to do for Linux is just run a series of commands.
So what I'm going to do, there's one option here
to kind of get all the commands in one go.
or you can run them separately.
Now, I'm going to use an EC2 instance for Linux.
It's running Ubuntu.
Now, if you use the Amazon 2 Linux AMI, which we use throughout the course
it already has the CLI installed.
So you don't need to do anything.
So what I'm going to do here is simply
copy this first command which downloads the installer.
Logged into my Ubuntu instance, I'm going to paste in that command.
And it simply downloaded the file.
So if I run LS, I can now see that I have the installer.
Next I come back,
take the unzip command to my clipboard, paste that in just to unzip the file.
In this case I don't have the unzip utility installed on Ubuntu
so that means I just have to run this command.
So we just run Sudo apt install unzip.
That's done.
I'm just going to clear the screen to bring this back up
to the top so you can see it more easily.
And then we rerun the unzip command.
And that's going to unzip all those files.
If I run LS again, you can see we now have this directory.
Then what we need to do is run Sudo./AWS/install.
So I copy that to my clipboard, come back,
paste that in and that should now be installed.
Now it tells me I can run user local bin aws --version.
And that should then show me the version of the CLI that's running.
You should also be able to just run AWS on its own.
So then you can see the various options that are available to you using the CLI.
Now, we're going to go into more details about how to use the CLI in another lesson.
So that's how you install the CLI on Linux using the command line.
So next I want to show you how to do it on windows.
So for windows it's quite simple.
All we need to do is download and run the CLI MSI installer.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to copy this to my clipboard.
I'm now on an EC2 instance running Windows.
And what I've done is pasted in that link to the MSI into my browser.
Let's just download this file. I need to click on save.
And the file has been downloaded.
Now just before we install, I just want to show you in a command prompt.
If I type AWS, it says it's not recognized as an internal
or external command so it's not actually known
as a utility that's installed on this system.
So I'm going to click on run at the bottom of the page here.
And that's going to run the MSI installer.
And it's just simply a case of clicking next,
accepting the license agreement,
and then going through and allowing the default options,
and that's going to be installed very quickly.
Then I'm going to click finish.
And let's come back to our command prompt and try and rerun AWS.
And that's not allowing it.
So what I'm going to do is I'm just going to close that out.
Let's open it again.
That might make a difference.
So I'm just going to search for cmd,
open the command prompt, type AWS,
and this time we can see that we do get a response.
So you can also run AWS --version
and that will then show you the version that's actually installed.
So it's the AWS CLI version two.
So that's how you install the CLI on Linux and windows.
As I mentioned, very simple on Mac as well, you just download the package installer
and run it.
Now, we're not able to do anything with our CLI at this point.
And the reason is we don't actually have any credentials, so we
don't have any permissions to be able to work with AWS.
So for example, if I run a command such as the AWS S3 LS command,
and this will list any buckets which we have in the Amazon S3 storage service.
And what will get as a response is unable to locate credentials.
So we have to run this command, AWS configure
and we have to supply some information which will enable
us to have the permissions to speak to AWS services.
And that's something we're going to do in another lesson.