In this lesson, we're going to configure some credentials for our command line
so that we can enable a user to work with AWS.
Now back in the IAM management console,
what we're going to do for this particular exercise is I'm going to
use the user Paul and we're going to configure our terminal for Paul.
So let's go into Paul's account here.
And what I need to do is I need to generate some security credentials.
Now you'll remember that when we created the account,
we only enabled management console access.
That means that Paul doesn't have any access keys to
use for accessing AWS programmatically through the API or the CLI.
So what we do is we go to security credentials,
we just scroll down and choose create access key.
And what we get here is two pieces of information. We get the access key ID,
and then we get the secret access key.
Now you shouldn't share this information with anyone because
this information is all that's needed to be able to access AWS
as the particular user that it's associated with.
Now I don't mind showing you because I'm going to delete them.
You can always delete these at any time and create new ones.
So I'm going to copy the access key ID.
That's the first piece of information I need.
And I'm going to paste it somewhere where I can keep it securely recorded.
Then I'm going to select show for the secret access key,
copy that to my Clipboard and store that securely as well.
And I'm now going to configure the credentials on both the Linux instance
and the Windows instance that we used in the last lesson.
I'm back on my Linux instance and I'm going to run the command AWS configure.
The first thing it's going to ask me for is my access key ID.
So let's paste that in, hit enter, and then I need to enter my secret access key.
So I'm going to paste that in.
Then it asked me for the default region name.
For me, I'm going to use us-east-1.
Then I can hit enter.
Enter again.
And we've now configured the CLI.
So now, if I run a command like AWS S3 LS to list the buckets in my account,
rather than getting the unable to locate credentials
instead, it just gives me an access denied.
So it's a slightly different error message.
And the reason for that is we don't actually have any permissions at this stage to S3.
So back in the console, what I'm going to do for the purposes of the demonstration
is I'm going to give some permissions to this user.
So what we're going to do is C Lick on, add permissions,
I'm going to choose to attach existing policies directly.
So this is going to add the policies directly to this user.
and we're going to choose two different policies.
I want to provide full access to EC2, so I choose Amazon EC2 full access.
And I want to provide full access to S3.
So I'm going to choose Amazon S3 full access.
Click on next and add permissions.
So rather than using a group, we've added these permissions directly to this user.
Back on my Linux instance, if I rerun this command
now I don't get any error message.
Now I don't see anything because I don't have any buckets at this point.
But the fact that I don't get an error message shows that we do now have permissions.
And we will work with a few commands in the next lesson to show you how to use the CLI.
When we configured the CLI there were a couple of files that were created.
I want to show you those now.
Now, I'm going to use cat, the utility to be able to read the files.
And I put in cat.AWS/.
And there's actually two different files.
One is called credentials and one is called config.
Now in fact we're going to Config first.
and hit enter.
And this is the contents of the file.
It literally just has the configuration for the region that I specified.
So nothing particularly interesting other than the default region.
But if we go into the credentials file,
here we see something really important. So we have the access key ID
and the secret access key.
So of course this is within my usual account on this EC2 instance,
but it's stored here in plain text.
It's not encrypted.
If you compromise this instance, you compromise these credentials,
and then you can do anything that Paul can do with AWS.
So not particularly secure configuration,
but it's you need to know that this exists here.
So let's now go to our Windows instance
and we're going to configure our credentials on Windows.
Using the command line on Windows, I'm going to also run the AWS configure command.
It's going to ask me for the same information.
So I put in my access key ID, followed by my secret access key.
Again, I'm going to specify us-east-1 as my region, hit enter again.
And now I've configured my command line.
And again I can run a command like AWS S3 LS.
And it shouldn't error.
And if it doesn't, that means then we have permissions to that service.
So that's great. We've configured the credentials for our user account.
Now, just like on Linux,
there are a couple of files that have been created in our file system.
So what I'm going to do is just show you quickly
where those are because it's slightly different on Windows.
So on Windows, what I'm going to do is go to my C drive,
I'm going to go into users,
choose administrator as that's the account I'm logged in with.
You would just choose whatever your user name is on your computer
and you'll see the .AWS directory is here.
And then you get the same file.
So we have the config which specifies our region and then the credentials file.
And if we open that up with note pad,
just as before, we're going to see the access key ID and a secret access key.
Now, what I've shown you really are the key differences
between running the CLI on windows and Linux.
So the location of the credentials and the config file is obviously
different because the layout of the file system is different between Linux
and Windows.
But other than that, running commands on the CLI is exactly the same.
So of course your directory structure where you store your
files is going to be different on Windows or Linux.
So you need to know where you're storing information
you might want to supply to a command.
But other than that, the actual commands, the AWS commands are exactly the same.
So when I show you commands throughout the course and I'm often using Mac,
it doesn't matter if you're on Linux or Windows or Mac, it's going to be the same.
And that's it for this lesson.
In the next lesson, I'm going to give you more of an overview of using the CLI
and you'll actually get to see some commands in action.