Hi guys and welcome to this section.
In this section we're going to get our AWS account up and running,
you're going to create a free tier account
and then perform some configuration on that account.
Make sure you set up multi factor authentication and it's
also very important to set up a billing alarm.
So we will be launching lots of services in
this course through the many hands on lessons.
So you'll want to make sure that you've got a billing alarm just in
case you forget to terminate or delete something that might cost you money.
So the billing alarm can be set at a low value like $5 and you'll get an
email notifying you that you are starting to run up a little bit of a bill.
You'll also learn about the AWS identity and access management service.
I am and I'm going to teach you about role based
access control and attribute based access
control to really important concepts for
how we can control access to resources and I'll show you
how to actually assume an I am role using the console.
So I hope you enjoy the lessons. I'll see you in the next one