Hi, guys.
Before we get started creating our accounts, I'm just going to walk you through what the process is
and a little bit of information about what the account includes.
So what you're going to need when you sign up to us is a credit card and you're going to need a unique
email address.
So one that has not been used to create any other accounts, then with these two things through the
signup process aways is going to create the account for you.
Now, when you sign in to the account, you'll be signing in using the account root user.
The root user has full control over the account and you use the email address you signed up with to
log in as the account root user.
Now you can also use the Identity and Access Management Service to create users, groups, roles and
permissions policies, and you should be using those to log in.
So, for example, the best thing to do is to create your own individual user accounts in IAM and log
in as that account.
The root user account is very powerful and it's an IAM best practice to create individual users and
avoid using the root account if you can.
Now we'll look in more detail at what users, groups, roles and policies are and how they're used within
the course.
But for now, just understand that when you create your account you'll be using the root user account.
When you initially log in.
When we log into our US accounts, for example, using the management console, we get authenticated.
It's the identity and access management principles that are used to authenticate IAM, whether you're
using the management console, the API for programmatic access or the command line interface, then
authorization happens and authorization is the process of determining what you're allowed to do.
So for example, you may be able to create resources across different regions around the world and all
of those resources are created within the AWS account and all of the identities you're using, like
the users, the groups, the roles and the policies are within the account.