Hey, guys, and welcome to this hands on lesson.
In this lesson, we're going to create an awareness free tier account.
So what are you going to need?
You will need a credit card for setting up the account and paying any bills.
You'll need a unique email address for this account that shouldn't be used with any other US accounts.
But it's okay if your credit card has been used with other accounts.
Now just as a tip.
Depending on your email provider, you may be able to use something called a dynamic alias.
So for example, if your email is John at gmail.com, you can create a dynamic alias that looks like
this.
You would write John plus and then you would have some unique name and then at gmail.com.
In this case what I'm using is the alias for my AWS account, which will come to in a moment.
Then if I create additional accounts, I can just put that alias in or maybe add a two on the end.
Now the account name and alias needs to be unique across us and you'll see how we create that shortly.
Lastly, you need a phone to receive an SMS verification code, so that's all you need.
Let's get on with it.
The easiest way to find the right web page is to search for a free to in Google.
And the very first result here is where we need to go.
So here we can create our free tier accounts.
Now you'll see that what a US offers is there's 12 months free for many US services.
There's also a free tier for some services on an ongoing basis or a certain amount of the resources
you can use.
Now, if you scroll down a little way, you can see what comes with the free tier and it's really generous.
We get 750 hours a month of Amazon EC2, but we've got to make sure we use the right instance type so
we don't get charged.
Now you can see you get five gigabytes of storage on Amazon, S3 750 hours of ads and 25 gigabytes on
the Dynamo DB database service.
So we get a really large amount of resources that we can use, and it's usually more than enough for
the exercises in the course.
So let's click Create a free tier account.
Now, on this page, which is the normal sign in page, we just click create a new AWS account.
Now the very first thing it asks for is a root user email address, and this is going to be the address
we sign in with as the root user after we've created our account.
So make sure you have an email address that is unique.
On AWS, we also need to provide an account name.
So this I've called Neil Dash AWS Dash Labs and you can change this after you've signed up.
So I'm ready to go.
I'm going to click on Verify email address.
I've now been emailed a verification code and I need to put that in and click on Verify.
After the verification, we need to enter a strong root user password and then confirm it before continuing
on this page of the sign up.
We need to enter some contacts information.
Now the first thing you need to do is choose personal because we're using this for our own purposes.
Then enter all of your personal information and click on Continue.
Next, we need to enter our billing information.
So enter in your credit card details and then click on Verify and continue on step four or five.
You need to enter your phone number, enter the characters from the security check, and then click
send SMS so they can verify that your phone number is working on the last page.
After you've verified your phone number is to choose a support plan.
Now you don't need to pay for support.
You can choose the basic support free and then just choose complete sign up and that's it.
We have actually created our AWS account.
Now, as you can see on the page here, it says that they're activating your account and it should only
take a few minutes.
So what you need to do is watch out for the email in your inbox and once you receive it, you can go
and log into your AWS account as the root user.
Now, mine came through very quickly, so I'm going to click on this option to go to the AWS management
console.
Now, as you can see, the first thing you need to do is enter your account ID or account alias.
Now this is actually when you're logging in as an IAM user.
Now we're not doing that yet.
What we need to do now is actually sign in as the root user using the email address we signed up with.
So choose sign in using root user email.
Then you need to enter the email that you used when you signed up and click on next.
Then enter your password and click on sign in.
Okay, so that's it.
We are now signed in to the US management console.
Now, as you can see in the top right hand corner, we can see the name that I gave to the account,
Neil Dash Dash Labs in this case, and I've got the Northern Virginia region selected.
Now for most of the hands on exercises we do, you'll need to be in the Northern Virginia region.
We'll talk more about regions and see how we can use them later on in the course.
So from here you can now access the US services using this menu in the top left hand corner, for example,
you can go to compute and then find services like EC2.
So that's it.
We're in our AWS account ready to start using it and that's it for this lesson.
I'll see you in the next lesson where we're actually going to start configuring our account.