Welcome back.
In this lesson, we're going to configure our account and we're going to create a budget and an alarm.
So what are the steps we're going to follow?
Well, we're going to configure an account alias if we haven't already.
We're going to enable access to billing for IAM users.
We're going to update our billing preferences and we're going to create a budget and alarm.
These are really important so that you get notified if you accidentally leave something running and
you're going to start running up a bill.
I'm logged in to my free tier account and what I'm going to do is in the top left hand corner, use
this menu, Select services.
Scroll down to security, identity and compliance.
In here you will find the IAM Identity and Access Management Service and we're going to use that to
configure our account alias.
So what is an account alias?
Well, it's a name that we can use to sign in instead of using our accounts ID.
So for example, you can see this sign in URL.
Once we create user accounts, those users will need to know this URL or at least this account number
in order to be able to sign in.
And that's not really very user friendly.
So what we're going to do, I'm going to give it the same name as my account.
I'm going to choose, create type in my preferred alias as Neil Dash a dash and then labs and choose
save changes.
So it's now created the alias for my account and you can see that in the sign in URL here.
So now the sign in URL is a little bit easier to remember.
The next thing we're going to do is we're going to enable billing access for IAM users.
What this means is you may remember that I mentioned that we shouldn't sign in as the root user account
on an ongoing basis.
It's a best practice to create a user account here in IAM that has the permissions we need to do our
jobs and log in and start user.
Now that user won't be able to access billing information which is quite useful when it's your own account.
So what we're going to do is choose the account option in the dropdown box in the top right hand corner
and if you scroll down this page you will find IAM user and role access to billing information.
Click on edit, click on Activate IAM access.
And then if we supply the permissions to our users, they'll be able to access billing information.
Next, we can choose the dropdown in the top right and choose the billing dashboard.
Here we're going to go to billing preferences on the left hand side.
And what I like to do here is I like to receive my PDF invoice via email.
Saves me having to log in when I receive it.
I can just view it straight away and I would like to receive free to usage alerts.
So that means when we're approaching or have exceeded our free to usage limits, we will get an email
to notify us.
I'm going to select this box and enter my email address.
Lastly, I'm going to select receive billing alerts as well and save these preferences.
Now the last thing I want to do is really important, and that is to create a budget so that I can get
an alert when my bill is starting to reach a certain limit.
So I've chosen budgets on the left hand side here and I can choose create a budget to create my budget.
And on this page you can leave the user template, simplified, selected, and then we have a couple
of options.
Now, you can either create a budget that notifies you once your spending exceeds the free tier limits
or choose a monthly cost budget.
Now I'm going to choose the monthly cost budget and I'm simply going to enter a small amount like you
could put in $5 or $10.
Now most of what we do should be in the free tier.
So it's unlikely that you're going to spend any money, but sometimes you might have a couple of dollars
here and there.
So all in all, a really, really cheap way to learn us.
Now we can see it's trying to calculate last month's cost, but we didn't have any because it's brand
new.
So that's not going to work.
Now all you need to do here is enter your email address and then create the budget and that's it.
I have my monthly cost budget of $5 and I will get some notifications in my email inbox if I start getting
close to or exceed that budget.
So make sure you do that.
It's a great way to just safeguard against something accidental where you might leave something running
and rack up a bit of a bill.