Hi, guys. In this lesson, I'm going to give you an overview of the IAM service,
the Identity and Access Management service.
Now, you have seen this in the last section when we logged into AWS and we configured our account.
We actually went into the IAM management console.
IAM is the Identity and Access Management service, and it's a way that we can authenticate and be
authorized to access services on AWS.
So let's say we're connecting to an AWS service via either the management console, the Command Line
Interface or the API.
We'll connect to AWS IAM and we can then authenticate.
And all principles must be authenticated to send requests.
Now what is a principle?
Well, a principle is a person or an application that can make a request for an action
or an operation on a resource.
Now actions and operations are both where we're using the API to interact with an AWS service.
So we have users, roles, federated users, and applications.
We then have a couple of types of policy.
So we can assign permissions to users and then we can use policies to control access to resources.
We have identity-based policies and resource-based policies.
And these determine whether to authorize the request, whether to allow or to deny
the request to the resource.
And once you've got an allow or a deny, assuming it's a deny in this case, you're then able to run
an action against a resource.
Now, remember, I said that everything in AWS is an API call.
So when you're trying to launch an EC2 to instance, you're basically executing the RunInstances command.
If you're trying to get information about an S3 bucket, you're running the GetBucket API action.
And if you trying to create a user in IAM, you're running the CreateUser action.
So whatever resource you're interacting with in AWS, an API action is actually being executed
and you need to have the permissions assigned to your account and you need to be allowed through a policy
to be able to actually perform that specific action.
So the actions are then authorized on the AWS resources.
So that's a really quick overview of what this service does.
And in the next lesson, we're going to delve in more depth into users, groups, roles, and policies.