Okay, so let's look into some more details of users, groups, roles, and policies
in the Identity and Access Management service.
So we have an account here and within an account, we have these various principles.
We have users, groups, roles, and policies.
A group is a way of organizing users.
So we create a group and then we can assign our users to the group.
And we can then apply permissions to these users.
And we do that through a policy.
So the policy defines what the people in this group are allowed to do.
So this is a great way to organize.
Create a group, put everybody in that group that has similar job responsibilities and therefore need
similar permissions and then apply a policy to them.
So the policies define the permissions for the identities or resources they're associated with,
and the user will gain the permissions applied to the group through the policy.
There are different types of policies.
One is called an identity-based policy, and these can be applied to users, groups, or roles.
So what is a role?
A role is a little bit of a more difficult concept to understand.
Roles are used for delegation and they're assumed.
Now, if that doesn't make sense, don't worry.
In another slide, it's going to make a lot more sense when I show you graphically how it works.
Let's first go into some more detail on users.
So in IAM, we have our account root user.
Now the root user is the account that we created when we logged in,
so it's the email address that we used to sign up for our AWS account.
The root user has full permissions and it's a best practice to avoid using the root user account.
And you should also enable multifactor authentication for the root user account.
Then we have our individual users.
You can create up to 5,000 individual users in IAM.
And users will have no permissions by default.
That's really important to remember.
So you can create a user account and that user is able to log in to AWS, but they can't do anything
because they don't have any permissions.
So what you then have to do is give them permissions.
Now each user will have a friendly name.
In this case, the user account name is Andrea, so this person can log in with the user name Andrea.
There's also something called an Amazon Resource Name, an ARN.
And ARNs are assigned to resources within AWS.
They're a bit harder to remember as you can see. They're quite long.
They contain the account number for the AWS account.
And as you can see, they tell you the type of resource, a user account, and then the actual friendly
name is on the end.
There's a few ways that our users can actually authenticate to AWS.
You remember that you can access AWS through the management console, the Command Line Interface,
and also the API.
And authentication to the console is enabled through a username and password.
And for the CLI and the API, there is something called Access Keys, which we'll explore in more
detail a bit later on.
Next up, we have groups.
With groups we can create our different groups for different users.
So here we have an admin group, we have a development group, and we have an operations group.
So these are job role specific groups.
We can then place our users into these groups as is appropriate.
Groups are a collection of users and you can have a user be a member of up to 10 groups.
The main purpose of using groups is not just to organize the users, but to organize them and then apply
permissions to those users.
And we do that by assigning policies to the groups.
The user will then gain the permissions applied to the group through the policy.
Next, we have IAM roles.
An IAM role is an identity that has specific permissions assigned to it.
The roles are assumed by users, applications, and services.
So we have some user accounts and maybe you have an application or service running somewhere else
and we're able to assume the role.
So each of these is able to then assume the role and then gain the permissions
that's assigned to that role.
So once assumed, the identity actually becomes the role.
So in other words, you have a user here and the user assumes the role.
At that point, the user is no longer acting as the user, they're acting as the role,
and they have the permissions that are assigned to the role.
And in this case, that might mean that they can access an S3 bucket.
Lastly, we have policies.
We've seen in this lesson that policies are a way to assign permissions.
They're actually documents that define the permissions and they're written in JSON.
That's JavaScript Object Notation.
They look something like this.
And as you can see, there's a bit of code here.
This is JSON code.
And this one essentially says the effect is to allow any action on any resource.
So this is one that you might assign to an administrator who needs to be able to do
everything in the account.
We then have a bucket policy here.
A bucket policy is another type of policy that's just assigned to a resource and it defines
who is able to act on that resource, what they're able to do.
All permissions are implicitly denied by default in AWS.
Now, what that means is that if you don't assign a permission to allow something, then it's just denied.
Everything will be denied unless you explicitly allow it.
The policy at the top here is an identity-based policy and it can be assigned to users, groups
and roles.
The resource-based policy at the bottom here can be assigned to specific resources such as
an S3 bucket, which is a container for storing data or DynamoDB Table, which is a type of database.