Hi, guys.
And this lesson we're going to create an IAM user and a group.
So I'm logged in to the management console and I'm logged in as my route user account because we don't
have an IM user yet.
So what I'm going to do is search for I am in the top left in the search box and then choose the IAM
service.
So in IAM we're going to create a user and that user is going to have full permissions to the AWS account
and we're going to assign the permissions through a group.
Now we're going to do this so that we can log into our accounts using our own personal IAM user instead
of the root user.
So the first thing I want to do is go to user groups and I'm going to create a group called Admins.
So I'm going to choose, create group, and I'm going to give my group a name, I'm going to call it
admins.
And then what I need to do is attach permissions policies.
So these are going to be the permissions that users who are in the group will obtain.
Now I'm going to search for administrator access, and what I should find is there's a few options here,
but I want this one that's just called administrator access with no space between.
Now, if I expand, I can see the permissions.
In this policy, we can see that the effect is allow the action is what's called a wild card.
That's a star and the resource is star.
That basically means that all actions on all resources will be allowed.
So that's what I want.
I'm going to select this option, come down to the bottom and create group.
So now we have our group called Admins.
I'm then going to go to users on the left and I'm going to click on Add users.
I'm going to call my user Niel and I'm going to select password for a management console access.
We'll create an access key for programmatic access later on.
Now I'm going to enter a custom password and I'm going to deselect the requirement to change the password
at next log on.
Then I click next permissions.
I'm going to select the admins group to provide administrative permissions to my user account.
Click next.
I'm not going to assign any tax.
I'm going to go to review and then create user, and that's it.
My user account is being created.
So now you can see we have a user account.
The user is in a group called Admins and the admins group has administrative permissions assigned through
this policy that's been attached.
So that's great.
What I want to do now is sign in as this user.
So I'm going to sign out using the menu in the top right hand corner and then log back in again.
Now, this time we're going to log in as an IAM user, so we need to enter our account alias.
I've entered my alias, I'm going to click on next, enter my IAM username and password.
And then click on sign in and that's it.
I'm now signed in using my own personal IAM user account to AWAs and I have full administrative permissions
over the account.