Welcome to this lesson.
In this lesson, I'm going to show you how to assume an IAM role
from the management console.
I'm logged into my account and I'm on the
dashboard of the identity and access management console.
We're going to create a new user.
So I'm going to go to users,
click add users
and I'm going to call my user Paul.
I'm only going to provide management console access for Paul at this point in time.
I'm going to configure my own password
and I'm going to remove the requirement to reset the password.
Then we can click next to go to permissions,
and I'm not going to provide any permissions to Paul at this point in time.
Let's click on next,
review.
It's going to warn me that of course Paul doesn't have any
permission so he's not going to be able to do anything.
Now Paul will be able to log into the console but then won't be able to do anything.
Now let's just create this user.
So the user is being created.
And what we're going to do is go back to the main console.
So click on close.
Now, back on the user's pane here, I'm going to select Paul.
And what I want to do is I need Paul's ARN, so the amazon resource name.
So I'm going to click copy here to copy that to my clipboard.
Now you'll find a file in the course, download
which you can download from the last lesson in section one.
And in there, once you've unzipped the course download, you'll find a code directory
IAM and then you will find this switch-role-trust-policy.JSON.
Now what I want to do in here is I need to enter the ARN
for Paul between these two inverted commas here.
So I'm just going to paste in Paul's ARN
and then I can copy all of this code
to my clipboard. Now this is the trust policy for the role.
Back in IAM, let's go to roles and we're going to create
the IAM role that Paul is going to assume.
So let's choose create role.
I'm going to choose custom trust policy
and then I'm going to delete the code in here
and paste in the code that we just updated.
So now we have a trust policy.
And this trust policy is going to allow
the principal and it's configured specifically for Paul
to assume a role.
So it's allowing Paul the privilege to be able to assume an IAM role.
Then we click on next.
And I'm going to search for EC2. So let's just search for EC2 in the top here.
And I'm going to select the Amazon EC2 full access.
So this IAM role is going to be assumable by Paul.
Paul will be allowed to assume this role.
And then when Paul assumes this role,
he will have the EC2 full access permissions.
So let's click on next.
Give it a name.
I'm going to call it EC2-full-access.
And then let's just scroll down and create that role.
So the role has been created.
All we need to do now is log in as Paul.
And we're going to see if we can assume this role.
I'm now logged in as Paul in a private window,
so I've still got my management console logged in
as myself and then in a private window, I'm logged in as Paul.
So if I now go over to the EC2 management console,
what we should see is these API errors.
And that's because Paul doesn't have any permissions.
So essentially it's saying you don't have
any permissions to view any of the information
in EC2.
And he wouldn't be able to launch instances or do anything in EC2.
So what we want to do is assume a role so that we can
then get those permissions through the IAM role that we created previously.
Now back in the console where I'm logged in as myself, I'm logged in as Neal,
I'm just going to go into this role. So let's click on the role.
And what you'll find is all the information you need to assume
the role is actually provided here.
There's even a link that you can use to do it for you.
Now, all we really need is the account number of the account and the name of the role.
So what I'm going to do is the easiest place to find the
account number is you just come back up to the dashboard,
click on copy and I've got that on my clipboard.
Now logged back in as Paul here, I'm going to go up into the top right hand corner,
choose switch role,
click switch role again,
I'm going to paste in my account number.
I need to put in the name of the role.
And then I can add a display name as well.
Once I've entered that information I can choose switch role.
And I've now switched roles and as you can see all those API errors have gone.
So we can now actually use EC2.
So what we've done is we've logged in as Paul.
Paul was unable to do anything in EC2 because he doesn't have any permissions
But the permission that we did assign was for Paul to be able to assume a role.
And once he assumed that role,
He had access to whatever the permissions assigned to that role are.
In this case, that's EC2 full access.
So now Paul is free to do whatever he wants in EC2
and could always then switch back
by just clicking on switch back
and then he will go back to being logged in purely as Paul.
And of course all the API errors return because Paul no longer has those permissions.
So that's how you assume a role using the AWS management console.
A bit later in the course,
we'll see how to do it using the command line interface as well.