Hi, guys. In this lesson, you're going to learn about the Amazon Simple Storage Service or Amazon
S3.
Now we have used Amazon S3 a little bit in this course already where I showed you how to create a bucket
and upload an object.
But I wasn't really aimed at teaching you S3 at that point, so we went through it fairly quickly.
In this section, you're going to learn about S3 in a lot of detail. Now, S3 is what's called
an object-based storage system.
So let's have a look at what this is.
With Amazon S3,
we have something called a bucket. A bucket is a container. And inside that container we put our objects.
Our objects
are files. So, things like a word document, a PDF, an MP4 movie or a JPEG image, or any other
file type.
You can store files in S3 as objects within a bucket.
Each object is a single file and you can have many, many objects.
In fact, you can have millions of objects in a bucket.
S3 is extremely scalable, so you really can store huge quantities of data on Amazon S3, and it scales
seamlessly.
There's nothing you need to do in order to be able to add more files to your storage.
How do we access the objects in our buckets?
Well, with an object-based storage system, we actually use a URL.
The URL will look something like this.
Access is using the HTTPS protocol, so it's secure.
And as you can see in this URL, there's a few of the words are in red, and that's where we have variables.
So, bucket would be the name of your bucket.
AWS-region would be the region in which you created the bucket.
And then on the end, we have slash and then key.
And the key is actually the name of the file. S3 is a key value store.
So, the key is the name of the file and the value is the data of the file itself.
There are actually a couple of different formats for the URL, so it's worth understanding
it's not always going to look the same.
So, as I mentioned, we're using the secure version of the HTTP protocol. And an object-based storage
system is accessed using HTTP over a REST API.
So, REST stands for Representational State Transfer and API is Application Programming Interface.
Essentially, a REST API over HTTP allows you to use the HTTP methods to manipulate your data. So, you're
actually issuing
GET requests to read data from S3 or PUT requests or POST requests to actually upload files to S3.
You can select files, delete files, etc. And all this is done programmatically using an API.
Let's go over a few key facts.
You can store any file type in S3.
Your files can be anywhere from zero bytes up to a maximum individual file size of five terabytes.
There's unlimited storage available. So, as long as your file size is within those limits, then you
can store an unlimited number of those files on S3.
S3 is a universal namespace.
So, bucket names must be unique globally.
So, as you've seen, we actually access our buckets using a URL,
and as you know, no two domains on the internet can share the same name or the same URL. That would
be impossible.
So, every URL has to be unique on the internet.
Therefore, the bucket name must be unique globally because we're going to use it from anywhere on the
internet.
Now, even though the bucket name must be unique globally, you actually create your bucket within a
region.
So, the actual physical data is stored within a single AWS region. And it will never leave that region
unless you specifically configure it to do so.
You can replicate your data to another region, but you have to manually set that up. In all other circumstances,
your data will always sit within a single region.
It's therefore a best practice that you create your buckets closer to where the users are, who are
going to access the data.
And that just means that you're geographically or physically closer, and that means less latency to
access the files in your buckets.
There's no hierarchy for objects within a bucket.
It's essentially a flat namespace.
So just like if you took a lot of sand and throw it into a bucket, there's no hierarchy.
It's just a whole load of individual grains of sand in a bucket. And that's essentially what your objects
are in S3.
Now there is a way that you can mimic a structure. And that's by using a folder, which really just
is an extra part of the key, which makes it look like you have a structure in your bucket.
So, we'll look at that a bit later on.
S3 delivers what's called strong read-after-write consistency.
Now this is a change.
This was implemented towards the end of 2020.
Before that, you only had eventual consistency
when you actually over-wrote something. That means if you uploaded a new version of a file and somebody
immediately tried to read that file, they might get the old version or they might get the new version,
it really depends on whether it's replicated.
That's no longer the case. But it's unclear at this point in time which questions you'll see on the
exam.
Let's have a look at the structure and a bit more detail.
So, we have our bucket and we have a new URL with which we can access that bucket.
We then have our files within the bucket.
So here we have a spreadsheet and we can access that using this URL. And on the end of /orders.xlsx.
So that is the key or the name of the file.
The value is the actual data of that file itself.
We might then have a word document and another word document here as well.
And each of those will then also have a URL with a key on the end.
But what you might notice here is that we have an extra level, so we have this Project+Alpha/
and then the sales proposal.
Now this is a folder.
Now, as I mentioned, that is actually part of the key.
It looks like a folder. And in the management console it will look like a folder and it looks like you've
created a hierarchy.
But really, all the objects are at the same level, but you've mimicked a folder structure instead.
So, you can think of a folder as a shared prefix for grouping your objects together.
A few more facts about buckets, folders, and objects.
Folders can be created within folders to mimic an even deeper hierarchy.
But buckets can never be created inside another bucket.
A bucket is not a hierarchical structure.
You just create a bucket and then you can potentially create your own folder structure within that or
just throw your object straight into it.
But you can never have one bucket in another bucket.
Each object consists of a key, and that's the name of the object,
so, the actual file name itself, a version ID, a value.
So remember, this is a key value store.
So, at a basic level, you have the key, the name of the object or the file, and the value, which is
the actual data.
Then you have metadata, and subresources. We'll cover some of these a bit later on.
And also, access control information. We'll go into quite a bit detail about how you can implement access
control with S3.
So how do we access Amazon S3?
Well, as you've seen, it uses a public URL, so a URL that you can access over the internet.
And that's because it has a public endpoint, it's a public service.
It's not within a VPC.
It's in the AWS public space and it's always accessed via the internet.
So, you might have an internet client with some kind of web browser-based application accessing S3
over the internet.
You might have an application that uses the REST API to talk to Amazon S3 programmatically.
You can also use the CLI as well.
Now, what about accessing S3 from a VPC?
Let's say you have EC2 instances in public and private subnets.
Well, as you know, we have Internet gateways that we can attach to our VPC. And that's great for
the instance in the public subnet because it can use the Internet gateway to talk to S3 across
the internet using the S3 public endpoint.
Now, there is another way that we can access S3, and this is useful for clients, especially in
private subnets. And that's using an S3 gateway endpoint.
What this does is it creates a private connection. So, we're actually able to use private addresses
to access S3. Really important exam tips to remember that. If you ever see a question that relates
to accessing Amazon S3 where you want to avoid the internet or you want to use private addresses,
S3 gateway endpoints which are a type of VPC endpoint are the most likely answer.
So that's it for the overview. And we've got lots more to get on with. So,
I'll see you in the next lesson.