When we store our objects on Amazon S3, we have a choice of which storage class to use.
There are several storage classes and each comes with a series of strengths and weaknesses.
And they come at different price points.
So, it's really important to understand which storage class to use for a specific use case.
Now, the best way to go over these is literally to use this table that comes from AWS because it shows
the six storage classes side by side.
And it's a great way of comparing the different features.
Most of what you need to know is on this table. We'll cover some more details throughout the section.
The very top line in this table is the name of the storage class.
So, by default, when you upload an object to S3, it's going to use the S3 Standard storage class.
But if you want to store your objects in one of the other storage classes, you've got to actually configure
that as part of your upload.
So, there's Intelligent Tiering, which actually moves data for you between storage classes based on
access patterns. It tries to work out what's the best, the optimal storage class to use.
Standard-IA stands for Standard Infrequently Access, so it's good for data use cases where you don't
access the data too much.
We've then got One Zone-IA, which is also infrequently access data, but it's only stored in one availability
zone.
The next two storage classes are for archiving.
We have S3 Glacier and Dlacier Deep Archive.
So, this is where you want to hold your data for a long period of time at the lowest cost possible.
And Deep Archive is the lowest cost of these two.
But Glacier is still quite a bit cheaper than the other storage classes.
So, let's go through the different attributes and understand these classes in a bit more detail.
Now, the first line is durability. And as you can see, it's the same for all storage classes.
We have what we call 11 nines of durability here.
Now, you can think of durability as the likelihood of losing an object.
So, 11 nines basically means the likelihood of an object being lost is extremely low.
So, it's the same across all storage classes, not something you need to worry about too much.
We've then got availability.
Now, this does vary. So, availability is your ability to access the data.
So, imagine if a region becomes inaccessible due to a network issue.
You can't access your data, but your data is not lost, so the durability still counts.
The data is still there, but you just can't get access to it
because the networks not available. It could be a network,
it could be a power failure,
it could be a variety of things.
So, availability is how have they designed the system such that, you know, they're going to minimize
the likelihood of you not being able to access your data?
The highest availability is 99.99% or four nines.
And that applies to Standard, Glacier, and Glacier Deep Archive.
Then we go down a bit with Intelligent Tiering to three nines and the same for Standard Infrequently Accessed.
And then the lowest is One Zone-IA because the data, as you see in the next line, is only within
a single availability zone instead of three.
So, you get 99.5 availability.
The next line is the minimum capacity charge per object.
So, as you can see, with Standard and Intelligent Tiering, you get charged based on the amount of data
you actually put on.
With the other storage classes
there is a minimum capacity charge, so even if you have less than 128 kilobytes per object, you're
going to have to pay for 128 kilobytes with Standard-IA.
So, as you can see, it's the same for One Zone-IA and then 40 kilobytes for Glacier and Glacier Deep Archive.
Now you don't often get tested on that in the exam, so that's one of the things not to worry too much
about. Minimum storage
duration charge is something you need to understand. So, this is the minimum time you must store an
object in a certain storage class before you move it somewhere else.
One of the subjects of this section is Lifecycle management, where we might want to automatically move
data after a certain period of time to another storage class.
Now, you do need to take these into account when you configure your lifecycle rules because, for example,
we have a minimum storage duration charge of 30 days with Infrequently Accessed.
So, you're still going to get charged,
you won't be able to move your data out and stop paying for it before 30 days.
Now, as you can see, Standard doesn't have a minimum duration, which is important to remember.
The minimum duration is then 30 days for the next three storage classes, 90 days for Glacier, and 180
days for Deep Archive.
Make sure you remember those for the exam.
They often come up in questions.
Now, a retrieval fee is another thing that's really important to understand when you're calculating
the costs for your storage.
As you can see, Standard, there is no retrieval fee.
Same of Intelligent
Tiering. So, if you put some objects in Standard, it's more expensive than Standard-IA, but you don't
have to pay any retrieval fee.
So Standard-IA might be cheaper, but only if you don't retrieve your data often. If you retrieve
your data often and you're paying those retrieval fees,
you might end up paying more than if you just kept it in Standard.
So, that's definitely something in cost management that you really need to understand.
Otherwise, you might end up paying more when you think that you're moving your data to a tier where
it should cost less.
So really, it's about fitting the use case to the right tier.
So, data that gets accessed often should probably not be an Infrequently Accessed storage class.
First byte latency is another really important thing to understand.
So, what does this mean?
It means how long does it take to actually access your data?
Now, milliseconds essentially means that your data is immediately accessible.
So, if you have your data in the S3 Standard storage class, you can issue an API call and pull an object
down immediately.
But if you have your data in one of the archival classes like Glacier or Glacier Deep Archive, it's
actually archived.
It's not immediately available.
Think of it in a way like you've got files in a file system and then you move some of those files to
a tape drive.
So, it's an archive for data that you don't access
very often. You've moved it off your file system to save storage space.
Now, how do you get that data back?
Well, you have to load it from the tape and then you have to access that data, so it takes a bit more
time.
So, with the archival tier, that's very similar. You're actually archiving your data. So, you cannot
issue an API call and just access it immediately.
And that's somewhere between minutes and hours for Glacier, or even up to 24 hours for Deep Archive.
So that's why Deep Archive is even cheaper.
But just remember that it does take longer to get your data from Deep Archive.
The final two lines are the same for every storage class.
It's always objects.
We don't have any other type of file that gets stored in Amazon S3. And we can use lifecycle transitions
with all six storage classes.
And that's going to be a subject of another lesson.
Let's go over a couple of use cases now to help to see how we might fit our use case to a storage class.
So, we've got our six storage classes on the left. And here's our first use case. We require long term
storage for production data with low cost and immediate access for occasional requests.
Well, which storage class do you think is the best fit for this particular scenario?
Well, it's Standard-IA. we want long term storage with low cost, but we need immediate access and
the requests are occasional.
So that makes a lot of sense.
We want to lower our cost.
We always want to try and find the most cost-effective solution. And the requests are occasional,
so, we're not going to be paying that retrieval fee too often. But we do need immediate access, so
we can't use an archival tier.
The next use case is we want to make a copy of some backup data in a separate AWS region, and we need
to be able to access it with minimal latency.
So, if you think about this scenario, we have a system somewhere that has some data.
That data is then backed up somewhere else. And we're now wanting to take an additional copy of that
backup data just in case the main system goes down,
there's something wrong with the backup,
so now, we've got another copy.
Now, a good storage solution for this would be One Zone-IA because it's a bit cheaper than Standard-IA,
we're not going to access the data very often.
Very rarely,
hopefully, if at all.
And we're saving a bit more money because it doesn't have all the extra availability now.
When we have multiple copies of this data in multiple places, maybe we don't need the extra availability
zones within that region.
So, this could be a good use case.
The next use case is really a couple of different scenarios where the same storage class might be useful
for all of these.
So, we might have frequently accessed data,
we might have ad hoc needs or short-term requirements of less than 30 days.
So, for this we would use the Standard storage class. So, it has to be frequently accessed.
That's a good idea for Standard because we don't want to have retrieval fees, ad hoc needs, so you might be
storing data for a short period of time.
You don't know how much it's going to be used or you might be deleting after a few days.
And then, yeah, the short-term requirements as well.
So, anything less than 30 days, Standard might make the most sense because you can delete it and then
stop paying for that data.
Lastly, we have some long-term archival data that we must keep for compliance purposes, and we're
looking for the absolute lowest cost.
Well, in that case, Glacier Deep Archive would be a good use case.
With Deep Archive, you can store your data long term at an extremely low cost.
And as long as you don't need to access it quickly, then that is going to be the most cost effective
storage class for you.
So, that's it for this lesson.
Hopefully
that gives you an understanding of the different storage classes of when you might use them.
I'll see you in the next lesson.