Welcome to another lesson in this one
We're going to cover Amazon S3 encryption with encryption on S3
There's a few different options.
Firstly, we have what's called server side encryption with S3 manage keys known as
SSE-S3. Here, the keys are managed by AWS using a
256 bit encryption.
And
the encryption and decryption takes place on the AWS side within the S3 service.
So if you're a user and you upload and objects, when you upload that object,
it's secured in transit using TLS, but then it's secured in S3 at rest by
AWS encrypting it as it's actually written to the discs.
If you then download it, it's decrypted on the S3 side.
But then it's encrypted in transit using TLS.
Another option is server side encryption with
AWS KMS manage keys, SSE
KMS.
So here we're using the key management service. The keys are managed by KMS.
They can be
Aws managed keys or customer managed KMS keys.
Again, the encryption and decryption is taking place in S3.
Next, we have server side encryption with client provided keys
known as
SSE-C
We still have the encryption decryption taking place in S3 here,
but the keys are managed on the client side,
they're not stored on
AWS
at all.
Lastly, we have client side encryption here, we have client manage keys,
they're not stored on
AWS at all, but you can use a KMS key as well. Here
The difference is that the encryption and decryption
is taking place on the client side.
OK.
So you have some kind of application that
is performing the encryption and the decryption on the
client side, not in AWS,
Aws will just see the encrypted objects and it
has no way of decrypting them for you all
Amazon S3 buckets have encryption configured by default. Now,
that's the default option.
It wasn't always like that you used to have to choose to turn on encryption.
But now this is the default setting. All new
object uploads to S3 are automatically encrypted and
there's no additional cost and there's no impact
on the performance objects are automatically encrypted by
using server side encryption with S3 manage keys.
That's the default. Of course, you can change that
If you want to, to encrypt existing unencrypted objects,
you can use S3 batch operations.
So if you were using S3 before the default encryption option was implemented,
then you can encrypt those existing unencrypted objects.
You can also encrypt existing objects using the copy objects,
API operation or the copy objects,
AWS
CLI command.
You can also use bucket policies to enforce the encryption settings that
you want this particular one enforces encryption using SSE KMS.
We can also enforce encryption
using a bucket policy.
So for example, we might want to force the use of SSE KMS rather than SSE S3.
This policy would do that.
So here we have a deny for the put objects API action, we can specify our bucket name.
And then there's a condition that says that the
string not equals S3 X AM Z server side encryption
AWS KMS.
So if KMS is not present in the put request as it is in this one here, then
the bucket policy will deny access.