In this lesson we're going to look at how we can use a bucket policy
in order to enforce encryption for objects that are uploaded to the bucket.
Now, we're going to use this policy here.
And I've already copied the ARN of my bucket to my clipboard
and I'm going to paste that in and make sure that the /* is still on the end.
So just do that and then you can copy this code to your clipboard.
And back in S3, I'm going to go to permissions,
come down to where my bucket policy is, click on edit,
and we're going to override this policy here.
This policy is going to deny all principals
the S3 PUT objects API action, so you can't upload objects
to this resource so this bucket and any object within the bucket.
And there's a condition in the condition is that this value is null.
Now this value is XMZ server-side encryption true.
Now if that is specified, that means the object is going to be encrypted.
If it's null then you're trying to upload an object that isn't encrypted.
And in that case this policy will apply and you'll be denied.
So let's save those changes.
Come back to objects,
click on upload,
add files.
Let's try uploading this mountain image. And if we come down to properties,
this is where we can specify encryption if we want to.
So let's try not specifying encryption.
And what happens?
Well, it fails. So we can't upload that object.
Now, we can also run commands. So we can run these commands.
What I'm going to do is copy the bucket name to my clipboard,
paste it in here where it says your bucket name.
And now we have this command.
Now we need to specify our own file name, so mine is called mountain.jpg.
And then I can copy this command to my clipboard.
So this command is essentially trying to do exactly
the same as we just did through the console.
So if I come to a location here where I have this file,
and I'm going to try and run this command with my profile specified.
And of course, we get an access denied just as before.
The next command we can run to try and actually get around this issue
is using the AWS S3 API CLI.
And then we can specify service side encryption using the command line.
Now, I need to copy the name of my file into two locations here for the body
and for the key.
So let's paste that one in.
Then I need to copy my bucket name
and put that here next to the --bucket.
Now I can copy this entire command.
Let's paste that in. I'm going to specify my profile information.
And let's try and upload this file.
And this time it succeeds.
So now we know that the S3 bucket policy is enforcing encryption and this is
how we can actually ensure that our objects are encrypted using the command line.
Now back in the console, we could also achieve this by adding a file.
Let's add a different file this time.
Click on upload.
And under properties,
I'm going to scroll down.
I'm going to specify an encryption key and I'll
just use the Amazon S3 managed keys option
and then upload.
And again that's going to work.
Now another thing you can do to make this a bit easier is go to properties,
and let's enable default encryption.
So now I'm going to specify enable.
Default encryption is going to be using S3 managed keys.
Let's save those changes.
So now we actually have the default encryption specified,
but we also do have this bucket policy so let's remove our bucket policy.
I just need to delete this policy
because that's going to enforce us to set certain settings for encryption.
So I've deleted the bucket policy.
We have enabled default encryption.
Now let's see what happens if I try and upload a file without specifying
any encryption information.
So I'm going to upload this file. Let's go to properties.
Let's make sure that we have not specified encryption settings.
And then let's click on upload.
And this time it does succeed despite the fact that we didn't actually
enable any encryption settings. And if we click on the file here,
we can see the information relating to this file and down here we can see
that the server-side encryption is actually enabled through default encryption.
So that's how we can use bucket policies to enforce encryption,
and we can use default encryption to automatically encrypt objects in our bucket.