Hi guys. In this lesson, I'm going to cover a quick bit of theory
on performance optimization in relation to Amazon S3.
So let's look at some design patterns for optimizing S3 performance.
S3 will automatically scale to very high request rates with at least,
and this is per prefix,
3,500 Put, copy, post, or delete request per second
and 5,500 Get, head request per second.
Now you can increase the read and write
performance by using parallelization across multiple prefixes.
So you're going to spread your data across more prefixes.
And these limitations only apply within each prefix.
To increase upload speeds over long distances
you can use S3 transfer acceleration that leverages the CloudFront network to upload
your data and move it into S3 across the AWS global network.
You can also use what are called byte-range fetches with the range HTTP header.
And that means that you're only transferring the specified
byte range from an object that you actually need.
You should also look at combining S3 and EC2 in the same AWS region.
And use the latest version of the AWS SDKs.
You could also use caching services to cache the latest content
like a content delivery network like CloudFront
or ElastiCache for an in-memory cache.
Try to horizontally scale your requests across S3 endpoints.
So S3 has lots of public endpoints. You can look up what they are.
And you can configure your application to spread
the load across those different public endpoints.
Now there's more info here. I do suggest that you click on this link and have a look.
It's worth a little bit of revision ahead of your exam.