In this lesson, we're going to create a static website on Amazon S3
and then we're going to create a CloudFront distribution in front of
our static website.
And we'll use an origin access identity to secure access
so that people can only access the static website through CloudFront.
They can't go directly to the S3 bucket.
I'm back in, Amazon S3 and I'm going to create a new bucket.
I'm going to give this one a name.
I'm going to call mine My Static Website-DCT. Hopefully that name is unique.
It's going to be in the us-east-1 region.
I do recommend you use us-east-1 whenever you're using a CloudFront distribution.
It can make it a lot faster to actually converge and become ready.
So use us-east-1 for your bucket.
We're not going to enable ACLs
and we're not going to enable public access.
We're just going to scroll down to the bottom and create the bucket.
So I've got that bucket.
Now at the moment, we don't have any public access to
this bucket and I'm actually going to keep it that way.
But I do need to upload some files.
So I'm going to add files.
And in the code Amazon S3 directory you should find error.html and index.html.
So we're going to upload these two files
and click on upload.
So those have been added. Next, we need to go to properties,
scroll all the way to the bottom and this is where we enable static website hosting.
So we click on enable.
We're going to host a static website.
And we're going to use index.html and error.html for the two documents.
So I've added my document names and then I simply save my changes.
when you do that, you will find that there's a URL for the bucket.
So at the bottom of the page here I can see a URL.
I'm going to copy that to my clipboard.
And I just want to check if this is accessible. It shouldn't be accessible.
And sure enough it says access denied.
And that's fine. I'm actually going to leave it this way.
I don't want anyone to be able to come and directly access this S3 bucket.
I want them to only be able to access
the contents of the bucket via the CloudFront distribution.
I've opened the CloudFront management console
and here I'm just going to create a CloudFront distribution.
For origin domain name here, we'll see the actual S3 bucket.
So as you can see you can choose S3 buckets, Elastic Load Balancers,
media store containers, and media package containers.
So I'm going to choose my static website.
I'm not going to enter an origin path.
The name is fine. I don't need to change that.
Now we are going to use an origin access identity, so I need to click yes.
Now, we can select from existing OAIs
or we can create a new one.
So we'll create a new OAI. I'm happy with the name that it suggests.
And that's now specified.
So that is the identity that's being created through CloudFront.
And what we want to do is update the bucket policy.
And that will actually add a bucket policy that only allows access to the bucket
if the caller is this particular OAI.
Let's just scroll down now. We're going to leave the default cache behavior.
We want to use HTTP and HTTPS.
And then we just scroll down farther.
We can leave all of these settings as they are.
The only thing we need to update
is the default root object which needs to be index.html.
So make sure you put in index.html as the default root object
and then create distribution.
Now it can take several minutes for the CloudFront distribution
to deploy and become ready. So at the moment we can see it's in the deploying status.
And that should change within the next 5-10 minutes.
While that's happening. Let's go back to our static website.
And I want to go across to the permissions page.
And here we can actually see the bucket policy that was automatically added
by CloudFront.
So this policy has a statement which is allow
and then it specifies a principal.
And that principal is the origin access identity.
And only that principal will be allowed the get object permission.
And you can see the resource is also locked down to this particular bucket
and its contents.
So that all looks good.
Let's go back to CloudFront and let's just wait a few minutes for it to become ready.
It's been a few minutes and I refresh my page and it does look like it's now deployed.
So let's copy the distribution domain name to our clipboards
and then go over to a new browser window.
I'm going to paste it in.
And we can see the web page, that's the index.html from our bucket, which tells
us we've successfully launched a static website
and then we've securely accessed it through amazon CloudFront.
So it's as simple as that just to serve a static website through CloudFront.
And of course we've used an OAI here to make sure that there's no way that anyone
can directly access the S3 bucket.
They must come through the CloudFront distribution.
Now I've finished with the distribution for this demonstration, but feel
free to go and have a look around the various options
that you can configure through CloudFront.
What I want to do now that I've finished is select my distribution
and then click on disable.
And then disable again.
Now it will take several minutes for this to happen. Until it's fully disabled,
you will not be able to delete it.
So just make sure you don't forget about it.
Give it a few minutes, probably 10-15 minutes maximum
and then you can delete your distribution