Amazon.
Route 53 is an intelligent DNS service, a domain name system service, and it has a variety of capabilities.
On the left of the screen here, you can see that Route 53 can perform domain registration.
So if you want to register your own domain name, you can use Route 53 and it will charge you a small
fee and register your domain.
And we'll see how that works in the hands on.
When you register a domain such as example dot com, you will then find that a hosted zone is created
for you in a US.
The hosted zone is essentially a container into which your DNS records are added and you can also create
private hosted zones as well for use within the environment with your VPC.
So the hosted zone has the records which need resolution.
You remember from earlier in the course we talked about DNS resolution.
So for example, your computer might need to know the IP address, for example, dot com.
So it checks the hosted zone for example, dot com to find that information.
Amazon Route 53 can also do health checks.
That means it checks endpoints on a regular basis to make sure that they're accessible.
If they're not accessible, that means, you know, there could be a problem and you wouldn't want to
route any connections to those instances.
So what around 53 will do is make sure that once it knows a health check has failed, it will no longer
respond with the addresses that relate to those failed health checks.
There's also a feature called Traffic Flow, where you can build even more intelligence using workflows.
Now let's just have a quick recap on DNS resolution.
So here we have a user, the user wants to connect to the website, for example, dot com.
And we can see here there's a hosted zone called example dot com In Route 53, the hosted zone represents
a set of records belonging to a domain.
The user enters example dot com into their web browser and the computer will then connect to Route 53
and ask the question What's the address for example, dot com That's known as an A record where we're
trying to get the IP address for a name.
Route 53 responds with the IP address.
8.1.2.1 Now the computer knows where to connect to the server on the internet, so it performs an HTTP
get request to 8.1.2.1 and it can view the website.
So that's the basics of how DNS resolution works.
And that is what we're doing with Route 53.
Now, Route 53 is an intelligent DNS service, so it's not just responding in a simple way by providing
a response such as we saw before, there's some additional things that we can do so we can have conditional
responses based on various criteria that is implemented through what's called a routing policy.
Now, the simple routing policy at the top really is simple.
There's not a lot of intelligence there.
It's simply providing the IP address associated with the name, just as we saw in the previous slide.
We then have fail over with.
Fail over Route 53 is checking whether the resources alive based on health checks, Is it responding
to health checks?
If so, I will provide the response to go to the primary server.
If the primary server has failed its health checks, then it will route the connection to a secondary
destination.
So it's failing over because we know that the primary resource is not available.
We then have geolocation which uses the geographic location that the client is in to route the connection
to the closest geographic endpoint geo proximity routes you to the closest region within a specific
area.
We then have latency which is really useful.
What latency does is it tries to work out what is the latency between the various endpoints and send
you to the lowest latency endpoint.
So let's say for example, you have a website deployed on Amazon EC2 in the US East region.
You also have a website with the same information deployed in the Singapore region.
Now if somebody in the United States wants to connect to your website, round 53 is going to send them
to the US East region because it's geographically closer and the latency is likely to be much lower.
Now, if somebody is in South East Asia, they're more likely to be routed to the Singapore instance
because the latency is lower for them to go to Singapore.
Now we also have multi value answer.
It's kind of a bit like load balancing where different IP addresses are returned and so the load gets
spread across the different instances that you have records for.
Lastly, we have weighted which uses relative weights.
So for example, you can configure it such that 80% of the traffic goes to one resource and 20 to another.
It's a great way of testing out some updates before you fully implement them.
It means you can send a subset of your traffic to one resource that's been updated and see what happens.