Welcome to another exam cram
this exam cram is on Amazon S three and cloudfront.
So let's get started. You can store any type of file in S three
files can be anywhere from zero bytes to
five terabytes and there's unlimited storage available.
S three is a universal name space, so bucket names
must be unique globally,
but you can create your buckets within a specific region.
It's a best practice to create buckets in
regions that are physically closest to your users
to reduce latency
and there's no hierarchy for objects within a bucket.
S free delivers strong read after write consistency.
The object name is the key. The data is the value.
A folder is a shared prefix for grouping objects,
folders can be created within folders so you can have a
hierarchy but it's not like a hierarchy with a file system,
it's just a prefix on your key
buckets cannot be created within other buckets.
S three is a public service that has public endpoints.
VPc endpoints can be used to connect using private iP addresses.
I am policies are identity-based policies and can control access to S- three
I am policies are attached to I am users groups or roles.
They're also written in Jason using the AWS access policy Language,
Bucket policies are resource-based policies and can only
be attached to Amazon S- three buckets.
They also use the AWS access policy language
A C L S R a legacy access control mechanism that predates
I AM
AWS generally recommends using bucket policies or I AM policies rather than a CLS.
A CLS can be attached to a bucket or directly to an object.
They offer limited options for grantees and permissions
to delete adds a multi factor authentication requirement for bucket owners.
Delete applies to changing versioning state or permanent object. Deletion
versioning can be enabled by bucket owners.
The AWS account that created the buckets and authorized. I. M users
delete can be enabled by the bucket owner only.
M. F. A. Protected api access enforces another level of authentication.
Another factor when accessing AWS resources,
let's look at the encryption options for s free.
You got service side encryption with S three managed keys known as S S C S free.
We've got service side encryption with kms managed keys.
Sse KMs.
We've got service side encryption with client provided keys.
Sse E C.
And then we've got client side encryption.
S three default encryption provides a way to set
the default encryption behavior for an S three bucket,
you can set default encryption on a bucket so that all
new objects are encrypted when they are stored in the bucket.
The objects are encrypted Using service side encryption.
S re encrypts the objects before saving them to disk
and then decrypt them when the objects are downloaded.
There's no change to the encryption of objects that
existed in the bucket before default encryption was enabled.
Server access logging provides detailed records for
the requests that are made to a bucket
details will include the requester the bucket name, request time,
request action response status and error code.
Cause cross origin.
Resource sharing allows requests from an origin to another origin.
An origin is defined by DNS name protocol and ports
Cause is enabled through setting access control allow origin
and access control allow methods
and also access control allow headers.
S3 automatically scales for high request rates with at least
3500. Put copy post, delete or 5500.
Get head requests per second per partition prefix.
You can increase read and write
performance by using parallelization across multiple prefixes
to increase up loads over long distances. You can use S3 transfer acceleration
byte range fetches used the range http header to
transfer only specified byte ranges from an object.
You can combine s free and easy to in the same region for better performance.
And you should also use the latest version of the SDK s for best performance.
You can also use cashing services to cash the latest content.
And also you can horizontally scale requests across S three endpoints.
Cloudfront can be used for cash in content. Again, for performance,
a distribution is created in cloudfront and each distribution has an Origin
only. Web distributions are currently supported
signed. Your L. S can be used to provide more control over access to your content.
You can specify the beginning and exploration, date and time and I.
P address ranges of your users
signed cookies are similar to sign you or else
you signed cookies when you don't want to change your else.
They can also be used when you want to provide access to multiple restricted files,
and that's it for this exam cram.